[
    {
        "question": "Colonial cities functioned primarily as?:",
        "correct_answer": "mercantile centers for collecting agricultural goods and distributing imported manufactured goods.",
        "distractor1": "places where most poor immigrants settled and worked as independent artisans.",
        "distractor2": "centers where large scale financial and banking operations were conducted.",
        "distractor3": "places to which wage earners commuted from numerous surrounding communities.",
        "distractor4": "centers of light manufacturing."
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the Whig ideology, the best defense against corruption and tyranny rested in the?:",
        "correct_answer": "eternal vigilance by the people.",
        "distractor1": "increased power of the executive.",
        "distractor2": "maintenance of a strong standing army.",
        "distractor3": "suppression of dissent and sedition."
    },
    {
        "question": "Between 1650 and 1750, family life in the English colonies changed such that in?:",
        "correct_answer": "northern colonies it grew less patriarchal, while in southern colonies it grew more patriarchal.",
        "distractor1": "both northern and southern colonies, it grew more patriarchal.",
        "distractor2": "both northern and southern colonies, it grew less patriarchal.",
        "distractor3": "northern colonies it grew more patriarchal, while in southern colonies it grew less patriarchal."
    },
    {
        "question": "By the early 1700s, the slave codes of the English colonies in North America established all of the following rules EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "allowed a slave with some white ancestry to apply for freedom.",
        "distractor1": "made slavery a permanent condition.",
        "distractor2": "limited the rights of slaves severely.",
        "distractor3": "provided that the children of slaves would also be slaves."
    },
    {
        "question": "Anglo-American women in colonial times?:",
        "correct_answer": "could own property or execute legal documents only if they were widowed or unmarried.",
        "distractor1": "enjoyed more liberties and rights than did Native American women.",
        "distractor2": "attended church less frequently than did Anglo-American men.",
        "distractor3": "were more likely than men to do agricultural work.",
        "distractor4": "were required by law to learn to read and write, in order to teach their children."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Salem Village witchcraft crisis occurred for which of the following reasons?:",
        "correct_answer": "experiencing feelings of powerlessness and insecurity, many Puritans found in witchcraft an explanation for the disorder and change around them.",
        "distractor1": "as the poor felt more and more powerless, they tried to take out their frustrations on the wealthy by charging them with practicing witchcraft.",
        "distractor2": "old-guard Puritans created the crisis to regain their power and restore morality to the community.",
        "distractor3": "the crisis was primarily the result of a power struggle among leading Puritan families."
    },
    {
        "question": "Benjamin Franklin's concept of the  ideal American  differed from John Winthrop's in which of the following ways?:",
        "correct_answer": "Franklin valued individualism; Winthrop valued the submission of individual will to the good of the community.",
        "distractor1": "Franklin included women and blacks; Winthrop did not.",
        "distractor2": "Franklin emphasized devotion to one's family; Winthrop emphasized devotion to God.",
        "distractor3": "Franklin emphasized political activism; Winthrop shunned political involvement."
    },
    {
        "question": "Thomas Jefferson once observed that the best school of political liberty the world ever saw was the?:",
        "correct_answer": "New England town meeting.",
        "distractor1": "College of William and Mary.",
        "distractor2": "Chesapeake plantation system.",
        "distractor3": "Virginia House of Burgesses.",
        "distractor4": "Congregationalist meeting house."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT TRUE of English colonial families in mid-18c America?:",
        "correct_answer": "women, while subservient to their husbands, set the moral standards by which children were raised and decided how the children would be educated and trained.",
        "distractor1": "physical punishment was the normal method of enforcing unquestioned obedience from children.",
        "distractor2": "women lost virtually all of their legal rights as individuals once they married.",
        "distractor3": "most families bore children who lived long enough to bear children of their own.",
        "distractor4": "more than 90% of families lived in rural areas at about this time."
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the Great Awakening, inter-colonial trade and American attitudes toward English culture and constitutional",
        "correct_answer": "they contributed to a growing sense of shared American identity.",
        "distractor1": "they created disdain for England.",
        "distractor2": "they created a rebellious spirit in America.",
        "distractor3": "they helped create imperial rivalry between England and France."
    },
    {
        "question": "The decade of the 1950s in the United States was characterized by which of the following?:",
        "correct_answer": "a steady rise in the number of women employees in the overall work force.",
        "distractor1": "more women than men in the legal and medical professions.",
        "distractor2": "a declining birth rate.",
        "distractor3": "widespread use of oral contraceptives.",
        "distractor4": "a decline in the life expectancy of women."
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following factors promoted the growth of suburbs EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "laws forbidding residential segregation by races.",
        "distractor1": "low-cost government loans.",
        "distractor2": "expanded road and highway construction.",
        "distractor3": "increased automobile production."
    },
    {
        "question": "The mood of the  Beat Generation  is best reflected in which of the following?:",
        "correct_answer": "Jack Kerouac's  On the Road .",
        "distractor1": "F. Scott Fitzgerald's  This Side of Paradise .",
        "distractor2": "Arthur Miller's  Death of a Salesman .",
        "distractor3": "J. D. Sallinger's  Catcher in the Rye .",
        "distractor4": "James Joyce's  Ulysses ."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is TRUE of White Citizens' Councils?:",
        "correct_answer": "supported by white business and professional people, they used their economic power against black civil rights activists.",
        "distractor1": "made up primarily of the white power elite within southern communities, they denounced the racist beliefs of the Ku Klux Klan.",
        "distractor2": "members of these organizations attempted to implement the Brown decision in a peaceful and orderly manner.",
        "distractor3": "made up primarily of rural whites, these organizations advocated the violent overthrow of the government of the United States."
    },
    {
        "question": "Homeownership in Levittown in the 1950s was stimulated by all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "the migration of African-Americans from the ghettos to the suburbs.",
        "distractor1": "standardized construction methods.",
        "distractor2": "extensive car ownership and the expanding highway system.",
        "distractor3": "low-cost mortgages from the Federal Housing Administration and the Veterans Administration."
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following are true regarding television during the 1950s EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "its drama was noted for its  earthiness  and extreme violence.",
        "distractor1": "it altered eating habits at dinnertime with the appearance of TV trays and frozen TV dinners.",
        "distractor2": "it is revered as a classic period in television programming--a  golden age of television. ",
        "distractor3": "it relied heavily on programming that included the variety show and live drama."
    },
    {
        "question": "From the mid-1920s to the mid-1950s, the duties of the Hays Office involved which of the following?:",
        "correct_answer": "enforcement of moral standards in motion pictures.",
        "distractor1": "First Amendment complaints against the press.",
        "distractor2": "consumer protests against poor railroad service.",
        "distractor3": "supervision of intercollegiate sports. ",
        "distractor4": "civil rights litigation in the federal courts."
    },
    {
        "question": "The 1950s saw all of the following demographic shifts EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "total United States population grew less than in any previous decade of the 20c.",
        "distractor1": "some 18 million Americans moved from cities to the suburbs.",
        "distractor2": "more than 5 million Americans moved from the North and East to the South and West.",
        "distractor3": "millions of rural blacks and Puerto Ricans moved to cities."
    },
    {
        "question": " Silent Spring ?:",
        "correct_answer": "argued that the use of DDT was dangerous to the entire food chain.",
        "distractor1": "predicted the consequences of a nuclear power plant  melt-down. ",
        "distractor2": "was Beat poet Allen Ginsberg's denunciation of American materialism.",
        "distractor3": "described the lack of political involvement of most Americans during the 1950s."
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following were reasons why a consumer culture appeared in the 1950s EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "a considerable drop in the prices of consumer goods.",
        "distractor1": "the creation of credit cards and easy payments plans.",
        "distractor2": "an increased ability of advertisers to create demand for new products.",
        "distractor3": "the appearance of new and varied products."
    },
    {
        "question": "A major cause of the movement to the suburbs in the decades following World War II was?:",
        "correct_answer": "the growth of the middle class during the post-World War II period.",
        "distractor1": "greater economic opportunities found in the suburbs.",
        "distractor2": "the availability of comfortable and efficient railroad transportation from suburban to urban centers.",
        "distractor3": "opportunities for minorities to find jobs and homes in the suburbs."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following developments did NOT occur in American society between 1815 and 1860?:",
        "correct_answer": "the percentage of foreign-born people living in the nation declined.",
        "distractor1": "there was a decline in the importation of slaves.",
        "distractor2": "an active women's rights movement took form.",
        "distractor3": "temperance became a major social and political issue.",
        "distractor4": "birth control became more commonplace in middle-class families."
    },
    {
        "question": "The term  Cult of Domesticity  refers to?:",
        "correct_answer": "the idealization of women in their roles as wives and mothers during the early 19c.",
        "distractor1": "an aspect of the Salem witchcraft trials of 1692, in which mainly middle-aged matrons were accused of practicing evil magic.",
        "distractor2": "the Shakers, a religious sect founded by Mother Ann Lee in the 18c.",
        "distractor3": "the defense given by antebellum apologists for slavery, who argued that bondage was a form of benevolent paternalism.",
        "distractor4": "the Puritans' insistence on the importance of the family as the cornerstone of their social order."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Know-Nothing Party?:",
        "correct_answer": "demanded an end to immigration into the United States.",
        "distractor1": "wanted to limit the rights of freed slaves in the South.",
        "distractor2": "advocated prohibiting the teaching of evolution in the public schools.",
        "distractor3": "backed the early efforts of unskilled workers to form unions.",
        "distractor4": "supported the claims of farmers against the railroads."
    },
    {
        "question": "Large numbers of Irish immigrants came to the United States in the 1840s because of the?:",
        "correct_answer": "massive failure of the potato crop in Ireland.",
        "distractor1": "persecution of Irish Catholics in the rest of Europe.",
        "distractor2": "lure of gold in California.",
        "distractor3": "civil war between North Ireland and the rest of the country.",
        "distractor4": "British military aggression in Ireland."
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following were aspects of Protestantism in the United States during the period 1800-1850 EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "a growing consensus for the abolition of slavery.",
        "distractor1": "evangelism and revivalism.",
        "distractor2": "the proliferation of Protestant church sects.",
        "distractor3": "the founding of denominational colleges.",
        "distractor4": "the growth and spread of both foreign and domestic missionary societies."
    },
    {
        "question": "The art of the Hudson River school may be described as?:",
        "correct_answer": "classically romantic, expressing an air of wonder at the mystery of nature.",
        "distractor1": "brutally realistic in its depiction of often unpleasant subjects.",
        "distractor2": "concentrating on grimy scenes of everyday life in crowded New York City tenements.",
        "distractor3": "almost completely abstract.",
        "distractor4": "concerned with portraiture to the exclusion of significant landscape painting."
    },
    {
        "question": "Mark Twain's classic stories, such as Tom Sawyer and Huckleberry Finn, were primary examples of the ? trend in",
        "correct_answer": "realistic.",
        "distractor1": "romantic.",
        "distractor2": "gothic.",
        "distractor3": "fantasy.",
        "distractor4": "heroic."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Lyceum movement in the United States is a term that refers to which of the following?:",
        "correct_answer": "the lectures on educational topics given by a series of speakers who traveled from city to city.",
        "distractor1": "the founding of a series of communities based on the doctrines of utopian French socialism.",
        "distractor2": "the efforts by classicists to reintroduce Latin into the public school curriculum.",
        "distractor3": "the Greek Revival in architecture in New England.",
        "distractor4": "the movement to support the Greek war of independence of 1820-1830."
    },
    {
        "question": "Horace Mann championed which of the following educational reforms?:",
        "correct_answer": "professional teacher training.",
        "distractor1": "gradeless, open-concept schools.",
        "distractor2": "local curricular decisions.",
        "distractor3": "private funding and control.",
        "distractor4": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "The cultural nationalism of American intellectuals of the 1800s generally?:",
        "correct_answer": "celebrated the uniqueness of the American democratic spirit.",
        "distractor1": "was based on the autocratic political systems of Europe.",
        "distractor2": "paid tribute to the superiority of the British in all artistic matters.",
        "distractor3": "copied extensively the elitist values of Old World regimes."
    },
    {
        "question": "The role of the ideal woman in antebellum America was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "create a clean and wholesome home for family life.",
        "distractor1": "perform complementary tasks in the family's struggle to get ahead.",
        "distractor2": "produce vital goods or earn money necessary for the family's subsistence.",
        "distractor3": "pursue a rewarding and professional career."
    },
    {
        "question": "The doctrine of  separate spheres  suggested that?:",
        "correct_answer": "men were superior in worldly pursuits, and women were superior for their moral influence.",
        "distractor1": "children and parents should not mingle socially throughout the day, but gather only together at the dinner table.",
        "distractor2": "moral issues were to be determined by the church, while economic issues were to be determined by the family.",
        "distractor3": "none of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "American Tories believed that?:",
        "correct_answer": "separation from Britain was an illegal act that would ignite an unnecessary war.",
        "distractor1": "Parliament had the right to tax the colonies.",
        "distractor2": "only independence could preserve the colonists' constitutional rights.",
        "distractor3": "the king, not Parliament, was responsible for the problems facing the colonies."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Battle of Saratoga resulted in?:",
        "correct_answer": "France entering the war on the side of the colonies.",
        "distractor1": "an embarrassing defeat for the Continental Army.",
        "distractor2": "an unsuccessful peace overture from Lord North.",
        "distractor3": "renewed efforts of the Loyalists to enlist colonial support.",
        "distractor4": "the treason of Benedict Arnold."
    },
    {
        "question": "Spinning bees and dressing down in homespun?:",
        "correct_answer": "contributed to the solidarity of resistance by displaying fewer differences in appearance between rich and poor.",
        "distractor1": "were ways in which poor women were forced to support the Army.",
        "distractor2": "were tactics used by loyalists to demonstrate that independence would lower the American standard of living.",
        "distractor3": "helped to raise money and provide clothing for the Continental Army."
    },
    {
        "question": "George Washington's primary goal as commander-in-chief of the continental Army was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "avoid decisive military losses.",
        "distractor1": "prevent British reinforcements from coming ashore.",
        "distractor2": "destroy the British Army.",
        "distractor3": "secure financial aid from foreign sources."
    },
    {
        "question": "Some Indian nations joined the British during the Revolutionary War because?:",
        "correct_answer": "they believed that a British victory would restrain American expansion into the West.",
        "distractor1": "the British threatened them with destruction if they did not help.",
        "distractor2": "the British hired them as mercenaries.",
        "distractor3": "none of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was NOT one of the provisions of the Peace of Paris (1783)?:",
        "correct_answer": "Congress would restore all property confiscated from Loyalists during the war.",
        "distractor1": "Florida was given to Spain.",
        "distractor2": "Congress would not prevent the British merchants from collecting debts owed to them by Americans.",
        "distractor3": "the Mississippi River was recognized as the western boundary of the United States."
    },
    {
        "question": "White residents in South Carolina and Georgia were more restrained in their revolutionary expressions than were counterparts",
        "correct_answer": "fearful that talk of rebellion would inspire slaves to revolt.",
        "distractor1": "primarily rice planters, unaffected by British restrictions.",
        "distractor2": "Anglican and loyal to the Church of England.",
        "distractor3": "closely tied to families back in England."
    },
    {
        "question": "The new state constitutions adopted during the American Revolution?:",
        "correct_answer": "generally protected the people's civil liberties with a bill of rights.",
        "distractor1": "eliminated all property qualifications for voting.",
        "distractor2": "generally did not contain a bill of rights.",
        "distractor3": "abolished the office of governor.",
        "distractor4": "provided for unicameral legislatures."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the Revolution, women took on new responsibilities. After the war?:",
        "correct_answer": "things generally went back to the way they were before and few concrete reforms occurred in the status of women.",
        "distractor1": "women were able to translate wartime gains into peacetime reforms.",
        "distractor2": "women were recognized and honored for their contributions with new careers.",
        "distractor3": "women got the right to vote in most northern colonies."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was NOT TRUE about slavery as a labor system?:",
        "correct_answer": "as slavery spread into the Deep South, wealth and power became more equally shared among the various classes of white southerners.",
        "distractor1": "slavery was worth more in terms of investment than all the land in the South.",
        "distractor2": "it was slavery that made possible the South's  mass production  of agriculture products for export.",
        "distractor3": "only a minority of Southerners owned slaves."
    },
    {
        "question": "Manufacturing in the Old South lagged behind that in the North because?:",
        "correct_answer": "cotton was a more profitable investment.",
        "distractor1": "black labor was incompatible with industry.",
        "distractor2": "white leaders in the South were more concerned with prestige than with profits.",
        "distractor3": "the South lacked important natural resources."
    },
    {
        "question": "The paternalistic view of slavery held that?:",
        "correct_answer": "slavery was necessary to protect blacks from the mistreatment and abuse they would receive if they were freed.",
        "distractor1": "slavery was a necessary evil that should be phased out as soon as was economically possible.",
        "distractor2": "slavery was a totally unjustifiable abuse of humanity demanding immediate abolition.",
        "distractor3": "slavery was an artifact of a more primitive past that would eventually fade out on its own.",
        "distractor4": "slavery was necessary to keep blacks from developing their superior potential and eventually dominating the white race."
    },
    {
        "question": "What lesson did white southerners learn from the Nat Turner Rebellion?:",
        "correct_answer": "that slave insurrections were an ever-present threat.",
        "distractor1": "that gradual emancipation was inevitable.",
        "distractor2": "that slaves should not be allowed to work in cities.",
        "distractor3": "that slaves should not be allowed to read the Bible."
    },
    {
        "question": "Hinton R. Helper's  The Impending Crisis of the South  was intended as?:",
        "correct_answer": "an argument against slavery as an economic institution.",
        "distractor1": "a refutation of Harriet Beecher Stowe's  Uncle Tom's Cabin .",
        "distractor2": "a rallying cry against abolitionism.",
        "distractor3": "a condemnation of the violent acts of Preston Brooks.",
        "distractor4": "a rational defense of the practice of slavery."
    },
    {
        "question": "Antislavery sentiment underlay the formation in 1840 of the?:",
        "correct_answer": "Liberty Party.",
        "distractor1": "Democratic Party.",
        "distractor2": "Union Party.",
        "distractor3": "Republican Party.",
        "distractor4": "Know-Nothing Party."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which was true of free blacks living in the North during the thirty years prior to the Civil War?:",
        "correct_answer": "racial tensions often exploded into riots.",
        "distractor1": "all Northern states granted free blacks the right to vote.",
        "distractor2": "public facilities were integrated.",
        "distractor3": "economic opportunities for employment matched those given to recent immigrants.",
        "distractor4": "free public education was open to blacks."
    },
    {
        "question": "The American Colonization Society was an antislavery organization that?:",
        "correct_answer": "advocated the forced shipment of freed slaves to Africa.",
        "distractor1": "advocated racial equality.",
        "distractor2": "sought full political rights for blacks.",
        "distractor3": "favored immediate emancipation.",
        "distractor4": "relied upon governmental action to end slavery."
    },
    {
        "question": "The southern demand that slavery be allowed to expand into the territories seems to have been motivated by the?:",
        "correct_answer": "fear that free territories could be used as bases for spreading abolitionism into the South.",
        "distractor1": "expectation that slavery would be even more profitable in the West than in the South.",
        "distractor2": "belief that expansion was necessary to allow the profitable sale of surplus southern slaves.",
        "distractor3": "assumption of southern politicians that they should put forward extreme positions as a tactic in political bargaining with the North."
    },
    {
        "question": "William Lloyd Garrison pledged his dedication to?:",
        "correct_answer": "the immediate abolition of slavery in the South.",
        "distractor1": "shipping freed blacks back to Africa.",
        "distractor2": "outlawing the slave trade.",
        "distractor3": "preventing the expansion of slavery beyond the South."
    },
    {
        "question": "Before the Civil War, the abolitionists used all of the following tactics EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "asking Congress for laws outlawing slavery in the states.",
        "distractor1": "using moral persuasion on slaveholders.",
        "distractor2": "providing assistance to escaped slaves.",
        "distractor3": "lobbying state legislatures for  personal liberty  laws."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the late 1850s, the free laborites of the North came to believe in all of the following ideas EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "slavery was such a moral evil that it must be abolished quickly.",
        "distractor1": "the perfect society was one of small-scale capitalism that allowed everyone a chance at upward mobility.",
        "distractor2": "southern society was so backward that it constituted a threat to democracy and individualism.",
        "distractor3": "the South was engaged in a conspiracy to extend slavery throughout the nation."
    },
    {
        "question": "The most divisive and controversial aspect of the slavery issue during the first half of the 19c was?:",
        "correct_answer": "the status of slavery in the territories.",
        "distractor1": "the right of abolitionists to send their literature throughout the U. S. mail.",
        "distractor2": "the enforcement of the draconian Fugitive Slave Law.",
        "distractor3": "the status of slavery in the District of Columbia.",
        "distractor4": "the prohibition of international slave trade."
    },
    {
        "question": "Approximately how many slaves would half of all slaveowning families have owned?:",
        "correct_answer": "fewer than 5.",
        "distractor1": "25 to 50.",
        "distractor2": "50 to 100.",
        "distractor3": "100 or more."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the significance of Harriet Beecher Stowe's  Uncle Tom's Cabin ?:",
        "correct_answer": "it provoked a more aggressive antisouthern and antislavery position in those who were uncertain on the slavery issue.",
        "distractor1": "it contradicted prevailing stereotypes that described dark-skinned blacks as docile and submissive and light-skinned blacks as aggressive and",
        "distractor2": "by presenting a dynamic slave society, the book challenged the common notion that slavery tore apart the black family.",
        "distractor3": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "The upper class plantation mistress?:",
        "correct_answer": "faced an unexpected variety of burdensome managerial and service duties.",
        "distractor1": "accepted a sexual code that kept white women pure, but tolerated sexual relations between white men and slave women.",
        "distractor2": "lived lives of leisure centered around artistic and literary pursuits.",
        "distractor3": "enjoyed the unique luxury of criticizing their own role in society as well as the slave system in general."
    },
    {
        "question": "The split in the American Anti-Slavery Society in 1840 was over the issue of?:",
        "correct_answer": "the right of women to participate in the antislavery society.",
        "distractor1": "the colonization of freed blacks in Africa.",
        "distractor2": "the right of blacks to speak in racially mixed gatherings.",
        "distractor3": "the role of blacks and women in the antislavery movement."
    },
    {
        "question": "What impact did slavery have on the southern value system?:",
        "correct_answer": "the acceptance of slave labor had the effect of devaluing free labor in the South.",
        "distractor1": "slavery created a strong sense of community responsibility among the white majority.",
        "distractor2": "the presence of slave labor created an egalitarian value system among the white majority.",
        "distractor3": "slavery created constant tension between slaveowners and non-slaveowners."
    },
    {
        "question": "Harriet Tubman gained fame?:",
        "correct_answer": "by helping slaves to escape to Canada.",
        "distractor1": "in the gold fields of California.",
        "distractor2": "as an African-American poet.",
        "distractor3": "as an advocate of the Fugitive Slave Law."
    },
    {
        "question": "Between 1830 and 1860, many southerners came to defend slavery because of all of the following reasons EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "they saw how the North silenced those with pro-slavery opinions while they remained tolerant of opposition.",
        "distractor1": "the growth of the cotton economy made slavery very profitable again.",
        "distractor2": "they believed slaves were better off than the poor  unfortunate people who worked in northern factories.",
        "distractor3": "the attacks of the abolitionists pushed them into defending the southern way of life."
    },
    {
        "question": "King Philip's War of 1675-1676 was fought to?:",
        "correct_answer": "establish English control over the Indians in New England.",
        "distractor1": "remove Spanish Catholics from Florida.",
        "distractor2": "end Spanish control over the African slave trade.",
        "distractor3": "establish New England trade with the West Indies.",
        "distractor4": "stop the French from settling the Ohio River Valley."
    },
    {
        "question": "Great Britain sought to control colonial trade because?:",
        "correct_answer": "it did not want competition with its own manufacturers.",
        "distractor1": "colonial products were inferior to British products.",
        "distractor2": "the colonies were seeking political independence.",
        "distractor3": "colonial products were too expensive.",
        "distractor4": "the colonies were unable to establish trade with France and Spain."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is properly considered the main purpose of the Navigation Acts?:",
        "correct_answer": "to guarantee that England alone would profit from trade with the colonies.",
        "distractor1": "the promotion of trade among the colonies.",
        "distractor2": "the protection of American manufacturing from foreign competition.",
        "distractor3": "to raise revenue for maintaining the British Empire.",
        "distractor4": "the regulation of the slave trade in the colonies."
    },
    {
        "question": "The considerable powers that colonial governors possessed included all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "control over taxes and the budget.",
        "distractor1": "the right to veto acts.",
        "distractor2": "the power to call or dismiss assembly sessions at will.",
        "distractor3": "the authority to schedule elections at any time."
    },
    {
        "question": "The trial of John Peter Zenger in 1735 for seditious libel?:",
        "correct_answer": "encouraged editors to be more critical of public officials.",
        "distractor1": "established the government's right to censor the press.",
        "distractor2": "resulted in a  hung jury  and a dismissal of the charges.",
        "distractor3": "determined that government censorship of the press was unconstitutional.",
        "distractor4": "found Zenger guilty."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following nations was forced out of its colonial holdings in North America in the 17c?:",
        "correct_answer": "the Netherlands.",
        "distractor1": "Spain.",
        "distractor2": "England.",
        "distractor3": "France.",
        "distractor4": "Portugal."
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to 1763, the British policy of  salutary neglect ?:",
        "correct_answer": "did not enforce the Navigation Acts.",
        "distractor1": "allowed royal colonies to elect their own governors.",
        "distractor2": "took the Royal Navy off the high seas.",
        "distractor3": "encouraged colonists to establish their own parliament.",
        "distractor4": "withdrew British soldiers from North America."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following best describes the power generally exercised by British colonial governors in the American",
        "correct_answer": "they exercised less power than they were permitted because of legislative control of taxing and spending.",
        "distractor1": "they exercised more power than they were legally permitted because of royal support.",
        "distractor2": "they exercised more power than they were legally permitted through the use of patronage.",
        "distractor3": "they exercised less power than they were permitted because they were chosen by the colonial legislatures.",
        "distractor4": "they exercised less power than they were permitted because they were popularly elected."
    },
    {
        "question": "The right to vote for members of the colonial assemblies was?:",
        "correct_answer": "extended to a greater proportion of the population than anywhere else in the world of the 18c.",
        "distractor1": "greatly restricted because of high property qualifications.",
        "distractor2": "open to women in most of the colonies.",
        "distractor3": "restricted to Protestants.",
        "distractor4": "none of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "Bacon's Rebellion was supported mainly by?:",
        "correct_answer": "young men frustrated by their inability to acquire land.",
        "distractor1": "the planter class of Virginia.",
        "distractor2": "those protesting the increased importation of African slaves.",
        "distractor3": "people from Jamestown only."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the presidency of George Bush, the United States worked closely with the United Nations in all of the following",
        "correct_answer": "ouster of Manuel Noriega from Panama.",
        "distractor1": "attempts to minimize civilian suffering in Bosnia.",
        "distractor2": "ouster of Iraqi troops from Kuwait.",
        "distractor3": "aid to Somalia.",
        "distractor4": "attempts to limit the spread of nuclear weapons."
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following ways was Operation Desert Storm different from the Vietnam War?:",
        "correct_answer": "all of these choices are correct.",
        "distractor1": "President Bush built a consensus for action.",
        "distractor2": "President Bush articulated a clear military objective.",
        "distractor3": "President Bush provided the military support necessary to achieve the goal."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Bush administration succeeded in easing tensions in all of the following areas EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "Bosnia.",
        "distractor1": "Kuwait.",
        "distractor2": "Panama.",
        "distractor3": "Somalia.",
        "distractor4": "Middle East."
    },
    {
        "question": "The U. S. Senate faced a major controversy during the Bush administration when the president?:",
        "correct_answer": "nominated Clarence Thomas, a conservative African American judge, as an associate justice.",
        "distractor1": "refused to nominate to the Supreme Court Jesse Jackson, who had the overwhelming support of African Americans.",
        "distractor2": "requested that the Court reaffirm the  Roe v. Wade  decision of the Burger Court.",
        "distractor3": "refused to accept Justice Thurgood Marshall's retirement because it was important to have an African American on the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor4": "nominated General Colin Powell to the Court to remove him as a presidential rival in the 1992 race."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following best describes the Bush administration's approach to the problem of the growing federal budget",
        "correct_answer": "despite Bush's  no new taxes  pledge, he worked out a multiyear budget package with Congress that included a significant tax increase.",
        "distractor1": "massive spending cuts proposed by Bush were adopted by Congress, and the deficit declined for the first time since the 1970s.",
        "distractor2": "Congress passed a deficit-reduction plan composed of small spending cuts and large tax increases, but Bush vetoed it.",
        "distractor3": "Bush proposed a major tax increase, but conservative Republicans teamed with liberal Democrats to defeat it."
    },
    {
        "question": "In response to the Tiananmen Square massacre, the Bush administration?:",
        "correct_answer": "expressed revulsion but took no steps to punish the Chinese government.",
        "distractor1": "severed diplomatic relations with the People's Republic of China.",
        "distractor2": "introduced and gained passage of a United Nations resolution placing severe economic sanctions on the People's Republic of China.",
        "distractor3": "immediately denied China most-favored nation status in its trade with the United States."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following best expresses George Bush's philosophy about the role of government in solving social and",
        "correct_answer": "the government should play only a minimal role in solving the nation's social and economic problems.",
        "distractor1": "the adoption of Keynesian economic policy is the best way to solve the social and economic problems stemming from a recession.",
        "distractor2": "the government must act aggressively and decisively to reduce the deficit, for by so doing, the nation's economic and social problems may then be solved.",
        "distractor3": "the government must establish job-training programs for the unemployed and fund a comprehensive research and development program to help American industry stay"
    },
    {
        "question": "President Bush signed all of the following pieces of legislation EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "the Equal Rights Amendment.",
        "distractor1": "the Clean Air Act of 1990.",
        "distractor2": "the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1991.",
        "distractor3": "the act authorizing the federal government to bail out the savings and loan industry."
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following occurred after the fall of the Berlin Wall in 1989 EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "the beginning of  perestroika  and  glasnost .",
        "distractor1": "the breakup of the Soviet Union into separate nations.",
        "distractor2": "the outbreak of warfare in Yugoslavia.",
        "distractor3": "the emergence of President Yeltsin as the leader of Russia.",
        "distractor4": "the support of the Russian economy by the International Monetary Fund."
    },
    {
        "question": "One of George Bush's last decisions as president was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "pardon several figures connected to the Iran-Contra scandal.",
        "distractor1": "withdraw American troops from Somalia.",
        "distractor2": "send American troops to Bosnia.",
        "distractor3": "call for an investigation of the House banking scandal."
    },
    {
        "question": "An important factor in the rapid development of industry in the United States during the last half of the 19c was?:",
        "correct_answer": "the availability of capital for investment purposes.",
        "distractor1": "increasing competition in the oil business.",
        "distractor2": "a stable economic cycle.",
        "distractor3": "effective regulation of monopolistic business practices by the national government."
    },
    {
        "question": "In its approach to union organization, the Knights of Labor officially?:",
        "correct_answer": "welcomed both skilled and unskilled workers.",
        "distractor1": "stressed the organization of workers by craft.",
        "distractor2": "encouraged the use of the strike.",
        "distractor3": "discriminated against Blacks and women."
    },
    {
        "question": "A long-range influence of Samuel Gompers on the American labor movement was his advocacy of?:",
        "correct_answer": "non-involvement in party politics.",
        "distractor1": "unrestricted immigration.",
        "distractor2": "industrial unionism.",
        "distractor3": "compulsory arbitration of industrial disputes.",
        "distractor4": "government regulation of hours and wages."
    },
    {
        "question": "The concept of  limited liability  contributed to the development of corporations and was appealing to many",
        "correct_answer": "all of these choices are correct.",
        "distractor1": "they risked only their own investment and were not responsible for the debts of the corporation.",
        "distractor2": "they did not have to be personally involved in the corporation to purchase stock in it.",
        "distractor3": "entrepreneurs could now amass great sums of money for investment purposes."
    },
    {
        "question": "The  Gospel of Wealth,  as advanced by Andrew Carnegie, promoted the concept that people with wealth should?:",
        "correct_answer": "use their resources to help society.",
        "distractor1": "give aid directly to the poor.",
        "distractor2": "devout time to the public welfare.",
        "distractor3": "donate the bulk of their wealth to religious institutions."
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the most significant aspects of the Interstate Commerce Act was that it?:",
        "correct_answer": "represented the first large-scale attempt by the federal government to regulate business.",
        "distractor1": "revolutionized the business system.",
        "distractor2": "actually did nothing to control the abuses of big business.",
        "distractor3": "failed to prohibit some of the worst abuses of big business, such as pools and rebates."
    },
    {
        "question": "J. P. Morgan monitored his competition by placing officers of his bank on the board of companies that he wanted to",
        "correct_answer": "interlocking directorate.",
        "distractor1": "trust.",
        "distractor2": "pool.",
        "distractor3": "vertical integration.",
        "distractor4": "horizontal integration."
    },
    {
        "question": "The first  big business  in America, at least in terms of finance, labor relations, and management, was?:",
        "correct_answer": "the railroad industry.",
        "distractor1": "the oil refining industry.",
        "distractor2": "the telephone industry.",
        "distractor3": "the movie industry.",
        "distractor4": "the steel industry."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court in the  United States v. Knight Company ?:",
        "correct_answer": "diminished the effectiveness of the Sherman Anti-Trust Act by ruling that manufacturing was not interstate commerce.",
        "distractor1": "declared the Granger laws unconstitutional because states could not regulate interstate commerce.",
        "distractor2": "ruled that all trusts and monopolies in interstate commerce were illegal and could be broken up by the federal government.",
        "distractor3": "held that employers could force employees to sign and abide by  yellow dog contracts. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Why did the proportion of women working in clerical jobs increase in the late 19c and early",
        "correct_answer": "because many women had taken typing and shorthand courses in school, employers did not have to invest much in training them.",
        "distractor1": "because women had smaller hands than men, they were better typists.",
        "distractor2": "clerical work demanded many different skills that women usually possessed.",
        "distractor3": "clerical jobs usually led to the managerial positions that most working women desired."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Interstate Commerce Act of 1887 and the Sherman Anti-Trust Act of 1890 had in common the fact that they?:",
        "correct_answer": "were greatly strengthened by the Supreme Court in the years after they were passed.",
        "distractor1": "convinced the Populists that they had achieved their goals.",
        "distractor2": "ended the Republican domination of the U. S. Senate.",
        "distractor3": "had no impact on the U. S. economy for several years after they were passed.",
        "distractor4": "were intended to do away with the spoils system in politics."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of governmental assistance was most helpful to labor during the period 1876-1914?:",
        "correct_answer": "state legislation.",
        "distractor1": "Presidential support in nationwide strikes.",
        "distractor2": "amendments to the federal Constitution.",
        "distractor3": "federal legislation.",
        "distractor4": "Supreme Court decisions."
    },
    {
        "question": "Labor unions were ruled not to be illegal conspiracies provided that their methods were honorable and peaceful in the",
        "correct_answer": " Commonwealth v. Hunt  (1842).",
        "distractor1": " Brown v. Board of Education  (1954).",
        "distractor2": " Plessy v. Ferguson  (1896).",
        "distractor3": " Munn v. Illinois  (1876)."
    },
    {
        "question": "The 1880s movement for the eight-hour working day is usually associated with which of the following labor",
        "correct_answer": "the Knights of Labor.",
        "distractor1": "the Teamsters Union.",
        "distractor2": "the Industrial Workers of the World.",
        "distractor3": "the Congress of Industrial Organizations.",
        "distractor4": "the International Ladies' Garment Workers Union."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following best accounts for the success of Standard Oil?:",
        "correct_answer": "its corporate structure--known as horizontal integration--allowed the company to grow tremendously.",
        "distractor1": "its scientists developed processes for refining oil more efficiently.",
        "distractor2": "it bought out the Erie Railroad in order to keep transportation charges low.",
        "distractor3": "it was one of the first companies to invest heavily in advertising."
    },
    {
        "question": "Terence V. Powderly, head of the Knights of Labor, advocated?:",
        "correct_answer": "all of these choices are correct.",
        "distractor1": "a gradual end to the wage system and the reorganization of society on cooperative principles.",
        "distractor2": "temperance.",
        "distractor3": "the admission of blacks into local Knights of Labor assemblies."
    },
    {
        "question": " Yellow dog  contracts were contracts?:",
        "correct_answer": "in which workers promised not to strike or join a union.",
        "distractor1": "in which employers agreed not to hire Chinese immigrants.",
        "distractor2": "that guaranteed that only union members would be hired.",
        "distractor3": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "A major reason for the low wages of unskilled workers throughout the late 19c was that?:",
        "correct_answer": "management was able to draw on cheap labor on a global scale.",
        "distractor1": "most industries simply made too little profit and thus were unable to pass on higher wages to labor.",
        "distractor2": "the great expense of modern factories and equipment made higher wages impossible.",
        "distractor3": "the cost of living was lower, and so workers required less in wages."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 19c, railroads formed pools in order to?:",
        "correct_answer": "fix prices and divide business for greater profit.",
        "distractor1": "share equipment and terminals for greater efficiency.",
        "distractor2": "inflate the value of assets and profits before selling the stock.",
        "distractor3": "better serve farmers in remote rural areas.",
        "distractor4": "increase competition by dividing up large companies into smaller ones."
    },
    {
        "question": "A closed shop requires workers to?:",
        "correct_answer": "join a union to secure a job.",
        "distractor1": "receive national security clearance.",
        "distractor2": "promise not to join a union.",
        "distractor3": "receive their pay in cash.",
        "distractor4": "apply for unemployment benefits."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Haymarket bombing of May 4, 1886, was important to the labor movement because it?:",
        "correct_answer": "aroused public opposition against labor, contributed to the decline of the Knights of Labor, and caused an increase in the membership of the AFL.",
        "distractor1": "brought about the use of collective bargaining to settle labor disputes peacefully.",
        "distractor2": "demonstrated to unskilled workers their vulnerability to strikebreaking actions.",
        "distractor3": "began a tradition of federal intervention by U. S. troops."
    },
    {
        "question": "Why was the Clayton Anti-Trust Act an improvement over the Sherman Anti-Trust Act?:",
        "correct_answer": "labor unions and farm organizations were no longer considered as monopolies in restraint of trade.",
        "distractor1": "its execution was placed squarely in the Attorney General's hands.",
        "distractor2": "for the first time the actions of labor unions were not restricted.",
        "distractor3": "penalties in the form of fines and imprisonment were to be imposed on unions.",
        "distractor4": "labor unions as well as trusts were defined as monopolies in restraint of trade."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the case of  Gibbons v. Ogden , the United States Supreme Court did which of the following?:",
        "correct_answer": "affirmed the power of the federal government over commerce.",
        "distractor1": "upheld the sanctity of contracts.",
        "distractor2": "ruled that federal, rather than state, legislation applied to Native Americans.",
        "distractor3": "held a state law void because it conflicted with a provision of the United States Constitution.",
        "distractor4": "affirmed its power to declare acts of Congress unconstitutional."
    },
    {
        "question": "By the end of the 1800s, the use of pools, trusts, and holding companies by big business resulted in?:",
        "correct_answer": "a concentration of economic power in the hands of a few.",
        "distractor1": "a slowing in the growth rate of the economy.",
        "distractor2": "a more even distribution of wealth.",
        "distractor3": "an increase in costs of production.",
        "distractor4": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following were important factors in post-Civil War industrial expansion EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "immigration restrictions.",
        "distractor1": "a large pool of unskilled labor.",
        "distractor2": "American ingenuity and inventiveness.",
        "distractor3": "an abundance of natural resources."
    },
    {
        "question": "Many employers cut wages in the late 19c by?:",
        "correct_answer": "hiring women and children.",
        "distractor1": "eliminating pension plans.",
        "distractor2": "hiring skilled workers.",
        "distractor3": "eliminating health insurance plans."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Grover Cleveland responded to the 1894 Pullman strike by?:",
        "correct_answer": "intervening on the side of management.",
        "distractor1": "offering to serve as a mediator.",
        "distractor2": "remaining uninvolved and doing nothing.",
        "distractor3": "intervening on the side of labor."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the West, the immigrants who bore the brunt of labor hostility in the 1870s and 1880s were?:",
        "correct_answer": "Chinese.",
        "distractor1": "Jewish.",
        "distractor2": "German.",
        "distractor3": "Irish Catholic.",
        "distractor4": "Russian."
    },
    {
        "question": "Labor relations at the end of the 19c were?:",
        "correct_answer": "characterized by violence and thousands of strikes.",
        "distractor1": "relatively peaceful because welfare paternalism prevailed and employers treated employees like family.",
        "distractor2": "relatively peaceful because employers had successfully eliminated labor unrest.",
        "distractor3": "occasionally turbulent, but most grievances were dealt with effectively through collective bargaining."
    },
    {
        "question": "The ideas of Social Darwinism allowed men of wealth, like Carnegie and Rockefeller, to?:",
        "correct_answer": "justify the economic inequality that favored them over the nation's poor.",
        "distractor1": "argue for more government intervention in dealing with social problems.",
        "distractor2": "create more humanitarian programs for their factory laborers.",
        "distractor3": "become more humanitarian in their declining years."
    },
    {
        "question": "At the outset, President Lincoln held that the Civil War was being fought to?:",
        "correct_answer": "preserve the Union.",
        "distractor1": "end all state sovereignty.",
        "distractor2": "carry out the goals of the abolitionist movement.",
        "distractor3": "free the slaves.",
        "distractor4": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the Civil War, Kansas and Missouri were?:",
        "correct_answer": "ravaged by guerilla bands from both sides.",
        "distractor1": "away from the fighting, thus largely peaceful.",
        "distractor2": "the scene of four major battles.",
        "distractor3": "attacked by Indians allied with the Confederacy."
    },
    {
        "question": "The major battle in the western theater during the Civil War which had the effect of splitting the Confederacy in half",
        "correct_answer": "Vicksburg.",
        "distractor1": "the Battle of the Wilderness.",
        "distractor2": "Gettysburg.",
        "distractor3": "Antietam.",
        "distractor4": "First Bull Run."
    },
    {
        "question": "Why did both the South and North experience rioting during the Civil War?:",
        "correct_answer": "in the South over food; in the North over the draft.",
        "distractor1": "in the South over easing slave codes; in the North over jailing dissidents.",
        "distractor2": "on both sides, over military regulations like the draft and economic controls.",
        "distractor3": "on both sides, over centralization of political power."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the Civil War, southern women played an especially important part as?:",
        "correct_answer": "managers of farms and plantations.",
        "distractor1": "typists and telegraph operators.",
        "distractor2": "members of auxiliary units of the armed forces.",
        "distractor3": "replacements for men in the South's light industries."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Emancipation Proclamation?:",
        "correct_answer": "freed slaves only in areas in rebellion against the United States but not in areas that remained loyal.",
        "distractor1": "freed the slaves and abolished slavery in all the states of the Union and the Confederacy.",
        "distractor2": "was formulated by the Radical Republicans and issued by Lincoln despite his strong personal objections.",
        "distractor3": "convinced England and France to enter the war on behalf of the Union in order to win the crusade against slavery."
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States Congress during the Civil War?:",
        "correct_answer": "adopted a tariff, a homestead law, and a transcontinental railroad.",
        "distractor1": "could do little because of the absent southern representatives.",
        "distractor2": "due to a lack of funds neglected legislation not directly related to the war.",
        "distractor3": "played a major role in choosing and firing generals to lead the Union forces."
    },
    {
        "question": "Suspension of the writ of habeas corpus for all people living between Washington and Philadelphia provides evidence of",
        "correct_answer": "presidential power increased during the Civil War.",
        "distractor1": "local law enforcement collapsed in many northern states.",
        "distractor2": "Union generals often usurped presidential power.",
        "distractor3": "Congressional power increased during the Civil War."
    },
    {
        "question": "The key event that guaranteed Lincoln's re-election in 1864 was?:",
        "correct_answer": "the fall of Atlanta to General Sherman.",
        "distractor1": "the fall of Vicksburg to General Grant.",
        "distractor2": "the capture of New Orleans by Admiral Farragut.",
        "distractor3": "the defeat of Lee's army by General Meade at Gettysburg.",
        "distractor4": "the successful defense of Nashville by General Thomas against repeated Confederate counterattacks."
    },
    {
        "question": "The final Union war strategy included all of the following components EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "guerilla warfare.",
        "distractor1": "undermining the Confederate economy.",
        "distractor2": "a naval blockade.",
        "distractor3": "seizing control of the Mississippi River."
    },
    {
        "question": "The content of the Constitution of the Confederate States of America indicated that a major difference between the South and",
        "correct_answer": "the federal relationship of the states and the national government.",
        "distractor1": "the role of the executive.",
        "distractor2": "representation in Congress.",
        "distractor3": "the impact of Supreme Court decisions."
    },
    {
        "question": "Sea power played an especially important role in the Civil War in the form of the?:",
        "correct_answer": "Union blockade of the Confederate coast.",
        "distractor1": "Confederate raids on northern shipping.",
        "distractor2": "transportation of revel troops and supplies on steamboats.",
        "distractor3": "ironclad ships that appeared during the war."
    },
    {
        "question": "In foreign affairs, President Lincoln's most significant achievement was his success in?:",
        "correct_answer": "restraining foreign powers from recognizing the Confederacy.",
        "distractor1": "gaining the support of the czar of Russia for the Union cause.",
        "distractor2": "negotiating the demilitarization of the Canadian-American boundary.",
        "distractor3": "meeting the challenge to the Monroe Doctrine in Mexico.",
        "distractor4": "establishing claims to islands in the Pacific."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Battle of Antietam was?:",
        "correct_answer": "the bloodiest single day's fighting of the war.",
        "distractor1": "a victory for General Lee's Army of Northern Virginia.",
        "distractor2": "a proof to President Lincoln of the inspired leadership of General George B. McClellan.",
        "distractor3": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the Civil War, northern black leaders such as Frederick Douglass worked as army recruiting agents because they believed",
        "correct_answer": "black participation in the army would be a step toward black citizenship.",
        "distractor1": "it was the best way to prevent blacks from being drafted.",
        "distractor2": "blacks were more resistant to the diseases that ravaged white soldiers in the garrisons.",
        "distractor3": "blacks would get to see their loved ones in the South only by fighting for the Union."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the Civil War, most of the Five Civilized Tribes in the Indian Territory of present-day Oklahoma?:",
        "correct_answer": "supported the Confederacy.",
        "distractor1": "remained neutral.",
        "distractor2": "supported the Union.",
        "distractor3": "gave up their slaves."
    },
    {
        "question": "States that sold public lands granted to them under the Morrill Land Grant Act of 1862 were required to use the income",
        "correct_answer": "promote public education in agriculture.",
        "distractor1": "subsidize the construction of factories important to the war effort.",
        "distractor2": "train and supply state militia units.",
        "distractor3": "provide loans to railroad construction companies."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was Jefferson Davis' central problem?:",
        "correct_answer": "in a society that prized states' rights, Davis had to centralize authority.",
        "distractor1": "in a culture that prized the English country gentry, Davis was rough-hewn and awkward.",
        "distractor2": "in a crisis that demanded tough-minded attention to military details, Davis was more of a grand strategist.",
        "distractor3": "in a war that required rapid mobilization of a whole society, most ordinary folk in the south expected a protracted conflict and hence were reluctant to"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the Civil War, the term  Copperhead  referred to?:",
        "correct_answer": "Northerners who opposed the Civil War.",
        "distractor1": "Northerners who supported slavery.",
        "distractor2": "Southerners who opposed the Confederacy.",
        "distractor3": "Northerners who called for the abolition of slavery.",
        "distractor4": "Southerners who called for the abolition of slavery."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Battle of Gettysburg was significant because it?:",
        "correct_answer": "inflicted a major loss on General Lee's army.",
        "distractor1": "led to an immediate end to the war.",
        "distractor2": "opened an invasion route to the North.",
        "distractor3": "cut off supplies to states west of the Mississippi River."
    },
    {
        "question": "What general theme did Bill Clinton stress most consistently in his 1992 presidential campaign?:",
        "correct_answer": "the economy.",
        "distractor1": "equal rights for all minorities.",
        "distractor2": "an immediate freeze of military spending.",
        "distractor3": "health care reform."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was NOT part of Ross Perot's appeal in the 1992 presidential election?:",
        "correct_answer": "his handsome appearance and suave, sophisticated public demeanor.",
        "distractor1": "his attacks on the federal bureaucracy.",
        "distractor2": "his charges that the political system was corrupt.",
        "distractor3": "his use of his own money for his campaign so that he could refuse to accept  special interest  contributions."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Clinton administration experiences problems in all of the following areas EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "tax increases.",
        "distractor1": "gays in the military.",
        "distractor2": "personal banking ventures.",
        "distractor3": "high-level government appointments."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Clinton's  New Democratic Coalition  was a?:",
        "correct_answer": "group of moderates who sought to shed the Democratic party's reputation for ultra-liberalism and wasteful spending.",
        "distractor1": "spin-off of the Christian Coalition.",
        "distractor2": "group dominated by feminists and environmentalists.",
        "distractor3": "group of ultra-liberals who sought to return the Democratic party to the policies of Franklin Roosevelt and the New Deal."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is true of NAFTA?:",
        "correct_answer": "it attempted to create a tariff-free marketplace among Mexico, Canada, and the U. S.",
        "distractor1": "the U. S., Mexico, and Canada agreed to buy certain products exclusively from Latin America in an effort to ease the debt burden of their southern",
        "distractor2": "it ended the trade war between Japan and the nations of North America.",
        "distractor3": "a free trade zone was established between the nations of North America and the European Economic Community."
    },
    {
        "question": "The  Contract With America  included all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "health care reform.",
        "distractor1": "a balanced-budget amendment.",
        "distractor2": "welfare reform.",
        "distractor3": "increased defense spending."
    },
    {
        "question": "Concerning homosexuals in the military, President Clinton?:",
        "correct_answer": "adopted a  don't ask, don't tell  policy.",
        "distractor1": "kept his campaign promise to end all discrimination.",
        "distractor2": "said it was up to Congress, not the president, to formulate policy.",
        "distractor3": "kept his campaign promise not to interfere with existing regulations."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the midterm elections of 1994?:",
        "correct_answer": "Republicans won both houses of Congress.",
        "distractor1": "Democrats won a net gain of eleven governorships and fifteen state legislatures.",
        "distractor2": "every Republican congressional incumbent was defeated.",
        "distractor3": "Democrats won both houses of Congress."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Clinton's health care reform bill failed because?:",
        "correct_answer": "it raised the specter of higher taxes and government interference.",
        "distractor1": "it lacked a clear-cut objective.",
        "distractor2": "it lacked popular support.",
        "distractor3": "the health care industry did not really need reforming."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Clinton's Middle East policy contributed to which of the following developments?:",
        "correct_answer": "Palestinian self-government in Gaza and Jericho and a declaration of peace between Israel and Jordan.",
        "distractor1": "a return of all Israeli-held Arab lands back to Syria, Jordan, and Egypt.",
        "distractor2": "a declaration of peace between Israel and Egypt.",
        "distractor3": "Syria and Iran's recognition of the state of Israel."
    },
    {
        "question": "The group most likely to approve of the Articles of Confederation would be?:",
        "correct_answer": "those who feared strong central government.",
        "distractor1": "former officers in the Continental army.",
        "distractor2": "those who held U. S. government securities.",
        "distractor3": "bankers, merchants, and financiers.",
        "distractor4": "those who feared the dangers of unrestrained democracy."
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to become a law, a bill in Congress must?:",
        "correct_answer": "pass both houses of Congress in identical form.",
        "distractor1": "receive a 2/3 majority of the votes in Congress.",
        "distractor2": "receive a 3/4 majority of the votes in each house of Congress.",
        "distractor3": "receive a 2/3 majority of votes in each house of Congress.",
        "distractor4": "pass as amended in the last house of Congress to consider it."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following amendments to the Constitution was NOT part of the Bill of Rights?:",
        "correct_answer": "direct election of senators.",
        "distractor1": "freedom of speech, press, and religion.",
        "distractor2": "trial by jury.",
        "distractor3": "protection against illegal search.",
        "distractor4": "the right to bear arms."
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the Constitution, the president is chosen by?:",
        "correct_answer": "the electoral college.",
        "distractor1": "the House of Representatives.",
        "distractor2": "the Senate.",
        "distractor3": "popular vote of the people.",
        "distractor4": "both Houses of Congress."
    },
    {
        "question": "Those who opposed ratification of the Constitution were called?:",
        "correct_answer": "Anti-Federalists.",
        "distractor1": "Democrats.",
        "distractor2": "Whigs.",
        "distractor3": "Republicans.",
        "distractor4": "Federalists."
    },
    {
        "question": "Under the Constitution, the status of the western Indian tribes was?:",
        "correct_answer": "not clearly defined.",
        "distractor1": "that of conquered nations.",
        "distractor2": "that of independent nations.",
        "distractor3": "the same as states."
    },
    {
        "question": "The American Constitutional Convention of 1787 was dominated by?:",
        "correct_answer": "men having large property holdings or commercial interests.",
        "distractor1": "isolationists and speculators.",
        "distractor2": "officers and enlisted men of the Continental Army.",
        "distractor3": "backwoods farmers and frontiersmen.",
        "distractor4": "artisans and mechanics."
    },
    {
        "question": "A major weakness of the Articles of Confederation was that they?:",
        "correct_answer": "made it too difficult for the government to raise money through taxes and duties.",
        "distractor1": "did not include a mechanism for their own amendment.",
        "distractor2": "denied the federal government the power to mediate disputes between states.",
        "distractor3": "required the ratification of only a simple majority of states.",
        "distractor4": "created a too-powerful chief executive."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the minimum number of years of citizenship required to serve as a justice on the U. S. Supreme Court?:",
        "correct_answer": "none of these choices are correct.",
        "distractor1": "5.",
        "distractor2": "7.",
        "distractor3": "14.",
        "distractor4": "20."
    },
    {
        "question": "The due process clause in the U. S. Constitution requires that?:",
        "correct_answer": "a standard set of procedures must be followed before any action is taken to punish persons accused of breaking the law.",
        "distractor1": "all labor-management contracts must be reviewed by a commission of the federal government.",
        "distractor2": "members of minority groups must be given preferential treatment in employment.",
        "distractor3": "the selection of the president and vice president must follow an established set of steps."
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following were weaknesses of the Articles of Confederation government EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "it lacked the power to borrow money.",
        "distractor1": "it lacked the power to levy taxes.",
        "distractor2": "it lacked the power to regulate commerce.",
        "distractor3": "it could not compel the states to abide by the terms of international treaties it had made.",
        "distractor4": "it lacked a strong executive."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Constitutional Convention, voting qualifications were made residual powers because of the?:",
        "correct_answer": "widespread variation of voting requirements in the states.",
        "distractor1": "desire to follow the practice of English common law.",
        "distractor2": "unwillingness of the federal government to bear the expense of the elections.",
        "distractor3": "realization that more state and local officers than federal officers were to be elected.",
        "distractor4": "conviction of the framers that the power to define citizenship should rest with the states."
    },
    {
        "question": "The U. S. Constitution includes provisions on all of the following subjects EXCEPT the?:",
        "correct_answer": "size of the Cabinet.",
        "distractor1": "powers reserved to the states.",
        "distractor2": "state militia.",
        "distractor3": "definition of treason.",
        "distractor4": "enumerated powers of Congress."
    },
    {
        "question": "The central compromise of the Constitutional Convention involved the issue of?:",
        "correct_answer": "representation of large and small states.",
        "distractor1": "balance of powers within the federal government.",
        "distractor2": "relationship of state and federal powers.",
        "distractor3": "abandonment of the Articles of Confederation.",
        "distractor4": "the powers of the presidency."
    },
    {
        "question": "The first amendments to the Constitution, the Bill of Rights, were added to protect?:",
        "correct_answer": "individual citizens from the power of the federal government.",
        "distractor1": "the states from the power of the federal government.",
        "distractor2": "individual citizens from the power of the federal government and state governments.",
        "distractor3": "minorities from the majority.",
        "distractor4": "individual citizens from the power of the state governments."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements most accurately describes the function of the  elastic clause  of the",
        "correct_answer": "it gives Congress greater powers than those explicitly delegated to it.",
        "distractor1": "it gives the president authority to affect the course of Congressional legislation.",
        "distractor2": "it prevents Congress from enacting bills of attainder or ex post facto laws.",
        "distractor3": "it gives the Senate the power to approve or reject treaties negotiated by the President.",
        "distractor4": "it reserves certain powers to the states."
    },
    {
        "question": "The fact that the United States Constitution provided for Federalism and a system of checks and balances suggests that?:",
        "correct_answer": "its writers feared a concentration of political power.",
        "distractor1": "the original thirteen states sought to dominate the national government.",
        "distractor2": "the writers desired the national government to rule over the states.",
        "distractor3": "the American people at that time supported a military government."
    },
    {
        "question": "Both the Articles of Confederation and the U.S. Constitution provided for?:",
        "correct_answer": "a Congress with legislative powers.",
        "distractor1": "a Supreme Court with judicial powers.",
        "distractor2": "president with executive powers.",
        "distractor3": "local governments with veto powers."
    },
    {
        "question": "In James Madison's tenth Federalist, the most dangerous threat to the U. S. Constitution was presented by?:",
        "correct_answer": "factions.",
        "distractor1": "the president's war powers.",
        "distractor2": "the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor3": "a standing army.",
        "distractor4": "freedom of speech."
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the U. S. Constitution, revenue bills must originate with?:",
        "correct_answer": "the House of Representatives.",
        "distractor1": "the Senate.",
        "distractor2": "either house of Congress.",
        "distractor3": "the House Ways and Means Committee.",
        "distractor4": "the president."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the early 1780s, the authority of the national government was vested in?:",
        "correct_answer": "the legislative branch.",
        "distractor1": "the judicial branch.",
        "distractor2": "the executive branch.",
        "distractor3": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Constitution was written to make it difficult for the majority of the population to impress their will on the federal",
        "correct_answer": "length of the term of office for members of the House of Representatives.",
        "distractor1": "length of the term of office for federal judges.",
        "distractor2": "choosing the president by the Electoral College.",
        "distractor3": "the method of electing U. S. Senators.",
        "distractor4": "having one-third of the Senate elected every two years."
    },
    {
        "question": "When the Founding Fathers established the electoral college system, they expected that?:",
        "correct_answer": "partisan conflict over the election of a president could be avoided.",
        "distractor1": "mass education would improve the electorate and make direct popular election reasonable.",
        "distractor2": "a democratic system would evolve whereby the people would select the president according to a weighted formula which equates the popular and electoral votes.",
        "distractor3": "a democratic party system would develop, thus making selection of the president a popular decision.",
        "distractor4": "Washington would serve two terms, after which an amendment would require the election of a president by the House of Representatives."
    },
    {
        "question": "The 3/5 Compromise of the Constitutional Convention of 1787 provided that?:",
        "correct_answer": "for purposes of representation and taxation, five slaves would be counted as three free persons.",
        "distractor1": "for purposes of representation and taxation, the votes of three free men were equal to those of five slaves.",
        "distractor2": "the votes of 3/5 of the southern states would be needed to pass any federal legislation affecting slavery.",
        "distractor3": "the voted of 3/5 of the southern states would be needed to pass any federal legislation affecting representation or taxation.",
        "distractor4": "for purposes of taxation, the numbers of slaves in a state would not be counted once they had exceeded 3/5 of the free population."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following civil liberties protected by the Bill of Rights was in the Constitution as originally ratified?:",
        "correct_answer": "trial by jury.",
        "distractor1": "freedom of the press.",
        "distractor2": "freedom of religion.",
        "distractor3": "the right to bear arms.",
        "distractor4": "protection against self-incrimination."
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the United States Constitution, each of the following may be accomplished by a simple majority vote EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "the Senate ratifies a treaty.",
        "distractor1": "Congress declares war.",
        "distractor2": "the Senate approves the appointment of a Supreme Court Justice.",
        "distractor3": "Congress passes an immigration law.",
        "distractor4": "the electoral college must select a president."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following provisions of the Constitution represents an abandonment of one or more of the principles on which the",
        "correct_answer": "Congress had the authority to levy and collect taxes, regulate commerce, and conduct diplomacy.",
        "distractor1": "the states had full freedom to act autonomously on purely internal matters.",
        "distractor2": "no one could interfere with the return of runaway slaves.",
        "distractor3": "none of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Constitution failed to address an issue concerning the Native Americans that would dictate their future relationship with",
        "correct_answer": "tribal sovereignty over their lands.",
        "distractor1": "the legitimacy of the treaties negotiated by the Confederacy.",
        "distractor2": "regulation of commerce with the Indians.",
        "distractor3": "the right of the federal government to tax the Native Americans."
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the chief reasons for the failure of the Articles of Confederation was?:",
        "correct_answer": "their lack of an adequate mechanism for Congress to force states to comply with its decisions.",
        "distractor1": "their focus on the separation of powers within the federal branch of government.",
        "distractor2": "their failure to adequately curb the powers of the executive branch of government.",
        "distractor3": "their failure to provide women and free blacks with the right to vote.",
        "distractor4": "their strict tax collections provisions. These raised resentments among the people in the smaller states who believed that they were being overtaxed while"
    },
    {
        "question": "The positions of loose construction and strict construction of the Constitution were first established in letters written by",
        "correct_answer": "the issue of creating a Bank of the United States.",
        "distractor1": "our obligations to France under the Treaty of 1778.",
        "distractor2": "consolidating the national, state, and foreign debt and paying them at face value.",
        "distractor3": "an appropriate response to the Whiskey Rebellion.",
        "distractor4": "Jefferson's decision to purchase Louisiana."
    },
    {
        "question": "Hamilton proposed a tariff soon after the launching of the United States government in order to?:",
        "correct_answer": "help develop manufacturing in the United States.",
        "distractor1": "stop the export of raw materials to Great Britain.",
        "distractor2": "help develop the American labor movement.",
        "distractor3": "punish Great Britain for postwar harassment of American shipping.",
        "distractor4": "support the creation of an American merchant marine."
    },
    {
        "question": "Women emerged from the American Revolution with the prescribed new responsibility of?:",
        "correct_answer": "raising sons and daughters as good republican citizens.",
        "distractor1": "enjoying the vote.",
        "distractor2": "serving in local political office.",
        "distractor3": "becoming public school teachers.",
        "distractor4": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary issue in dispute in Shay's Rebellion was?:",
        "correct_answer": "the jailing of individuals or seizure of their property for failure to pay taxes during a time of economic hardship.",
        "distractor1": "the under-representation of western Massachusetts in the state legislature, leading to accusations of  taxation without representation. ",
        "distractor2": "the failure of Massachusetts to pay a promised postwar bonus to soldiers who had served in its forces during the Revolution.",
        "distractor3": "the failure of Massachusetts authorities to take adequate steps to protect the western part of the state from the depredations of raiding Indians.",
        "distractor4": "economic oppression practiced by the banking interests of eastern Massachusetts."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Jay Treaty (1794) provided for?:",
        "correct_answer": "evacuation of English troops from their posts along the Great Lakes.",
        "distractor1": "the acceptance of American trade with the French West Indies.",
        "distractor2": "free navigation of the Mississippi.",
        "distractor3": "an ending of the impressment of American seamen.",
        "distractor4": "the settlement of the Canadian boundary."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Northwest Ordinance of 1787 established what precedent for new territories?:",
        "correct_answer": "equality of new states with old.",
        "distractor1": "fair treatment of Indians.",
        "distractor2": "popular sovereignty.",
        "distractor3": "support for public education.",
        "distractor4": "prohibition of slavery."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Republican vision of America, education was essential because?:",
        "correct_answer": "an ignorant electorate could not be trusted to preserve democracy.",
        "distractor1": "schools were the best place to teach children to be good party members.",
        "distractor2": "business leaders needed to be educated.",
        "distractor3": "schools were where religious values were taught."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Judiciary Act of 1789?:",
        "correct_answer": "established a system of lower federal courts.",
        "distractor1": "provided for the election of federal judges.",
        "distractor2": "provided for the establishment of state courts.",
        "distractor3": "provided for the impeachment of federal officials.",
        "distractor4": "was violated by William Marbury."
    },
    {
        "question": "The main purpose of the Alien and Sedition Acts was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "silence and punish critics of the Federalists.",
        "distractor1": "capture French and British spies.",
        "distractor2": "control the Federalists.",
        "distractor3": "keep Thomas Jefferson from becoming president."
    },
    {
        "question": "Washington's  Farewell Address  in 1796?:",
        "correct_answer": "warned against the dangers of permanent foreign alliances.",
        "distractor1": "warmly endorsed the appearance of two contending political parties in America.",
        "distractor2": "was delivered to a joint session of Congress by Washington himself.",
        "distractor3": "proposed a two-term limitation on the presidency."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was NOT a cause of John Adam's defeat in the presidential election of 1800?:",
        "correct_answer": "British harassment of American sailors.",
        "distractor1": "the Alien and Sedition Acts.",
        "distractor2": "the XYZ Affair.",
        "distractor3": "Alexander Hamilton's disagreement with John Adams.",
        "distractor4": "the failure of Adams to support war with France."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Virginia and Kentucky Resolutions argued that the right to determine the constitutionality of a law passed by",
        "correct_answer": "the states.",
        "distractor1": "Congress.",
        "distractor2": "the President.",
        "distractor3": "the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor4": "the vote of the people."
    },
    {
        "question": "A revolution in what country made American neutrality an issue in the 1790s?:",
        "correct_answer": "France.",
        "distractor1": "Great Britain.",
        "distractor2": "Spain.",
        "distractor3": "the Netherlands.",
        "distractor4": "Germany."
    },
    {
        "question": "While Chief Justice John Marshall presided over the Supreme Court, its decisions?:",
        "correct_answer": "laid the groundwork for a  broad  interpretation of the Constitution.",
        "distractor1": "were generally protective of states' rights.",
        "distractor2": "showed no clear leaning toward either a  broad  or  strict  interpretation of the Constitution.",
        "distractor3": "reflected the impact of Thomas Jefferson's Kentucky Resolutions.",
        "distractor4": "were hostile to the development of business."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Federalists made a last gasp attempt to maintain power by?:",
        "correct_answer": "creating new federal courts and judges.",
        "distractor1": "repealing the Alien and Sedition Acts.",
        "distractor2": "supporting Aaron Burr for president.",
        "distractor3": "plotting a revolution to prevent the election of Jefferson."
    },
    {
        "question": "The treaties of the 1780s negotiated by the new American government with Native Americans of the interior?:",
        "correct_answer": "intended to open trans-Appalachia to white settlement.",
        "distractor1": "confirmed the alliances made between the United States and the tribes during the Revolution.",
        "distractor2": "proved durable and effective in maintaining peaceful relations.",
        "distractor3": "afforded the Native Americans all the rights and privileges of United States citizenship."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following best reflects the economic hardships of the  Critical Period ?:",
        "correct_answer": "Shay's Rebellion.",
        "distractor1": "the Stamp Act Congress.",
        "distractor2": "the Northwest Ordinance.",
        "distractor3": "Tom Paine's Common Sense.",
        "distractor4": "the Embargo Act of 1807."
    },
    {
        "question": "The international incident known as the XYZ Affair involved?:",
        "correct_answer": "a French foreign minister's demand for a bribe before he would meet with American envoys.",
        "distractor1": "the British refused to evacuate their forts on American territory.",
        "distractor2": "General Andrew Jackson's incursion into Spanish-held Florida.",
        "distractor3": "the British seizure of American crewmen from a U. S. Navy warship in Chesapeake Bay.",
        "distractor4": "Aaron Burr's secret plot to detach the western United States in order to create a new nation of which he would be ruler."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the election of 1796?:",
        "correct_answer": "the Federalist party divided when southern Federalists refused to support Adams.",
        "distractor1": "Thomas Jefferson was the choice of southern Federalists.",
        "distractor2": "the Federalist Party united behind Adams.",
        "distractor3": "George Washington took an active role."
    },
    {
        "question": "Purposes of Alexander Hamilton's tax, tariff, and debt manipulation schemes during the presidency of George Washington",
        "correct_answer": "binding the interests of the moneyed class to the new federal government.",
        "distractor1": "ridding the federal government of debt as soon as possible.",
        "distractor2": "ending undue government interference in the economy.",
        "distractor3": "maintaining the United States as an agrarian society.",
        "distractor4": "promoting the importation of British manufactured goods."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the 1790s, Federalists and Republicans openly disagreed over?:",
        "correct_answer": "all of these choices are correct.",
        "distractor1": "the extent of popular control of government.",
        "distractor2": "foreign policy toward England and France.",
        "distractor3": "the activities of Citizen Genet.",
        "distractor4": "the fiscal policies of the national government."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Pilgrims were also known as Separatists because they?:",
        "correct_answer": "broke all ties with the Church of England.",
        "distractor1": "wanted to separate Plymouth from the Massachusetts Bay Colony.",
        "distractor2": "believed in the complete separation of church and state.",
        "distractor3": "were the first to declare independence from Great Britain.",
        "distractor4": "tried to isolate the Native Americans from white settlers."
    },
    {
        "question": "Jamestown survived as the first permanent British settlement in America because of?:",
        "correct_answer": "the emergence of tobacco as a cash crop.",
        "distractor1": "the settlers who followed the example of Roanoke.",
        "distractor2": "the religious convictions of its first settlers.",
        "distractor3": "the mild climate of Virginia.",
        "distractor4": "its use of Indian slaves as a labor force."
    },
    {
        "question": "Roger Williams is best known in American history as?:",
        "correct_answer": "an early champion of religious freedom.",
        "distractor1": "advocating the uniting of church and state into a theocracy.",
        "distractor2": "the chief justice at the Salem witch trials.",
        "distractor3": "the founder of New Hampshire.",
        "distractor4": "the first royal governor of Massachusetts."
    },
    {
        "question": "In founding the colony of Georgia, James Oglethorpe's primary purpose was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "provide a refuge for English debtors.",
        "distractor1": "provide a refuge for persecuted English Quakers.",
        "distractor2": "gain a base for launching English expeditions against Spanish-held Florida.",
        "distractor3": "make a financial profit.",
        "distractor4": "provide a refuge for persecuted Christians of all sects from all parts of Europe."
    },
    {
        "question": "Most of the slaves who came to the thirteen mainland colonies in British North America?:",
        "correct_answer": "were considered to be property and as such could be used as collateral for loans.",
        "distractor1": "were from the southern part of Africa in what is today South Africa.",
        "distractor2": "were granted their freedom after a specified period of service.",
        "distractor3": "never made up more than 5% of the population of any colony.",
        "distractor4": "were protected from physical harm by the Roman Catholic Church's Canon Law."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Mayflower Compact could best be described as?:",
        "correct_answer": "a foundation for self-government.",
        "distractor1": "a detailed frame of government.",
        "distractor2": "a complete constitution.",
        "distractor3": "a business contract.",
        "distractor4": "an enumeration of the causes for leaving England and coming to the New World."
    },
    {
        "question": "Seventeenth-century New England and the West Indies?:",
        "correct_answer": "were interdependent because the sugar islands could not feed themselves or supply their own lumber, and New England relied on the Caribbean to purchase",
        "distractor1": "were interdependent because New England's short growing season required the importation of food from the Caribbean Islands.",
        "distractor2": "were interdependent because New Englanders used the Caribbean as a  safety valve  for excess population in search of farmland.",
        "distractor3": "had virtually nothing to do with each other because the vast distance between them prohibited economic or cultural exchange.",
        "distractor4": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was a proprietary colony?:",
        "correct_answer": "a colony like New Jersey that was run as a privately owned estate.",
        "distractor1": "a colony like Virginia that was run like a business.",
        "distractor2": "a colony like Delaware that was sponsored by a particular religious group.",
        "distractor3": "a colony like Massachusetts that was forced to acknowledge the proper authority of the king."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following correctly describes the attitude of most English settlers toward the Indians and their way of life?:",
        "correct_answer": "they assumed the Indians to be their inferiors and showed little respect for Indian society.",
        "distractor1": "they accepted and respected the differences between their own culture and Indian culture.",
        "distractor2": "they were very interested in understanding as many aspects of Indian culture as possible.",
        "distractor3": "they were openly hostile toward the Indians and had no thoughts of living in peace with them."
    },
    {
        "question": "Indentured servants were important to the development of the 17c Chesapeake because they?:",
        "correct_answer": "provided a relatively cheap and abundant source of labor for Chesapeake tobacco planters.",
        "distractor1": "were usually artisans who brought needed skills to the area.",
        "distractor2": "brought new ideas concerning the cultivation and cure of tobacco.",
        "distractor3": "provided labor for important public projects undertaken by the colonial governments of Virginia and Maryland."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Virginia Company attracted new settlers to its colony after 1609 by?:",
        "correct_answer": "promising free land at the end of seven years' labor for the company.",
        "distractor1": "offering them a share of the company's profits.",
        "distractor2": "advertising the benefits of Virginia's healthy environment and comfortable living conditions.",
        "distractor3": "paying significantly higher wages than those prevailing throughout Europe."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the first two decades of the 17c, all of the following aided in the establishment and growth of the colony at",
        "correct_answer": "good relations with the local Native Americans.",
        "distractor1": "the establishment of the Virginia House of Burgesses.",
        "distractor2": "the beginning of tobacco cultivation.",
        "distractor3": "large influxes of supplies and colonists from England.",
        "distractor4": "the establishment of the ownership of private property."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Mayflower Compact is significant in American political thought because?:",
        "correct_answer": "in it the people agreed to be bound by the will of the majority.",
        "distractor1": "in it the people regard themselves as the source of political power.",
        "distractor2": "it was copied for the Massachusetts Bay Charter.",
        "distractor3": "in it church and state are separated.",
        "distractor4": "in it were provisions guaranteeing civil rights for women and blacks."
    },
    {
        "question": "Anne Hutchinson's teaching threatened to undermine the spiritual authority of the established clergy because she?:",
        "correct_answer": "claimed believers could communicate directly with God.",
        "distractor1": "preached that the clergy was corrupt.",
        "distractor2": "denounced clergymen who were also politicians.",
        "distractor3": "stressed faith over good works."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Maryland Toleration Act of 1649 provided for?:",
        "correct_answer": "the tolerance of most Christian churches.",
        "distractor1": "freedom of conscience for those not accepting the Trinity.",
        "distractor2": "an end to tax support for any church.",
        "distractor3": "a complete separation of church and state.",
        "distractor4": "the extension of the vote to Jews and non-Christians."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Half-Way Covenant was adopted because?:",
        "correct_answer": "too few second- and third-generation Puritans were willing to testify publicly about their conversion experiences.",
        "distractor1": "Puritans believed that Native Americans were not capable of becoming fully Christian.",
        "distractor2": "Puritans wanted to justify enslavement of converted Indians and Africans.",
        "distractor3": "Puritans wanted to show Anglicans that they were willing to meet them half-way on resolving differences over religious doctrine."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following characterized life in the Chesapeake region in the early 17c?:",
        "correct_answer": "the presence of many more men than women, giving women somewhat greater status because of their scarcity.",
        "distractor1": "a relatively long life expectancy compared with that in the harsh environment of New England.",
        "distractor2": "rapidly developing urbanization.",
        "distractor3": "a population density which required residents to live in close proximity to neighbors."
    },
    {
        "question": "As a result of the cultivation of tobacco in Virginia?:",
        "correct_answer": "a scattered pattern of settlement emerged in the colony.",
        "distractor1": "the large estates were divided into smaller agricultural units.",
        "distractor2": "the Virginia Company began to send male laborers to the colony.",
        "distractor3": "settlers began to congregate in urban areas."
    },
    {
        "question": "The CHIEF significance of the Great Awakening was that it?:",
        "correct_answer": "was the first genuine unified movement of the American colonists.",
        "distractor1": "led to the foundation of many colleges.",
        "distractor2": "provided Jonathan Edwards with an opportunity to preach.",
        "distractor3": "revived intolerance in the colonies.",
        "distractor4": "created a new interest in church attendance."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Eisenhower's domestic strategy of modern Republicanism advocated?:",
        "correct_answer": "acceptance of existing New Deal programs.",
        "distractor1": "increasing military spending.",
        "distractor2": "a continuation of McCarthyism.",
        "distractor3": "large deficit spending to finance socialized medicine.",
        "distractor4": "the support of civil rights activism."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is an idea of Woodrow Wilson's that came to be an accepted part of United States foreign policy after",
        "correct_answer": "the security of the United States is best preserved through collective security.",
        "distractor1": "non-recognition of revolutionary governments will lead to the downfall of such offensive governments.",
        "distractor2": "isolation has kept us out of past European wars and will keep us out of future European wars.",
        "distractor3": "the World Court is the best forum to settle international disputes.",
        "distractor4": "arbitration treaties between nations provide a much needed period for tempers to cool."
    },
    {
        "question": "John Foster Dulles is most closely associated with the?:",
        "correct_answer": "policy of massive retaliation.",
        "distractor1": "policy of mutually assured destruction.",
        "distractor2": "flexible response policy.",
        "distractor3": "Strategic Defense initiative.",
        "distractor4": "zero option policy."
    },
    {
        "question": "What action did President Eisenhower take to bring about school integration in Little Rock, Arkansas?:",
        "correct_answer": "he placed the Arkansas National Guard under federal command to carry out the desegregation plan.",
        "distractor1": "he urged Congress to pass civil rights legislation.",
        "distractor2": "he issued an executive order mandating integration.",
        "distractor3": "he began impeachment proceedings against Governor Orval Faubus.",
        "distractor4": "he had the Justice Department file a suit in the federal courts."
    },
    {
        "question": "Critics of McCarthyism in the 1950s stressed the idea that?:",
        "correct_answer": "fears of subversion can lead to the erosion of constitutional liberties.",
        "distractor1": "the government should always be on guard against Communist subversion.",
        "distractor2": "loyalty oaths can prevent espionage.",
        "distractor3": "communism is likely to gain influence in times of prosperity."
    },
    {
        "question": "By the end of Eisenhower's second term, the first Republican administration since the New Deal had?:",
        "correct_answer": "left the size and functions of the federal government intact.",
        "distractor1": "effectively dismantled much of the New Deal legislation and programs.",
        "distractor2": "dismantled only the farm aid programs and Social Security.",
        "distractor3": "reduced America's international commitments, thus seriously cutting the defense budget."
    },
    {
        "question": "Between 1954 and 1961, the Eisenhower administration's policy toward South Vietnam can be characterized as one that?:",
        "correct_answer": "propped up a corrupt and unpopular, anti-Communist dictatorship in order to contain the spread of communism in Southeast Asia.",
        "distractor1": "supported any leadership that would allow American business interests access to the region's natural resources.",
        "distractor2": "supported the country's Buddhist leaders as opposed to the Christian leaders.",
        "distractor3": "always supported the pro-democratic leadership."
    },
    {
        "question": "The significance of the civil rights laws of 1957 and 1960 was that they?:",
        "correct_answer": "were the first civil rights laws passed since Reconstruction.",
        "distractor1": "succeeded in ending discrimination in public facilities.",
        "distractor2": "opened the doors to equal opportunity in employment.",
        "distractor3": "provided protection for women as well as racial minorities."
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1960 which of the following contributed most directly to Soviet leader Nikita Khrushchev's cancellation of a scheduled",
        "correct_answer": "the downing of an American U-2 spy plane over the Soviet Union.",
        "distractor1": "the rise to power of Fidel Castro in Cuba.",
        "distractor2": "the failure, at the Bay of Pigs, of a U. S.-sponsored attempt to oust Fidel Castro.",
        "distractor3": "the sending of U. S. troops to Lebanon.",
        "distractor4": "the success of the Soviet space program in launching the Sputnik satellite."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Eisenhower was associated with each of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "bringing about the downfall of Senator Joseph McCarthy by publicly denouncing his irresponsible accusations.",
        "distractor1": "appointing Earl Warren as chief justice of the United States.",
        "distractor2": "bringing an end to the Korean War with the signing of an armistice in 1953.",
        "distractor3": "warning the nation about the growing power of the military and big industrial corporations in American life."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Soviet Union's launching of Sputnik in 1957 immediately led to?:",
        "correct_answer": "massive federal aid to American higher education.",
        "distractor1": "an easing of US-USSR tensions.",
        "distractor2": "the Suez Crisis.",
        "distractor3": "the Geneva Summit's endorsement of Open Skies.",
        "distractor4": "the U-2 Incident."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Eisenhower opposed Truman's plan for?:",
        "correct_answer": "national health insurance.",
        "distractor1": "creating the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare.",
        "distractor2": "Social Security increases.",
        "distractor3": "raising the minimum wage."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is true of the Eisenhower administration's termination policy?:",
        "correct_answer": "it led to the withdrawal of federal benefits from many Indian tribes.",
        "distractor1": "it ended attempts to assimilate Indians into mainstream American society.",
        "distractor2": "it placed control of federal benefit programs on Indian reservations in the hands of Indian leaders.",
        "distractor3": "it provided funds for educational programs on Indian reservations."
    },
    {
        "question": "In his farewell address in January 1961, President Eisenhower warned the American people against?:",
        "correct_answer": "the influence of the military-industrial complex.",
        "distractor1": "the rise of military pacifism.",
        "distractor2": "the tendency to hysterical anti-communism.",
        "distractor3": "the risk of creeping socialism."
    },
    {
        "question": "The 1956 boycott of the Montgomery bus system?:",
        "correct_answer": "was instigated by the arrest of Rosa parks.",
        "distractor1": "was led by Malcolm X.",
        "distractor2": "started because the city doubled bus fares.",
        "distractor3": "lasted for three weeks and failed to achieve its goal.",
        "distractor4": "resulted from the assassination of Martin Luther King, Jr."
    },
    {
        "question": "The case of  Brown vs. Board of Education of Topeka, Kansas  (1954) concerned?:",
        "correct_answer": "the constitutionality of racial segregation in public schools.",
        "distractor1": "the right of American women to receive equal pay.",
        "distractor2": "the constitutionality of federal aid to education.",
        "distractor3": "the closing of public schools by the governor of Kansas.",
        "distractor4": "voting rights for Hispanics and Native Americans."
    },
    {
        "question": "The largest public works project during Eisenhower's presidency was?:",
        "correct_answer": "construction of the interstate highway system.",
        "distractor1": "the space program.",
        "distractor2": "the building of Grand Coulee Dam.",
        "distractor3": "offshore oil drilling in the Gulf of Mexico."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Eisenhower administration's policy in the Middle East included all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "support for the British and French invasion of the Suez.",
        "distractor1": "the landing of marines at Beirut to protect the existing regime from a possible coup.",
        "distractor2": "the use of the CIA to help stage a coup to overthrow the nationalist prime minister of Iran and replace his with a pro-American leader.",
        "distractor3": "the withdrawal of offers to Egypt to build the Aswan Dam across the Nile as punishment for that government's friendliness toward the Soviet Union."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Civil Rights Act of 1957?:",
        "correct_answer": "established a permanent commission on civil rights with broad investigatory powers.",
        "distractor1": "was opposed by President Eisenhower because he believed one couldn't change the hearts of men with laws.",
        "distractor2": "empowered federal officials to register blacks to vote.",
        "distractor3": "overturned the doctrine of  separate but equal  in education."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Eisenhower described his domestic program as  dynamic conservatism.  An important part of this program",
        "correct_answer": "opposition to public power projects.",
        "distractor1": "national health insurance.",
        "distractor2": "reduced social security benefits.",
        "distractor3": "heavier tax burdens for the wealthy.",
        "distractor4": "the repeal of New Deal legislation."
    },
    {
        "question": "Gerald Ford's main liability in the 1976 presidential election was?:",
        "correct_answer": "the Watergate scandal.",
        "distractor1": "his inexperience in foreign policy.",
        "distractor2": "the Republican party's position on civil rights.",
        "distractor3": "the war in Vietnam.",
        "distractor4": "his support for a national health insurance plan."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Ford's foreign policy included support for all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "the abandonment of United States mediation efforts in the Middle East.",
        "distractor1": "the SALT II agreement.",
        "distractor2": "the Helsinki agreement on European boundaries.",
        "distractor3": "the continued rapprochement with China after the death of Mao Zedong."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following made the Ford administration different from any other in the history of the United States?:",
        "correct_answer": "neither the president nor the vice president had been elected to office.",
        "distractor1": "the vice president was also the Attorney General.",
        "distractor2": "President Ford made no appointments to the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor3": "Congress asserted power in the field of foreign policy."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Helsinki Accords, signed by Gerald Ford and leaders of thirty-four other nations?:",
        "correct_answer": "pledged signatories to guarantee certain basic human rights.",
        "distractor1": "rejected the Soviet-directed boundary of Poland.",
        "distractor2": "proved to many Americans that d tente was still a two-way street.",
        "distractor3": "was condemned by West Germany as meaningless."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following contributed to Iranian Ayatollah Khomeini's hatred of the United States?:",
        "correct_answer": "the CIA had put the Shah of Iran in power and had trained his ruthless secret police.",
        "distractor1": "while he was in exile, the American government had regarded him as a Communist rather than recognizing him as a Muslim fundamentalist.",
        "distractor2": "he had been subjected to prejudice and harassment many years earlier as a graduate student in the United States.",
        "distractor3": "he had been the target of CIA-sponsored assassination attempts on three different occasions in the 1970s."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was the most significant foreign policy accomplishment of President Jimmy Carter?:",
        "correct_answer": "Camp David Accords.",
        "distractor1": "Paris Peace Accords.",
        "distractor2": "Panama Canal Treaties.",
        "distractor3": "SALT I Treaty.",
        "distractor4": "Mayaguez Incident."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was NOT a major issue during the presidency of Jimmy Carter?:",
        "correct_answer": "the unilateral withdrawal of U. S. troops from Europe.",
        "distractor1": "Iranian hostage crisis.",
        "distractor2": "inflation.",
        "distractor3": "SALT negotiations.",
        "distractor4": "human rights."
    },
    {
        "question": "Jimmy Carter's success in the election of 1976 resulted in large part because?:",
        "correct_answer": "Carter seemed to possess honesty, piety, and an outsider's skepticism of the federal government.",
        "distractor1": "President Ford refused to choose a running mate who appealed to the Republican right.",
        "distractor2": "Carter's considerable service in Washington assured voters of an experienced administrator.",
        "distractor3": "Ford's acerbic personality had generated an atmosphere of bitterness and acrimony in Washington."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Carter's administration had its greatest difficulties with its?:",
        "correct_answer": "economic policy.",
        "distractor1": "Central American policy.",
        "distractor2": "energy conservation policy.",
        "distractor3": "land conservation policy.",
        "distractor4": "East Asian policy."
    },
    {
        "question": "In response to the Soviet invasion of Afghanistan in 1979, President Carter did all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "he invoked the SEATO treaty, by which member nations were to confer with one another in case of attack.",
        "distractor1": "he imposed economic sanctions on the Soviet Union.",
        "distractor2": "he called for a boycott of the 1980 Olympics in Moscow.",
        "distractor3": "he withdrew SALT II from consideration by the Senate."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Carter thought he could advance the cause of human rights by?:",
        "correct_answer": "cutting off U. S. aid to dictatorial regimes.",
        "distractor1": "arranging summit meetings with the leaders of the Middle East.",
        "distractor2": "intervening in the politics of Nicaragua.",
        "distractor3": "threatening to use force against Cuba's dictatorship."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Carter called this issue  The moral equivalent of war . What issue was it?:",
        "correct_answer": "the energy issue.",
        "distractor1": "worldwide poverty.",
        "distractor2": "deregulation of industry.",
        "distractor3": "poverty in America."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was NOT a factor in shaping Gilded Age politics?:",
        "correct_answer": "business remained separate from politics.",
        "distractor1": "politics was seen more as a way to get office rather than a way to press certain issues.",
        "distractor2": "in national politics, neither party could keep both a majority in Congress and a president in the White House.",
        "distractor3": "none of the presidents in this period could be described as a strong leader."
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of the Pendleton Act of 1883 was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "fill some government jobs on the basis of competitive exams.",
        "distractor1": "establish the first racial quotas for government jobs.",
        "distractor2": "ensure that appointments to government jobs were approved by Congress.",
        "distractor3": "declare illegal the system of city political machines and boss rule."
    },
    {
        "question": "Scholars considered the 1896 election  critical  because?:",
        "correct_answer": "it initiated a realignment in the power of the two main political parties.",
        "distractor1": "it showed that the American people will reject radicalism.",
        "distractor2": "it brought progressive politicians into power.",
        "distractor3": "it discredited the free silver crusade."
    },
    {
        "question": "What reason was given by President Cleveland for intervening with federal troops in the Pullman Strike of 1894?:",
        "correct_answer": "the strike interfered with the United States' mails and interstate commerce.",
        "distractor1": "the Governor of Illinois requested the troops.",
        "distractor2": "the strike endangered the national health and safety.",
        "distractor3": "federal property was being destroyed.",
        "distractor4": "the strike endangered the national defense."
    },
    {
        "question": "In its decision in the case of  Plessy v. Ferguson , the Supreme Court held that?:",
        "correct_answer": "separate but equal facilities for different races were constitutional.",
        "distractor1": "separate facilities for different races were inherently unequal and therefore unconstitutional.",
        "distractor2": "no black slave could be a citizen of the United States.",
        "distractor3": "Affirmative Action programs were acceptable only when it could be proven that specific previous cases of discrimination had occurred within the institution or",
        "distractor4": "imposition of a literacy test imposed an unconstitutional barrier to the right to vote."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which person would most likely have been inclined to vote for William McKinley in 1896?:",
        "correct_answer": "the president of a bank in Indiana.",
        "distractor1": "an owner of a silver mine.",
        "distractor2": "a member of the Knights of Labor.",
        "distractor3": "an Illinois farmer with a $5,000 mortgage on his farm.",
        "distractor4": "a person who favored vigorous enforcement of the Sherman Anti-Trust Act."
    },
    {
        "question": " If the gold delegates dare to defend the gold standard as a good thing, we will fight them to the uppermost. ",
        "correct_answer": "the unlimited coinage of silver.",
        "distractor1": "lower tariffs.",
        "distractor2": "a revival of greenback paper currency.",
        "distractor3": "renewed religious commitment for all Americans.",
        "distractor4": "federal and social welfare programs to deal with the Panic of 1893."
    },
    {
        "question": "Politicians of the Gilded Age used the spoils system to?:",
        "correct_answer": "dispense government jobs for political purposes.",
        "distractor1": "elect all federal government officials.",
        "distractor2": "fill government jobs based on merit rather than patronage.",
        "distractor3": "remove incompetent politicians from office."
    },
    {
        "question": "Stalwarts, Half-Breeds, and Mugwumps were?:",
        "correct_answer": "factions of the Republican party that fought over issues like civil service reform.",
        "distractor1": "names for Democratic Party reformers.",
        "distractor2": "Native American political groups of the late 19c.",
        "distractor3": "independent political parties."
    },
    {
        "question": "From 1876-1897, political control of the national government in the United States?:",
        "correct_answer": "was dominated by the Republican Party.",
        "distractor1": "reflected the general influence of the Socialist Party.",
        "distractor2": "was dominated by the Democratic Party.",
        "distractor3": "reflected a stalemate between the two major parties."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Interstate Commerce Act and the Sherman Anti-Trust Act?:",
        "correct_answer": "proved to be ineffective in the regulation of business abuses.",
        "distractor1": "created strong governmental machinery for dealing with corrupt business practices.",
        "distractor2": "both outlawed rebates.",
        "distractor3": "created price controls for industry."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is LEAST true about immigration to the U. S. between 1880 and 1900?:",
        "correct_answer": "most immigrants came from northern and western Europe.",
        "distractor1": "most immigrants were unskilled day laborers.",
        "distractor2": "immigration increased steadily during these years.",
        "distractor3": "immigrants tended to be Catholic, Eastern Orthodox, or Jewish.",
        "distractor4": "Chinese immigrants were excluded by law during most of these years."
    },
    {
        "question": "The strength of the Democratic party in the Gilded Age lay with?:",
        "correct_answer": "white southerners and northern urbanites.",
        "distractor1": "the educated and the affluent.",
        "distractor2": "western farmers and cattlemen.",
        "distractor3": "opponents to the tariff and civil service reform."
    },
    {
        "question": "Evidence justifying the use of the label  politics of paralysis  to describe the Gilded Age would include all of",
        "correct_answer": "the period was marked by relatively low voter turnout.",
        "distractor1": "much energy in Congress was expended on political patronage.",
        "distractor2": "parties used such devices as ethnic and religious appeals and entertaining campaign rallies to try to get voters to the polls.",
        "distractor3": "a majority of presidential candidates came from Ohio or New York."
    },
    {
        "question": "As a result of the Depression of 1893?:",
        "correct_answer": "new attitudes towards poverty and government responsibility emerged.",
        "distractor1": "the federal government adopted a silver standard of currency.",
        "distractor2": "the Populists expanded their following to the urban working classes.",
        "distractor3": "the Democrats and Republicans unified around strong leaders."
    },
    {
        "question": "One theme of the Gilded Age politics was the?:",
        "correct_answer": "triumph of urban-industrial interests.",
        "distractor1": "rise of the common man.",
        "distractor2": "extension of government into the private sphere.",
        "distractor3": "triumph of rural-agricultural interests."
    },
    {
        "question": "The 1896 presidential election marked the last time that?:",
        "correct_answer": "a serious effort to win the White House would be made with mostly agrarian votes.",
        "distractor1": "rural America would defeat urban America.",
        "distractor2": "the South remained solid for the Democratic party.",
        "distractor3": "factory workers would favor inflation."
    },
    {
        "question": "What did Grover Cleveland think was the way to deal with the Depression of 1893-1897?:",
        "correct_answer": "defend the gold standard and bolster government gold reserves.",
        "distractor1": "sell $62 million in gold to Wall Street bankers J. P. Morgan and August Belmont.",
        "distractor2": "enact the Sherman Silver Purchase bill.",
        "distractor3": "purchase 3.5 million ounces of silver."
    },
    {
        "question": "Booker T. Washington believed that the best way for blacks to improve their status in the United States was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "accommodate themselves to segregation and disfranchisement while at the same time working hard and proving their economic value to society.",
        "distractor1": "struggle militantly against all forms of racial discrimination in order to gain educational opportunity.",
        "distractor2": "form a nationwide council to work for federal laws against lynching.",
        "distractor3": "leave the United States and return to their African origins."
    },
    {
        "question": "Mark Twain called the era following the Civil War the  Gilded Age  because?:",
        "correct_answer": "the glitter and flashiness of the time seemed to mask the ugliness and crass materialism that lay beneath the surface.",
        "distractor1": "it was an age of universal benefit for all Americans.",
        "distractor2": "of the tremendous number of gold strikes that took place.",
        "distractor3": "the gold and silver issues seemed to dominate the era."
    },
    {
        "question": "Grover Cleveland, the only Democrat elected president between 1857 and 1912, believed that Government should?:",
        "correct_answer": "refrain from paternalistic meddling in the economy.",
        "distractor1": "actively intervene in the economy to guide the nation's industrial development.",
        "distractor2": "work to develop a humanitarian form of industrialism.",
        "distractor3": "regulate the trusts and provide drought relief to western farmers."
    },
    {
        "question": "In late 19c cases dealing with the rights of blacks, the Supreme Court decided that?:",
        "correct_answer": "racial segregation was constitutional as long as each race had equal facilities.",
        "distractor1": "the Fourteenth Amendment protected citizens from private acts of discrimination but not from governmental acts.",
        "distractor2": "poll taxes and literacy tests were illegal.",
        "distractor3": "the civil rights clauses of the Fifteenth Amendment were unconstitutional."
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States did NOT restrict immigration during most of the 19c for all of the following reasons EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "an amendment to the Constitution was necessary to enact such legislation.",
        "distractor1": "there was a continuous demand for cheap labor.",
        "distractor2": "population growth did not present serious ecological problems then.",
        "distractor3": "immigrants from China made excellent workers in building railroads.",
        "distractor4": "many Europeans wanted to immigrate to America."
    },
    {
        "question": "Thomas Nast achieved fame and influence as a?:",
        "correct_answer": "political cartoonist.",
        "distractor1": "radio commentator.",
        "distractor2": "photographer.",
        "distractor3": "film producer.",
        "distractor4": "newspaper publisher."
    },
    {
        "question": "A member of the Social Gospel movement would probably?:",
        "correct_answer": "argue that Christians should work to reorganize the industrial system and bring about international peace.",
        "distractor1": "consider such social sins as alcohol abuse and sexual permissiveness as society's most serious problems.",
        "distractor2": "assert that the poor themselves were at fault for their circumstances.",
        "distractor3": "maintain that abuses and social degradation resulted solely from a lack of willpower on the part of those who committed them.",
        "distractor4": "hold their religion is an entirely individualistic matter."
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1890, Jacob Riis vividly portrayed life in an American urban slum in his work?:",
        "correct_answer": " How the Other Half Lives .",
        "distractor1": " The Jungle .",
        "distractor2": " The Octopus .",
        "distractor3": " Ragged John .",
        "distractor4": " Maggie, Girl of the Streets ."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following population trends occurred in the United States from 1860 to 1910?:",
        "correct_answer": "faster rate of growth for the cities than for the general population.",
        "distractor1": "gradual decline of the rural population in absolute numbers.",
        "distractor2": "shift of the majority of the urban population from central city to suburbs.",
        "distractor3": "significant shift of the population from the North to the South."
    },
    {
        "question": " Native  Americans disliked immigrants for all of the following reasons EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "immigrants were strong supporters of prohibition.",
        "distractor1": "the language and customs of immigrants were very different.",
        "distractor2": "most immigrants were not Protestant.",
        "distractor3": "many Americans believed immigrants to be racially inferior."
    },
    {
        "question": "Thorstein Veblen?:",
        "correct_answer": "wrote about conspicuous consumption and conspicuous leisure.",
        "distractor1": "wrote  An American Tragedy .",
        "distractor2": "argued that too many industrial experts were becoming business managers.",
        "distractor3": "defended the productive efficiency of big business against its critics."
    },
    {
        "question": "As a result of the introduction of mass transit in cities?:",
        "correct_answer": "different social groups no longer lived close together.",
        "distractor1": "working-class neighborhoods were broken apart.",
        "distractor2": "more mixed-use areas consisting of residences, shops, and factories emerged.",
        "distractor3": "human resources were drawn inward toward the central city."
    },
    {
        "question": "Political machines spread and thrived in urban areas during the late 19c because?:",
        "correct_answer": "existing city government structures were so disorganized and chaotic.",
        "distractor1": "they represented efficiency and honesty in an age of political corruption.",
        "distractor2": "people were tired of the autocratic nature of existing city governments.",
        "distractor3": "the middle classes were angry at the favoritism shown by existing city governments to the urban poor and ethnic minorities."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Chinese in America encountered a form of racial prejudice for all of the following reasons EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "the perception that they were unwilling to perform hand work.",
        "distractor1": "the belief that they were recruited by the bosses to undercut wages.",
        "distractor2": "the perception that they threatened the values of  white society. ",
        "distractor3": "the feeling that their religious beliefs made them  heathens. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following groups would have been most likely to support Tammany Hall?:",
        "correct_answer": "poor urban immigrants.",
        "distractor1": "industrial and business leaders.",
        "distractor2": "organized religion.",
        "distractor3": "middle-class shop owners.",
        "distractor4": "wealthy rural landowners."
    },
    {
        "question": "Jane Addams is most closely associated with which of the following?:",
        "correct_answer": "the settlement house movement.",
        "distractor1": "temperance reform.",
        "distractor2": "higher education for women.",
        "distractor3": "women's suffrage.",
        "distractor4": "Protestant missions."
    },
    {
        "question": "After 1890, increased immigration began to present a national problem because?:",
        "correct_answer": "unskilled laborers tended to concentrate in crowded urban slums.",
        "distractor1": "contract laborers enabled employers to combat strikes effectively.",
        "distractor2": "the American educational system could not absorb the numbers of immigrant children.",
        "distractor3": "unskilled laborers could not become members of labor unions.",
        "distractor4": "skilled laborers were essential to industry."
    },
    {
        "question": "The social ethic which prevailed in late 19c America stressed that?:",
        "correct_answer": "economic success was available to anyone who worked hard.",
        "distractor1": "family background should determine social rank.",
        "distractor2": "social class should determine social rank.",
        "distractor3": "greed had more to do with success than good character did."
    },
    {
        "question": "Those believing in the idea of the  Melting Pot  predicted that?:",
        "correct_answer": "a unique American culture would emerge from the blending of Old World cultures.",
        "distractor1": "each immigrant group would always maintain its separate identity.",
        "distractor2": "all immigrant groups would eventually adopt an English culture.",
        "distractor3": "some immigrant groups would retain their culture while others would gradually blend into the mainstream culture."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the late 1800s, the available welfare services were generally provided to the urban poor by?:",
        "correct_answer": "the bosses of the city machines.",
        "distractor1": "private philanthropic organizations.",
        "distractor2": "federal relief agencies.",
        "distractor3": "state welfare agencies.",
        "distractor4": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "Europeans who came to the United States after 1880 have been described as  new  immigrants mainly because they?:",
        "correct_answer": "came generally from different countries than most earlier immigrants.",
        "distractor1": "were considered physically and mentally superior to earlier immigrants.",
        "distractor2": "arrived before the closing of the frontier and settled farms in the West.",
        "distractor3": "came chiefly from northern and western Europe."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following enabled city dwellers of the late 19c and early 20c to live in greater comfort and safety?:",
        "correct_answer": "the adoption of public health regulations.",
        "distractor1": "the increased use of coal-burning stoves.",
        "distractor2": "pollution-control legislation.",
        "distractor3": "government financing of low-income housing."
    },
    {
        "question": "The most dangerous aspect of urban life in the late 19c was?:",
        "correct_answer": "inadequate water and sewage systems.",
        "distractor1": "opium addiction.",
        "distractor2": "air pollution.",
        "distractor3": "the increase of murders and robberies."
    },
    {
        "question": "The groups that migrated to the cities after the Civil War included large numbers of all of the following groups EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "southern Whites.",
        "distractor1": "southern Blacks.",
        "distractor2": "foreign immigrants.",
        "distractor3": "eastern farmers."
    },
    {
        "question": "In his book  The Influence of Sea Power Upon History  (1890), Alfred T. Mahan argued which of the following?:",
        "correct_answer": "that great empires are based on naval supremacy.",
        "distractor1": "that colonial possessions are a drain on the nation's resources.",
        "distractor2": "that a strong merchant marine is less important than a navy.",
        "distractor3": "that naval bases are unnecessary for the protection of colonial possessions.",
        "distractor4": "that land forces are more important than naval forces."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Platt Amendment of 1901 provided for?:",
        "correct_answer": "the United States' right to intervene in Cuba to maintain peace and law and order.",
        "distractor1": "the construction of the Panama Canal.",
        "distractor2": "the leasing of the port of Hong Kong.",
        "distractor3": "a large subsidy to the British to compensate for American diplomatic slights.",
        "distractor4": "the establishment of cavalry under the command of Theodore Roosevelt."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement best summarizes the Open Door Policy?:",
        "correct_answer": "all nations should be granted equal trading rights in China.",
        "distractor1": "the United States should have its own sphere of influence in China.",
        "distractor2": "Japan should be excluded from trading with China.",
        "distractor3": "China should be punished for its support of the Boxer Rebellion.",
        "distractor4": "the United States should control international trade in the Pacific."
    },
    {
        "question": "When President Taft called for  Dollar Diplomacy,  he advocated?:",
        "correct_answer": "that American businessmen should invest in underdeveloped countries rather than lend those countries U. S. dollars.",
        "distractor1": "that American government money be loaned to underdeveloped countries.",
        "distractor2": "purchasing foreign-owned territories.",
        "distractor3": "the rejection of the Open Door Policy.",
        "distractor4": "encouraging foreign exports by reducing tariffs."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the first  quarter of the 20c, a major",
        "correct_answer": "defending the approaches to the Panama Canal.",
        "distractor1": "preventing the outbreak of war in Europe.",
        "distractor2": "creating international machinery to arbitrate disputes.",
        "distractor3": "meeting the challenge of Japanese imperialism.",
        "distractor4": "gaining international acceptance of the neutral concept of freedom of the seas."
    },
    {
        "question": "The use of African-American troops in the United States Army during the Spanish-American War had the effect of?:",
        "correct_answer": "arousing racial tensions among troops and with communities around posts, especially in several southern states.",
        "distractor1": "leading to the complete desegregation of the United States military.",
        "distractor2": "promoting a significant, if temporary, wave of racial unity throughout the nation.",
        "distractor3": "none of the above, for there were no black troops in the United States military at this time."
    },
    {
        "question": "The opening of Japan by the United States in the mid-19c was followed by a period of major change known as the Meiji",
        "correct_answer": "the creation of a modern political state which paved the way for industrialization.",
        "distractor1": "the destruction of the  emperor system. ",
        "distractor2": "the complete rejection of Shintom and other traditional values.",
        "distractor3": "the colonization of Japan by Western Europe and the United States.",
        "distractor4": "the  refeudalization  of the agricultural economy."
    },
    {
        "question": "To justify their policies, the new American expansionists of the late 1800s offered all of the following reasons EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "the U. S. should try to create a community of nations to guarantee world peace.",
        "distractor1": "strong nations were destined by natural law to dominate weak ones.",
        "distractor2": "a strong navy was the key to becoming a great nation, and colonies would serve as bases for such a navy.",
        "distractor3": "the U. S. had a duty to spread its superior institutions to less civilized peoples."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Grover Cleveland rejected the effort to annex Hawaii because?:",
        "correct_answer": "a majority of native Hawaiian opposed annexation to the United States.",
        "distractor1": "the islands were not particularly productive.",
        "distractor2": "the United States did not have the naval power to protect the islands.",
        "distractor3": "passage of the McKinley tariff made Hawaiian sugar unprofitable."
    },
    {
        "question": "American went to war against Spain in 1898 because of all of the following reasons EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "Spain's refusal to discuss terms for peace.",
        "distractor1": "the buildup of public pressure for war.",
        "distractor2": "alleged Spanish mistreatment of Cuban civilians.",
        "distractor3": "Americans tended to compare the Cuban insurrection with their own American Revolution."
    },
    {
        "question": "By the end of the 19c, jingoism in the United States was encouraged by all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "new immigrants.",
        "distractor1": "European imperialism.",
        "distractor2": "yellow journalism.",
        "distractor3": "international Darwinism.",
        "distractor4": "naval views of Alfred Thayer Mahan."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the 1890s, leaders who, like Grover Cleveland, favored economic expansion but not the annexation of overseas",
        "correct_answer": "gradually lost ground to those who advocated both formal and informal imperialism.",
        "distractor1": "became more vocal and began to dominate government decision making.",
        "distractor2": "completely abandoned their position in the aftermath of the Spanish-American-Cuban-Filipino War.",
        "distractor3": "came to be concentrated almost exclusively in the Republican party."
    },
    {
        "question": "               The price which",
        "correct_answer": "Social Darwinism.",
        "distractor1": "Calvinism.",
        "distractor2": "Progressivism.",
        "distractor3": "cultural pluralism.",
        "distractor4": "egalitarianism."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the significance of the Venezuelan crisis of 1895 and America's  jingoistic  behavior?:",
        "correct_answer": "it revived the Monroe Doctrine and strengthened U. S. power in Latin America.",
        "distractor1": "it provided Americans with control of the gold of the Orinoco basin.",
        "distractor2": "it proved the cooperative partnership of the new Pan-American Union could work.",
        "distractor3": "it showed that the U. S. should not try to build a canal across Venezuela."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Spanish-American War resulted in which of the following?:",
        "correct_answer": "a guerilla war between Americans and Filipinos.",
        "distractor1": "American colonization of Cuba.",
        "distractor2": "Theodore Roosevelt's election as president in 1900.",
        "distractor3": "the decline of the anti-imperialist movement.",
        "distractor4": "independence of Puerto Rico."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Roosevelt Corollary to the Monroe Doctrine established which of the following?:",
        "correct_answer": "the right of the U. S. to act as a police power in the Western Hemisphere nations.",
        "distractor1": "the right of European nations to forcefully collect debts in the Western Hemisphere.",
        "distractor2": "the right of the United States to build and fortify an Atlantic-Pacific canal.",
        "distractor3": "the independence of Panama from Columbia.",
        "distractor4": "the right of the U. S. to act as an arbitrator in European conflicts with Western hemisphere nations."
    },
    {
        "question": "At the Portsmouth Peace Conference ending the Russo-Japanese War, Teddy Roosevelt helped to establish?:",
        "correct_answer": "a new balance of power between the Russians and the Japanese.",
        "distractor1": "U. S. control over the potentially rich Manchurian peninsula.",
        "distractor2": "that Portsmouth, New Hampshire, would be the headquarters of the World Court established to resolve international disputes.",
        "distractor3": "the end of British influence over the affairs of China.",
        "distractor4": "the expulsion of all foreign nations from China."
    },
    {
        "question": "McKinley officially urged the Senate to accept acquisition of the Philippines for all of the following reasons EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "the Phlippines were a potential source for corporate business profits.",
        "distractor1": "we couldn't give them back to Spain.",
        "distractor2": "someone else such as Germany may take the Philippines if we don't.",
        "distractor3": "the Filipinos were unfit for self-government.",
        "distractor4": "we were obligated to Christianize and civilize the Filipinos."
    },
    {
        "question": "The policy of imperialism in the U. S. from 1890 to 1910 was largely the result of?:",
        "correct_answer": "demands for commercial expansion.",
        "distractor1": "the theory of isolation.",
        "distractor2": "a desire to build up a colonial empire.",
        "distractor3": "a widespread desire to become a world power.",
        "distractor4": "missionary zeal."
    },
    {
        "question": "The anti-imperialists in the 1890s opposed U. S. acquisition of an empire for all of the following reasons EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "the vast majority of Americans opposed such empire-building.",
        "distractor1": "acquiring Pacific territories would bring  inferior  Asian races into the nation as potential citizens.",
        "distractor2": "an empire would require a large standing army and entangling foreign alliances.",
        "distractor3": "imperialism was simply immoral, a repudiation of America's commitment to human freedom."
    },
    {
        "question": "The rise of the Industrial Revolution led to?:",
        "correct_answer": "all of these choices are correct.",
        "distractor1": "a rise in the standard of living for the working class.",
        "distractor2": "the development of the middle class.",
        "distractor3": "great difficulty for the workers in adapting to the new way of life."
    },
    {
        "question": "The most profound economic development by mid-19c America was the?",
        "correct_answer": "rise of the factory.",
        "distractor1": "development of a national banking system.",
        "distractor2": "creation of corporations.",
        "distractor3": "decline of the small-town merchant and general store."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Erie Canal revolutionized domestic markets because it permitted the?:",
        "correct_answer": "transfer of goods from New York to New Orleans along inland waterways.",
        "distractor1": "shipment of wheat from Chicago to the Pacific Northwest.",
        "distractor2": "movement of cotton from the Deep South to New England.",
        "distractor3": "transport of gold from California to the east coast."
    },
    {
        "question": "The following pairs match inventions with their inventors. Which pair is incorrectly matched?:",
        "correct_answer": "Samuel Slater -- standardized muskets.",
        "distractor1": "Eli Whitney -- cotton gin.",
        "distractor2": "James Watt -- steam engine.",
        "distractor3": "Robert Fulton -- steamboat."
    },
    {
        "question": "The situation of women and immigrants in the factory system was similar in that they both?:",
        "correct_answer": "were powerless to affect pay rates or working conditions.",
        "distractor1": "were able to organize labor unions successfully.",
        "distractor2": "saw conditions in their factories slowly improve.",
        "distractor3": "found opportunities for rapid improvement."
    },
    {
        "question": "By the first decade of the 19c, American manufacturing had been revolutionized by the advent of?:",
        "correct_answer": "interchangeable machine parts.",
        "distractor1": "labor unions.",
        "distractor2": "transcontinental railroads.",
        "distractor3": "mail-order catalogues.",
        "distractor4": "the electric engine."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following supplied the largest number of immigrants to the United States during the first half of the 19c?:",
        "correct_answer": "Ireland.",
        "distractor1": "England.",
        "distractor2": "Africa.",
        "distractor3": "the German states.",
        "distractor4": "Holland."
    },
    {
        "question": "The direction of the population movement that took place between 1790 and 1840 was from?:",
        "correct_answer": "the Atlantic coast to the areas between the Appalachians and the Mississippi.",
        "distractor1": "the North to the South.",
        "distractor2": "the Old Northwest back to New England.",
        "distractor3": "New England to California.",
        "distractor4": "the South to the North."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the case of  Commonwealth v. Hunt , the Massachusetts Supreme Court ruled that?:",
        "correct_answer": "labor unions were not necessarily illegal combinations or monopolies.",
        "distractor1": "slavery was unconstitutional in Massachusetts.",
        "distractor2": "Massachusetts tax money could not be used to support an unjust war against Mexico.",
        "distractor3": "segregated schools for blacks in Massachusetts did not violate the U. S. Constitution."
    },
    {
        "question": "What conflict in values emerged as America went through its market revolution?:",
        "correct_answer": "although Americans professed to believe in equality, the market revolution coupled with American materialistic pursuits led to great inequalities",
        "distractor1": "Americans had long enjoyed living in settled and stable communities, but transportation improvements led to much greater geographic mobility.",
        "distractor2": "personal lifestyles prized by Northerners, who were more religious, differed from those of southerners, who were more materialistic--a distinction that",
        "distractor3": "most farmers clung to Crevecoeur's ideal of a semi-subsistence way of life, despite the relentless reach of commercial networks."
    },
    {
        "question": "The beginning of the American Industrial Revolution during the early 1800s resulted from all of the following",
        "correct_answer": "monetary assistance from the federal government to new factories.",
        "distractor1": "technological advanced imported from England.",
        "distractor2": "the appearance of better transportation systems.",
        "distractor3": "new inventions such as the cotton gin."
    },
    {
        "question": "Marshall's decisions in  Fletcher v. Peck  and  Dartmouth v. Woodward  dealt with the?:",
        "correct_answer": "protection of contracts from violation by state governments.",
        "distractor1": "enforcement of federal law in the territories.",
        "distractor2": "right of Indians to control their own lands.",
        "distractor3": "sale of publicly held frontier lands."
    },
    {
        "question": "The paternalistic factory system of Lowell and Waltham did not lost long because?:",
        "correct_answer": "in the highly competitive textile market, manufacturers were eager to cut labor costs.",
        "distractor1": "workers resented being watched over so carefully.",
        "distractor2": "unions undermined the owners' authority.",
        "distractor3": "men found jobs in the factories, and they disliked the paternalistic system."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the 1820s and 1830s, the growth of business was assisted by all of the following developments EXCEPT the?:",
        "correct_answer": "creation of a stable state banking system.",
        "distractor1": "specialization of stores.",
        "distractor2": "improvement in the distribution of goods.",
        "distractor3": "emergence of new general incorporation laws."
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following were provisions of Clay's  American System  EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "low tariffs and state support of internal improvements.",
        "distractor1": "high tariffs to protect infant industries.",
        "distractor2": "federal financing of internal improvements.",
        "distractor3": "a national bank with branches in the states."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Industrial Revolution had which of the following effects on slavery in the South?:",
        "correct_answer": "rapid growth in the textile industry encouraged Southern planters to grow cotton, thereby making slavery more important to the economy.",
        "distractor1": "the creation of numerous labor-saving machines vastly reduced the need for slave labor.",
        "distractor2": "the government bought and freed Southern slaves, then transported them to the North, where factories were experiencing a major labor shortage.",
        "distractor3": "the Industrial Revolution began as the Civil War was ending and it provided work for many former slaves.",
        "distractor4": "new farm machinery required slaves and masters to work more closely together, with a resulting reduction of mutual hostility."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which was the most important immediate cause of the rise of manufacturing in the United States?:",
        "correct_answer": "stoppages of trade by the embargoes and the War of 1812.",
        "distractor1": "growth of the textile industry.",
        "distractor2": "New England water power.",
        "distractor3": "patriotic appeals and the growth of nationalism."
    },
    {
        "question": "The American system of manufacturing, which emerged in the early 1800s, was successful because of its use of?:",
        "correct_answer": "interchangeable parts to allow for mass production of high-quality items.",
        "distractor1": "slave labor.",
        "distractor2": "handsome, individually crafted, high-quality items.",
        "distractor3": "the  putting out  system--distributing raw materials and collecting finished products for distribution.",
        "distractor4": "early electric power to provide cheap energy for new factories."
    },
    {
        "question": "The  Lowell System  refers to which of the following?:",
        "correct_answer": "employment of young women who were then housed in dormitories.",
        "distractor1": "chattel slavery.",
        "distractor2": "worker's cooperatives.",
        "distractor3": "an early American labor union.",
        "distractor4": "a business organization with limited liability for its owners."
    },
    {
        "question": "Developments in transportation usually occurred in the following order?:",
        "correct_answer": "turnpikes --&gt; steamboats --&gt; canals --&gt; railroads.",
        "distractor1": "railroads --&gt; flatboats --&gt; canals --&gt; turnpikes.",
        "distractor2": "turnpikes --&gt; canals --&gt; flatboats --&gt; steamboats.",
        "distractor3": "canals --&gt; turnpikes --&gt; railroads --&gt; steamboats."
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1933, the United States finally recognized the government of communist Russia, in part because the?:",
        "correct_answer": "United States hopes for substantial trade with Russia.",
        "distractor1": "Soviet Union completely abandoned support of the Comintern.",
        "distractor2": "communists had established their legitimacy through free elections.",
        "distractor3": "United States felt it needed a new ally against Hitler."
    },
    {
        "question": "The effect of the Neutrality Acts of 1935-1937 was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "encourage aggressor nations because they knew in advance that the U. S. would not become involved.",
        "distractor1": "halt all trade between the U. S. and belligerent nations.",
        "distractor2": "encourage trade between the United States and belligerent nations.",
        "distractor3": "prevent United States involvement in European wars.",
        "distractor4": "encourage peaceful settlement of problems between potentially belligerent nations."
    },
    {
        "question": "The diplomatic strategy behind the Lend-Lease program was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "support England's war efforts against Germany without the United States entering World War II.",
        "distractor1": "continue American neutrality at all costs during World War II.",
        "distractor2": "support non-Communist nations at the close of World War II.",
        "distractor3": "stimulate the growth of Third World nations' economies.",
        "distractor4": "aid American business interests in Latin America."
    },
    {
        "question": "The most accurate description of United States foreign policy toward Japan between 1900 and 1941 is that the United",
        "correct_answer": "attempted to restrict Japan's growth and power.",
        "distractor1": "supported Japan's territorial ambitions.",
        "distractor2": "encouraged Japan to develop a strong industrial base.",
        "distractor3": "lacked interest in Japanese policies."
    },
    {
        "question": "The America First Committee?:",
        "correct_answer": "argued that a Nazi victory in Europe would pose no threat to American national security.",
        "distractor1": "pushed for more aid to England and France in order to defend America.",
        "distractor2": "urged an immediate declaration of war on Germany.",
        "distractor3": "drew most of its support from the East and West Coasts and the South."
    },
    {
        "question": "The high-tariff policy of the United States between the two world wars?:",
        "correct_answer": "hindered European nations from repaying their war debts to the U. S.",
        "distractor1": "triggered economic growth in the United States but stagnation in Europe.",
        "distractor2": "created an abnormal speculative spiral on the U. S. stock market.",
        "distractor3": "retarded the growth of manufacturing in the U. S.",
        "distractor4": "enabled the U. S. to recover from the Depression more rapidly than other countries."
    },
    {
        "question": "The one obstacle to resolving American-Japanese during the 1941 negotiations was?:",
        "correct_answer": "the embargo on war supplies to Japan.",
        "distractor1": "control of the natural resources of southeast Asia.",
        "distractor2": "Japanese occupation of China.",
        "distractor3": "the Japanese alliance with Germany and Italy."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Latin American policies of Herbert Hoover and Franklin Roosevelt were similar in that both?:",
        "correct_answer": "intended to decrease U. S. intervention there.",
        "distractor1": "were guided by the protectionism of the Hawley-Smoot Tariff.",
        "distractor2": "intended to create a stable regime in Nicaragua.",
        "distractor3": "intended to use force, if necessary, to protect American oil interests in Mexico.",
        "distractor4": "advocated digging an isthmus canal in northern Nicaragua."
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States responded to the Japanese seizure of Manchuria from China in 1931 by?:",
        "correct_answer": "issuing the Stimson Doctrine, which amounted to a moral lecture.",
        "distractor1": "asking the League of Nations to condemn Japanese aggression.",
        "distractor2": "doing nothing.",
        "distractor3": "imposing trade sanctions against Japan."
    },
    {
        "question": "As Italy invaded Ethiopia and Japan invaded China, the Roosevelt administration?:",
        "correct_answer": "limited its actions to feeble warnings and moral outrage.",
        "distractor1": "encouraged the League of Nations to impose economic sanctions on the aggressor nations.",
        "distractor2": "sent men, money, and material to the invaded countries.",
        "distractor3": "joined the League of Nations in declaring war against the aggressor nations."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement best represents the United States' response to reports of the German persecution of Jews?:",
        "correct_answer": "the United States expressed sympathy for the plight of the Jews, but refused to liberalize its restrictive immigration laws.",
        "distractor1": "Americans overwhelmingly supported legislation to admit twenty thousand German refugee children.",
        "distractor2": "the United States expressed sympathy for the plight of the Jews, and liberalized its restrictive immigration laws.",
        "distractor3": "the United States sponsored the ship  St. Louis  to rescue 900 Jews for resettlement in America."
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of Franklin D. Roosevelt's Four Freedoms speech was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "gain support for his Lend-Lease program.",
        "distractor1": "obtain a congressional declaration of war against Germany.",
        "distractor2": "obtain a congressional declaration of war against Japan.",
        "distractor3": "assert complete American neutrality in the war in Europe.",
        "distractor4": "set forth the terms under which Germany's surrender would be accepted."
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the 1828 presidential election demonstrate?:",
        "correct_answer": "that the new political parties were strongly sectional in their sources of strength.",
        "distractor1": "that supporters of common people would have difficulty being elected.",
        "distractor2": "that first-term presidents usually can be reelected.",
        "distractor3": "that New Englanders would never vote for a southerner for president."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Second Bank of the United States performed all of the following functions EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "shifting funds from the West and South to the Northeast.",
        "distractor1": "receiving and paying out federal funds.",
        "distractor2": "stabilizing the money supply.",
        "distractor3": "keeping a check on the loans of other banks.",
        "distractor4": "making loans to the federal government."
    },
    {
        "question": "The debate between Webster and Hayne in 1830 concerned?:",
        "correct_answer": "the nullification of federal laws.",
        "distractor1": "the re-chartering of the Bank of the United States.",
        "distractor2": "the extension of slavery into the territories.",
        "distractor3": "the Fugitive Slave Law."
    },
    {
        "question": "Andrew Jackson's Specie Circular sought to?:",
        "correct_answer": "slow down speculation in public land.",
        "distractor1": "pay off the government debts.",
        "distractor2": "replace the Bank of the United States with an independent treasury.",
        "distractor3": "end the financial panic of 1837.",
        "distractor4": "establish the free coinage of silver."
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following statements concerning equality in Jacksonian America are true EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "because political leaders had to appeal to an expanded electorate, campaigns became less boisterous and more focused on specific policy issues.",
        "distractor1": "virtually all adult white males could vote and held equal status before the law.",
        "distractor2": "in terms of wealth and access to productive resources, American society was becoming less equal.",
        "distractor3": "patterns of democratic dress created both fewer differences in appearance between wealthy and ordinary men, and greater distinctions between men and women."
    },
    {
        "question": "As a result of Jackson's bank policies?:",
        "correct_answer": "all of these choices are correct.",
        "distractor1": "sales of public land rose tremendously.",
        "distractor2": "banks printed new banknotes with abandon.",
        "distractor3": "the nation entered a period of speculative mania."
    },
    {
        "question": "The chief weapon used by Andrew Jackson in his dispute with the National Bank was?:",
        "correct_answer": "to deposit government money in state banks.",
        "distractor1": "paying government debts from tariff revenue only.",
        "distractor2": "his decision to print more paper money.",
        "distractor3": "to give unqualified support to the Tariff of 1832.",
        "distractor4": "the support of the Supreme Court in voiding the bank's charter."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the opinion of Andrew Jackson, and probably most of his contemporaries, regarding the spoils system?:",
        "correct_answer": "the frequent rotation of officeholders had a beneficial effect on the government.",
        "distractor1": "it should be abolished, and civil service laws should be enacted.",
        "distractor2": "it was injurious to good government, but had to be retained for the good of the Democratic party.",
        "distractor3": "it would ultimately favor Henry Clay and the Whigs.",
        "distractor4": "it was injurious to the Democratic party, but had to be retained because of its beneficial effect on government."
    },
    {
        "question": "The political purpose for proposing the Tariff of 1828 was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "discredit the administration of President John Quincy Adams.",
        "distractor1": " get even  with the New Englanders for the Hartford Convention.",
        "distractor2": "secure the support of the shipping interests of New England by depriving manufacturers of the protection they desired.",
        "distractor3": "assure the Jacksonians of Southern support in the election of 1828.",
        "distractor4": "gain the favor of producers of such raw materials as wool, hemp, and flax."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Whig Party turned against President John Tyler because?:",
        "correct_answer": "he opposed the entire Whig legislative program.",
        "distractor1": "he was felt to be ineffective in pushing the Whig agenda through Congress.",
        "distractor2": "he spoke out in favor of the annexation of Texas.",
        "distractor3": "he criticized Henry Clay's handling of the Nullification Crisis.",
        "distractor4": "he aggressively favored the expansion of slavery."
    },
    {
        "question": "Jacksonian Democrats favored all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "the caucus system of nominating candidates.",
        "distractor1": "rotation in office.",
        "distractor2": "universal suffrage for white males.",
        "distractor3": "rewarding political supporters with government jobs.",
        "distractor4": "presidential electors being chosen by popular vote."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following describes the policy adopted during the 1820s and 1830s as a permanent solution to the Native American",
        "correct_answer": "the removal of Native Americans to lands west of the Mississippi.",
        "distractor1": "the payment of Native Americans to migrate to Canada.",
        "distractor2": "the establishment of reservations in various sections of the country.",
        "distractor3": "the forced migration of Native Americans to territories owned by Mexico.",
        "distractor4": "the assimilation of Native Americans by breaking up tribes and granting American citizenship to individual members."
    },
    {
        "question": "Andrew Jackson's view of the presidency emphasized?:",
        "correct_answer": "leadership by the executive branch in the interests of the people.",
        "distractor1": "strong Cabinet leadership.",
        "distractor2": "strengthening the power of the state.",
        "distractor3": "support for the nullification doctrine.",
        "distractor4": "congressional partisan leadership."
    },
    {
        "question": "John C. Calhoun advocated nullification of a federal law in 1828, and again in 1832 to?:",
        "correct_answer": "avoid secession.",
        "distractor1": "please President Jackson.",
        "distractor2": "defeat the re-charting of the Bank of the United States.",
        "distractor3": "promote the formation of the Confederate States of America."
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following reflect the views of Americans expressed by Alexis de Tocqueville and other early 19c European",
        "correct_answer": "Americans exhibited a strong sense of social deference.",
        "distractor1": "daily life in America was highly politicized.",
        "distractor2": "Americans exhibited a strong sense of national pride.",
        "distractor3": "Americans were highly individualistic.",
        "distractor4": "Americans valued personal freedom."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the early 19c, which section of the country tended to oppose tariffs?:",
        "correct_answer": "the South.",
        "distractor1": "New England.",
        "distractor2": "the West.",
        "distractor3": "the Middle Atlantic."
    },
    {
        "question": "Andrew Jackson's remark,  John Marshall has made his decision; now let him enforce it , refers to the president's",
        "correct_answer": "move the Cherokees west of the Mississippi River regardless of Supreme Court rulings.",
        "distractor1": "destroy the National Bank despite the Supreme Court ruling upholding its constitutionality.",
        "distractor2": "use force, if necessary, to make South Carolina obey federal law that South Carolina thought was unconstitutional.",
        "distractor3": "disregard Chief Justice Marshall's ruling in Gibbons v. Ogden."
    },
    {
        "question": "The major issue in Jackson's campaign for re-election in 1832 was the?:",
        "correct_answer": "Second Bank of the United States.",
        "distractor1": "stationing of federal troops in South Carolina.",
        "distractor2": "gag rule.",
        "distractor3": "Maysville Road veto.",
        "distractor4": "the spoils system."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 1830s and 1840s, the primary difference between Whigs and the Democrats was that?:",
        "correct_answer": "the Whigs favored an expanded, activist federal government while the Democrats favored a limited non-interventionist federal government.",
        "distractor1": "the Whigs favored economic expansion while the Democrats favored a stable but retracted economy.",
        "distractor2": "the Democrats favored the abolition of slavery while the Whigs favored retention of the current system of slavery allowed in the Southern states, but no further",
        "distractor3": "the Democrats were strongly supported by evangelical Christians and supported a wide range of moral reforms while the Whigs were supported by Westerners who",
        "distractor4": "the Whigs favored limitations on westward expansion while the Democrats favored the concept of Manifest Destiny and expansion to the Pacific Ocean."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the case of   Worcester v. Georgia , the Supreme Court?:",
        "correct_answer": "ruled that the Cherokees had  an unquestionable right  to their lands.",
        "distractor1": "ordered the Cherokees to vacate their lands east of the Mississippi River.",
        "distractor2": "prohibited the intermarriage of Indians and whites.",
        "distractor3": "ordered the state of Georgia to enforce Indian voting rights."
    },
    {
        "question": "In  Marbury v. Madison , Chief Justice John Marshall argued successfully that the Supreme Court could?:",
        "correct_answer": "declare federal laws unconstitutional.",
        "distractor1": "remove federal officials who would not or could not perform their duties.",
        "distractor2": "determine cases involving interstate commerce.",
        "distractor3": "decide whether debts should be considered in contracts.",
        "distractor4": "uphold the authority of the federal government over the states."
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1800 Federalists viewed Jeffersonian Republicans as dangerous radicals and feared the consequences if they gained",
        "correct_answer": "the Republicans did not make nearly as many changes as they had advocated.",
        "distractor1": "the Republicans adopted a more radical plan than they had previously advocated.",
        "distractor2": "Jefferson immediately curtailed overseas commerce with France.",
        "distractor3": "the Republicans maintained the policies of the Federalists.",
        "distractor4": "the Republicans ruthlessly destroyed all opposition to their policies."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following does NOT describe the Louisiana Purchase of 1803?:",
        "correct_answer": "French power expanded in the Western Hemisphere.",
        "distractor1": "the United States purchased Louisiana from France for $15,000,000.",
        "distractor2": "Jefferson expanded the powers of the presidency.",
        "distractor3": "the United States doubled in size.",
        "distractor4": "the treaty of cession left some of the boundaries vague."
    },
    {
        "question": "Between 1806 and 1809, non-importation, non-intercourse, and embargo acts sought to?:",
        "correct_answer": "forced Great Britain to recognize American rights.",
        "distractor1": "bring peace between France and Great Britain.",
        "distractor2": "encourage domestic American manufacturing.",
        "distractor3": "balance Southern and Northern economic power.",
        "distractor4": "help Britain in the Napoleonic Wars."
    },
    {
        "question": "The causes of the War of 1812 included all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "strong sectional rivalries that could only be overcome by an external enemy.",
        "distractor1": "demand for respect of America's neutral rights.",
        "distractor2": "land hunger in the West as well as a desire for Florida.",
        "distractor3": "fear that Indian attacks were caused by the British."
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the immediate results of the new transportation routes constructed during the  Canal Age  was?:",
        "correct_answer": "an increased white settlement in the Northwest.",
        "distractor1": "the renewed cooperation between states and the national government on internal improvement projects.",
        "distractor2": "the conviction that the national government should be responsible for all internal improvements.",
        "distractor3": "an increased white settlement in the Southwest."
    },
    {
        "question": "The issuance of the Monroe Doctrine in 1823 was prompted by?:",
        "correct_answer": "the fear that France might intervene in Latin America to restore Spanish colonial rule.",
        "distractor1": "the Russian annexation of Alaska.",
        "distractor2": "President Monroe's hope of increasing his popularity with the American public.",
        "distractor3": "continuing British intervention in Latin American affairs."
    },
    {
        "question": "As a result of the  Corrupt Bargain ?:",
        "correct_answer": "John Quincy Adams became president.",
        "distractor1": "Henry Clay's American System suffered a crushing defeat.",
        "distractor2": "Congress approved the Monroe Doctrine.",
        "distractor3": "the Bank of the United States was established.",
        "distractor4": "textile workers rebelled over unpaid wages."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Lewis and Clark expedition occurred AFTER which of the following events?:",
        "correct_answer": "the Louisiana Purchase.",
        "distractor1": "the War of 1812.",
        "distractor2": "the Embargo Act of 1807.",
        "distractor3": "the Missouri Compromise.",
        "distractor4": "the Nullification Controversy."
    },
    {
        "question": "All of these statements support the foreign policy of Jefferson and Madison EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "the Embargo Act and the Non-Intercourse Act were embarrassingly close to a peace-at-any-price policy.",
        "distractor1": "the Embargo Act of 1807 kept American ships off the high seas and prevented impressment of our sailors by England.",
        "distractor2": "England and France needed our goods more than we needed their trade. They were at war and needed all the imports they could get.",
        "distractor3": "circumstances can make avoidance of war a wiser policy than insistence upon national rights.",
        "distractor4": "had local officials aided the federal government in preventing smuggling, our rights as neutrals would soon have been observed by England and France."
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to the Embargo Act of 1807, a significant factor in the development of American industry in the period 1800-1820",
        "correct_answer": "protective tariffs.",
        "distractor1": "the invention of the cotton gin.",
        "distractor2": "the availability of cheap immigrant labor.",
        "distractor3": "the development of railroads.",
        "distractor4": "the Louisiana Purchase."
    },
    {
        "question": "Thomas Jefferson maintained that?:",
        "correct_answer": "by means of education, republican societies should train the ablest minds for leadership.",
        "distractor1": "only educated men could know the truth.",
        "distractor2": "until the masses were educated aristocratic government was more likely to be just than was republican government.",
        "distractor3": "education would make all men equal in ability.",
        "distractor4": "the greatest enemies of liberty were the over-educated."
    },
    {
        "question": "In  McCulloch v. Maryland , the Supreme Court declared that?:",
        "correct_answer": "a state cannot tax an agency of the federal government.",
        "distractor1": "Congress lacked the power to charter a national bank.",
        "distractor2": "the state of Maryland was superior to the United States.",
        "distractor3": "a college had a right to a charter."
    },
    {
        "question": "The War Hawks were?:",
        "correct_answer": "Republicans from the West and South who wanted to take Canada from Britain and Florida from Spain.",
        "distractor1": "mostly from New England.",
        "distractor2": "eager for war against Napoleon in order to gain the Louisiana Territory.",
        "distractor3": "supporters of Jefferson and Madison's policy of economic coercion."
    },
    {
        "question": "In diplomatic and economic terms, the War of 1812?:",
        "correct_answer": "could be considered the Second War for American Independence.",
        "distractor1": "was a disaster for the United States.",
        "distractor2": "was considered a victory for Britain.",
        "distractor3": "resulted in the fall of the British government that concluded the conflict."
    },
    {
        "question": "The resolutions from the Hartford Convention?:",
        "correct_answer": "helped to cause the death of the Federalist Party.",
        "distractor1": "resulted in the resurgence of states' rights.",
        "distractor2": "called for southern secession from the Union.",
        "distractor3": "supported use of state militias against the British."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Treaty of Ghent, which ended the War of 1812?:",
        "correct_answer": "nothing was settled beyond a restoration of the prewar status quo.",
        "distractor1": "most American demands were satisfied.",
        "distractor2": "the Americans made substantial concessions to the British.",
        "distractor3": "the issues that had led to war were finally resolved.",
        "distractor4": "Britain agreed to end the impressment of American seamen."
    },
    {
        "question": "The outcome of the election of 1824 between John Quincy Adams and Andrew Jackson was decided by?:",
        "correct_answer": "the House of Representatives.",
        "distractor1": "the Electoral College.",
        "distractor2": "a plurality of the popular vote.",
        "distractor3": "the Senate.",
        "distractor4": "the Supreme Court."
    },
    {
        "question": "During both the Washington and Jefferson administrations, the Western settlers' most urgent and consistent demand on the",
        "correct_answer": "guaranty of an outlet to the sea for their produce.",
        "distractor1": "repeal of the whiskey tax.",
        "distractor2": "establishment of a national banking system.",
        "distractor3": "reduction in the tariff.",
        "distractor4": "removal of Native Americans to reservations."
    },
    {
        "question": "Chief Justice John Marshall asserted that only Congress, not the states, possessed the power to control interstate commerce.",
        "correct_answer": " Gibbons v. Ogden .",
        "distractor1": " Marbury v. Madison .",
        "distractor2": " McCulloch v. Maryland .",
        "distractor3": " Cohens v. Virginia .",
        "distractor4": " Jones v. Clinton ."
    },
    {
        "question": "The congressional election of 1810 was important because it?:",
        "correct_answer": "added a number of young, western, anti-British representatives to the House.",
        "distractor1": "greatly increased the size of the Republican party.",
        "distractor2": "brought in a number of peace advocates.",
        "distractor3": "gave rise to a new political party."
    },
    {
        "question": "After the War of 1812, Henry Clay called for an  American System , by which he meant?:",
        "correct_answer": "internal improvements that would make the nation self-sufficient.",
        "distractor1": "a system of high tariffs to keep out European products.",
        "distractor2": "a unique method of manufacturing that Europeans could not emulate.",
        "distractor3": "a new way of winning wars."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Rush-Bagot Treaty, Great Britain and the United agreed?:",
        "correct_answer": "to limit their naval forces on the Great Lakes.",
        "distractor1": "on a timetable for the withdrawal of British forces from the Oregon territory.",
        "distractor2": "on the fishing rights of each in the Atlantic.",
        "distractor3": "to the creation of an Indian buffer state in the Northwest."
    },
    {
        "question": "Recent historians describe the  Era of Good Feelings  as?:",
        "correct_answer": "free of ideological disputes.",
        "distractor1": "marked by deep divisions over economic and sectional issues.",
        "distractor2": "characterized by multiparty harmony.",
        "distractor3": "marked by little interference of the Supreme Court in political affairs."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Embargo Act of 1807 hurt which of the following the MOST?:",
        "correct_answer": "New England.",
        "distractor1": "England.",
        "distractor2": "France.",
        "distractor3": "the South.",
        "distractor4": "Spain."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Panic of 1819 was the result of a speculative boom in the economy that ran for a number of years before the panic. All of",
        "correct_answer": "tight credit from the Bank of the United States.",
        "distractor1": "increasing world prices for American farm products.",
        "distractor2": "a land boom.",
        "distractor3": "easy credit from state wildcat banks."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Missouri Compromise of 1820 did all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "establish the principle of popular sovereignty south of 36o 30'.",
        "distractor1": "bring in Maine as a free state.",
        "distractor2": "prohibit slavery north of latitude 36o 30'.",
        "distractor3": "maintain the balance of slave and free states.",
        "distractor4": "bring in Missouri as a slave state."
    },
    {
        "question": "When the House of Representatives passed the Tallmadge Amendment in response to Missouri's request for admission to the",
        "correct_answer": "would threaten the sectional balance.",
        "distractor1": "might keep alive the institution of slavery.",
        "distractor2": "would slow the growth of the West.",
        "distractor3": "would silence the abolitionists."
    },
    {
        "question": "            Let every nation know, whether it",
        "correct_answer": "containment.",
        "distractor1": "colonialism.",
        "distractor2": "neutrality.",
        "distractor3": "non-involvement.",
        "distractor4": "non-alignment."
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following events took place during the Kennedy administration EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "the U-2 Incident.",
        "distractor1": "the Bay of Pigs invasion.",
        "distractor2": "the building of the Berlin Wall.",
        "distractor3": "a limited test ban treaty signed by the US, the USSR, and Great Britain.",
        "distractor4": "the Cuban Missile Crisis."
    },
    {
        "question": "After campaigning to expand the welfare state, especially in the areas of health care and education, President Kennedy?:",
        "correct_answer": "failed to obtain most of his major legislative initiatives.",
        "distractor1": "abandoned all of these ideas in favor of a more conservative approach.",
        "distractor2": "succeeded only in winning federal aid to education legislation.",
        "distractor3": "was killed too quickly to achieve anything important."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the Kennedy-Khrushchev era, America and the Soviet union came close to war over crises in Cuba and?:",
        "correct_answer": "Berlin.",
        "distractor1": "Vietnam.",
        "distractor2": "China.",
        "distractor3": "the Middle East.",
        "distractor4": "South Africa."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Alliance for Progress, proposed by President Kennedy in 1961, can be most accurately called an added dimension of?:",
        "correct_answer": "the Good Neighbor policy.",
        "distractor1": "the Truman Doctrine.",
        "distractor2": "the League of Nations.",
        "distractor3": "the Point Four Program.",
        "distractor4": "the Lend-Lease Act."
    },
    {
        "question": "The  hot line  and the nuclear test ban treaty were attempts to?:",
        "correct_answer": "reduce tensions between the United States and the Soviet Union.",
        "distractor1": "contain Soviet power.",
        "distractor2": "create a new alliance between the United States and the Soviet Union.",
        "distractor3": "contain Chinese communism from spreading throughout Southeast Asia."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Kennedy's main goal in the United States' 1962 decision to blockade Cuba was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "force the Soviet Union to remove its missiles from Cuba.",
        "distractor1": "encourage Castro to reopen diplomatic relations with the United States.",
        "distractor2": "use the CIA to overthrow the Castro government forcibly.",
        "distractor3": "encourage the Soviet Union to stop sending soldiers and aid to Castro.",
        "distractor4": "force the resignation of Soviet Premier Nikita Khrushchev."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the Kennedy administration up to 1963, tactics employed to end discrimination included all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "extensive violence by African Americans.",
        "distractor1": " sit-ins  at public lunch counters.",
        "distractor2": "use of federal troops.",
        "distractor3": " freedom riders  on public transportation."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Kennedy's legislative successes included all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "implementing a strong civil rights act.",
        "distractor1": "increasing the minimum wage.",
        "distractor2": "expanding the space program.",
        "distractor3": "establishing the Peace Corps."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about Martin Luther King, Jr.'s speech in Washington in 1963 is correct?:",
        "correct_answer": "it turned a political rally into a historic event and recalled the nation to the ideals of justice and equality.",
        "distractor1": "it spurred the United States Congress to swiftly approve President Kennedy's civil rights bill.",
        "distractor2": "it was a failure because the turnout at the rally was poor and it came at the end of a long and hot day of lengthy speeches.",
        "distractor3": "it was dramatically interrupted when a white racist shot King as he spoke on the steps of the Lincoln Memorial."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Kennedy decided to remove Diem from the presidency of South Vietnam when?:",
        "correct_answer": "Diem launched attacks on the country's Buddhists.",
        "distractor1": "Diem massacred a large number of Viet Cong.",
        "distractor2": "Diem refused to allow American soldiers to engage in combat.",
        "distractor3": "Diem had his own brother shot for treason."
    },
    {
        "question": "When James Meredith attempted to attend the University of Mississippi as that institution's first black student, President",
        "correct_answer": "ordered federal marshals to protect and defend him and ultimately ordered 5,000 army troops onto the campus.",
        "distractor1": "stood by helplessly while Governor Barnett ordered the university closed.",
        "distractor2": "urged Meredith to attend a northern university instead.",
        "distractor3": "prevented riots by quietly negotiating with the governor of Mississippi and university officials."
    },
    {
        "question": "The  centerpiece  of Lyndon Johnson's  war on poverty  was the?:",
        "correct_answer": "Office of Economic Opportunity, with an emphasis on community action.",
        "distractor1": "Department of Family Services, with an emphasis on social work.",
        "distractor2": "Children's Relief Fund, with an emphasis on preschooling.",
        "distractor3": "Agency for Economic Advancement, with an emphasis on job training."
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary reason for the crushing Republican party defeat in 1964 was that?:",
        "correct_answer": "American voters thought Goldwater's views were too extreme and that he was trigger-happy with nuclear weapons.",
        "distractor1": "Democrats were strongly opposed to civil rights legislation reform.",
        "distractor2": "the 1964 Republican national convention was bitterly divided between the Goldwater and Taft forces.",
        "distractor3": "the Deep South began to admire Lyndon Johnson's commitment to civil rights.",
        "distractor4": "there was growing support for President Johnson's policy in Vietnam."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Lyndon Johnson received authorization for the use of force in Vietnam through?:",
        "correct_answer": "the Gulf of Tonkin Resolution.",
        "distractor1": "the Southeast Asia Treaty Organization.",
        "distractor2": "the Truman Doctrine.",
        "distractor3": "the United Nations Security Council.",
        "distractor4": "a declaration of war by Congress."
    },
    {
        "question": "Both the New Frontier and the Great Society shared the idea that?:",
        "correct_answer": "the federal government should meet the economic and social needs of the less fortunate.",
        "distractor1": "foreign trade should be cut to a minimum.",
        "distractor2": "taxes should be raised to stimulate consumer spending.",
        "distractor3": "key industries should be nationalized."
    },
    {
        "question": "The 1968 Tet Offensive?:",
        "correct_answer": "led to the belief in the United States that the Vietnam War was unwinnable.",
        "distractor1": "was depicted in the American news media as a major victory for U. S. forces.",
        "distractor2": "was a military victory for the communist North Vietnamese forces.",
        "distractor3": "brought an immediate end to the Vietnam War.",
        "distractor4": "had little appreciable effect on the course of the Vietnam War."
    },
    {
        "question": "The common use of poll taxes to inhibit black voters in the South was outlawed by the?:",
        "correct_answer": "Twenty-fourth Amendment.",
        "distractor1": "Civil Rights Act of 1964.",
        "distractor2": "Voting Rights Act of 1965.",
        "distractor3": "War on Poverty."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was not part of Johnson's strategy for fighting the war in Vietnam?:",
        "correct_answer": "assassination attempts on North Vietnamese leaders, including Ho Chi Minh.",
        "distractor1": "a bombing campaign against the north, called operation Rolling Thunder.",
        "distractor2": "rejecting peace feelers from Hanoi.",
        "distractor3": "the dispatching of 50,000 more troops to Vietnam."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which section of the United States Constitution was cited by the South in its challenge to the power of the United States",
        "correct_answer": "the Tenth Amendment, which deals with state and federal powers.",
        "distractor1": "Section 5 of the Fourteenth Amendment, which deals with exercise of congressional powers.",
        "distractor2": "the sections of Article I that deal with the powers of Congress.",
        "distractor3": "the sections of Article III that deal with the powers of the Judiciary.",
        "distractor4": "the sections of Article IV that deal with the relations of the states to the federal government."
    },
    {
        "question": "Lyndon Johnson obtained congressional approval for a greater American role in Vietnam by?:",
        "correct_answer": "claiming that the North Vietnamese had fired on American ships in international waters.",
        "distractor1": "using his political skills to charm congressmen into granting him emergency powers.",
        "distractor2": "offering to cut many of his social programs in order to pay for an expanded role.",
        "distractor3": "claiming that nuclear weapons were being developed in North Vietnam."
    },
    {
        "question": "In both the Korean War and the Vietnam War, the?:",
        "correct_answer": "United States fought for years without Congress ever declaring war.",
        "distractor1": "United States managed to achieve a stalemate with the Communist forces.",
        "distractor2": "United Nations sanctioned the U. S. efforts to stop an aggressor.",
        "distractor3": "lack of U. S. success in combat led to the creation of a large anti-war movement."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Gulf of Tonkin Resolution?:",
        "correct_answer": "was claimed by President Johnson as legal authorization for the military escalation of the U. S. role in the conflict.",
        "distractor1": "aroused strong opposition and a lengthy debate in Congress before being narrowly passed.",
        "distractor2": "limited President Johnson to a one-time retaliatory bombing strike on the northern part of Vietnam.",
        "distractor3": "marked the beginning of significant international support for the American response to communist aggression in Indochina."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 1968 presidential election, George Wallace enjoyed an unusually high degree of support for a third-party candidate",
        "correct_answer": "busing of school children for racial integration, expanding government regulations and social programs, and soft treatment of rioters and demonstrators were",
        "distractor1": "the United States should immediately end its military involvement in Vietnam.",
        "distractor2": "the movement toward racial equality should be accelerated through  affirmative action  programs.",
        "distractor3": "programs to alleviate poverty should be fully funded by Congress and that defense spending should be cut sharply to get the money."
    },
    {
        "question": "Supporters of the Warren Court's decisions in the 1960s believed that persons accused of crimes?:",
        "correct_answer": "were entitled to the full protection of the Bill of Rights.",
        "distractor1": "should be treated as if they were guilty.",
        "distractor2": "were treated properly by local and state police.",
        "distractor3": "were the concern of state and local authorities only, not the U. S. government."
    },
    {
        "question": "Lyndon Johnson's Great Society programs included all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "the Alliance for Progress.",
        "distractor1": "the Office of Economic Opportunity.",
        "distractor2": "Head Start.",
        "distractor3": "Medicare.",
        "distractor4": "the Elementary and Secondary Education Act."
    },
    {
        "question": "Of the five major civil rights acts passed during the period 1957-1968, the Voting Rights Act of 1965 is often regarded as the",
        "correct_answer": "protection of the right to vote was regarded as a means whereby other basic rights could be secured.",
        "distractor1": "prior to 1965, there was no legal guarantee of the right to vote for African-Americans.",
        "distractor2": "voting rights would put an end to riots and racial violence.",
        "distractor3": "Malcolm X was a strong advocate of the Voting Rights Act of 1965."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Democratic national convention of 1968 had a negative impact on the Democratic election campaign because?:",
        "correct_answer": "television viewers were alienated by fierce fighting outside the convention hall between anti-war demonstrators and Chicago police.",
        "distractor1": "it resulted in the choice of Hubert Humphrey as the Democratic presidential candidate.",
        "distractor2": "a majority of the delegates left before the convention adjourned.",
        "distractor3": "sentiment among the delegates was strongly in favor of the renomination of Lyndon Johnson."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Immigration and Nationality Act of 1965?:",
        "correct_answer": "abolished the old quota system.",
        "distractor1": "resulted in a higher percentage of foreign-born persons in the American population in 1980 than in 1910.",
        "distractor2": "significantly reduced the annual rate of immigration.",
        "distractor3": "discriminated against Asians and Latin Americans, especially Mexicans."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Civil Rights Act of 1964 accomplished all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "outlawing literacy tests used to prevent citizens from voting.",
        "distractor1": "barring racial discrimination in public hotels.",
        "distractor2": "authorizing the attorney general to bring suit to desegregate the public schools.",
        "distractor3": "outlawing discriminatory employment practices.",
        "distractor4": "barring racial discrimination in restaurants."
    },
    {
        "question": "Belief in the Domino Theory would most likely lead a person to support?:",
        "correct_answer": "American intervention in the war in Vietnam to prevent a Vietcong victory.",
        "distractor1": "federal intervention in the South to protect freedom riders and other civil rights activists.",
        "distractor2": "a test ban treaty with the Soviets against further atmospheric and ocean firing of nuclear weapons.",
        "distractor3": "appointment of more conservative justices to the Supreme Court to prevent it from falling completely under the influence of Warren liberals."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following best explains why President Johnson was able to enact a sweeping program of reform legislation in 1965",
        "correct_answer": "his landslide election victory had given the Democrats large majorities in Congress.",
        "distractor1": "his proposals received overwhelming support from the public.",
        "distractor2": "the congressional Republicans decided to vote for his program.",
        "distractor3": "he was able to use the patriotic spirit engendered by the Vietnam War to win support for his program."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following did turn-of-the-century American artists tend to make the subject of most of their paintings?:",
        "correct_answer": "realistic urban scenes.",
        "distractor1": "romanticized images of the American frontier.",
        "distractor2": "realistic portrayals of rural family life.",
        "distractor3": "rapidly disappearing pristine natural landscapes.",
        "distractor4": "abstract images."
    },
    {
        "question": "The major point of difference between the two black leaders  ",
        "correct_answer": "the need for immediate equality for blacks and whites.",
        "distractor1": "the need for education.",
        "distractor2": "the importance of better race relations.",
        "distractor3": "the significance of independence for Africa.",
        "distractor4": "using white institutions to help the blacks."
    },
    {
        "question": "Edward Bellamy and Henry George shared the belief that?:",
        "correct_answer": "the nation's material progress had not been accompanied by social justice.",
        "distractor1": "the disadvantages of the competitive system outweighed its advantages.",
        "distractor2": "the clue to real reform lay in the tax structure.",
        "distractor3": "progress accompanied the poverty engendered by private land ownership.",
        "distractor4": "the evils of their day were essentially incurable."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court decision in the case of  Plessy v. Ferguson  upheld which of the following principles?:",
        "correct_answer": " Separate but equal. ",
        "distractor1": " Clear and present danger. ",
        "distractor2": " One man, one vote. ",
        "distractor3": " With all deliberate speed. ",
        "distractor4": " Without redeeming social value. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The combination of European musical influences with African musical influences dame together in 1890s New Orleans to form a",
        "correct_answer": "jazz.",
        "distractor1": "gospel.",
        "distractor2": "folk.",
        "distractor3": "country.",
        "distractor4": "blues."
    },
    {
        "question": "Marcus Garvey, leader of the Universal Negro Improvement Association, argued for?:",
        "correct_answer": "a return to Africa.",
        "distractor1": "equal rights.",
        "distractor2": "racial desegregation.",
        "distractor3": "violence in the cities.",
        "distractor4": "more representation in Congress for Washington, D. C."
    },
    {
        "question": "Both Social Darwinism and classical economics agree that?:",
        "correct_answer": "free competition promotes human progress.",
        "distractor1": "humans are descended from lower animals.",
        "distractor2": "the government should ease the lot of the poor.",
        "distractor3": "government ownership of the majority of the means of production is desirable."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the early 1900s, the term  yellow journalism  referred to?:",
        "correct_answer": "a sensational, often lurid style of reporting of the news.",
        "distractor1": "anti-Asian editorials and articles.",
        "distractor2": "an expression of opinion, not a reporting of the news.",
        "distractor3": "a reporting of news which reflected the political slant of the city machines and boss rule."
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following included new outlets for selling consumer goods at the end of the 19c EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "the outlying shopping mall, for middle class commuters living at the end of the streetcar lines.",
        "distractor1": "the mail order catalog, for rural residents.",
        "distractor2": "the chain store, for the working class.",
        "distractor3": "the downtown department store, for city dwellers."
    },
    {
        "question": "D. W. Griffith's early motion picture,  The Birth of a Nation ?:",
        "correct_answer": "furthered racial prejudice because of the way it depicted blacks.",
        "distractor1": "was an attempt to further the prohibition movement.",
        "distractor2": "depicted the important role of women in the shaping of the republic.",
        "distractor3": "was strongly anti-German in content."
    },
    {
        "question": "In a country hungry for news, American newspapers at the end of the 19c?:",
        "correct_answer": "became sensationalist.",
        "distractor1": "printed hard-hitting editorials.",
        "distractor2": "repudiated the tactics of Joseph Pulitzer and William Randolph Hearst.",
        "distractor3": "came to rely less on syndicated material."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Chautauqua movement was?:",
        "correct_answer": "an educational movement utilizing lectures and sermons.",
        "distractor1": "a political movement advocating better wages and hours for workers.",
        "distractor2": "an artistic movement which emphasized abstract forms.",
        "distractor3": "a religious movement promoting Protestant missions.",
        "distractor4": "a philosophical movement that defined truth in terms of results."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following became a major exponent of the architectural principle  form follows function ?:",
        "correct_answer": "Frank Lloyd Wright.",
        "distractor1": "Thomas Eakins.",
        "distractor2": "August Saint-Gaudens.",
        "distractor3": "Winslow Homer.",
        "distractor4": "Mary Cassatt."
    },
    {
        "question": "In  Plessy v. Ferguson , the Supreme Court argued that?:",
        "correct_answer": "states could pass laws separating people on the basis of race as long as equal facilities was provided.",
        "distractor1": "segregation on the basis of race was unconstitutional.",
        "distractor2": "the Fourteenth Amendment outlawed practices that emphasized racial distinctions.",
        "distractor3": "separate but equal laws would create separate but unequal facilities."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following groups, organized in the 1880s, reflected anti-Catholic and anti-immigrant sentiments?:",
        "correct_answer": "the American Protective Association.",
        "distractor1": "the Liberty Party.",
        "distractor2": "the Knights of Labor.",
        "distractor3": "the National Civic Federation.",
        "distractor4": "the Free Soilers."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was among the objectives of Booker T. Washington?:",
        "correct_answer": "to encourage Blacks to work hard, acquire property, and prove they were worthy of their rights.",
        "distractor1": "to keep up a constant agitation of questions of racial equality.",
        "distractor2": "to encourage Blacks to be more militant in demanding their rights.",
        "distractor3": "to urge blacks not to accept separate but equal facilities.",
        "distractor4": "to form an organization to advance the rights of Blacks."
    },
    {
        "question": "John Dewey was associated with?:",
        "correct_answer": "progressive education.",
        "distractor1": "the establishment of the junior high school.",
        "distractor2": "campaigning for child labor laws.",
        "distractor3": "the  back-to-basics  movement.",
        "distractor4": "the establishment of tax-supported public schools."
    },
    {
        "question": "She was the Afro-American woman, born in slavery and later to become the respected editor of a newspaper, who fought hard",
        "correct_answer": "Ida B. Wells.",
        "distractor1": "Harriet Beecher Stowe.",
        "distractor2": "Harriet Tubman.",
        "distractor3": "Dorothea Dix.",
        "distractor4": "Ida Tarbell."
    },
    {
        "question": "Horatio Alger?:",
        "correct_answer": "wrote rags-to-riches storied for boys.",
        "distractor1": "used in influence in Washington to get many of the federal government's large steel orders for Andrew Carnegie.",
        "distractor2": "coined the term  survival of the fittest. ",
        "distractor3": "was J. Pierpont Morgan's closest friend and financial adviser."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following accurately describes a trend in American society in the 1880s and 1890s?:",
        "correct_answer": "the workplace became more tightly organized and structured.",
        "distractor1": "the middle class declined in numbers and influence.",
        "distractor2": "the percentage of women in the labor force decreased.",
        "distractor3": "most married women worked to support their families.",
        "distractor4": "the wealthy avoided signs of self-indulgence."
    },
    {
        "question": "Policies based on the idea of Manifest Destiny led to all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "the decline of the Democratic party.",
        "distractor1": "war with Mexico.",
        "distractor2": "increased sectional conflict over slavery.",
        "distractor3": "the annexation of Texas."
    },
    {
        "question": "In Congress, most of the criticism of the Mexican War came from the?:",
        "correct_answer": "Whigs.",
        "distractor1": "Democrats.",
        "distractor2": "Federalists.",
        "distractor3": "Republicans.",
        "distractor4": "Populists."
    },
    {
        "question": "The California Gold Rush resulted in all of the following developments EXCEPT the?:",
        "correct_answer": "kidnapping of thousands of Chinese to serve as workers.",
        "distractor1": "influx of over 200,000 people into the region.",
        "distractor2": "forcing of thousands of Indians to serve as indentured laborers.",
        "distractor3": "pressuring of the federal government to create an effective government for the area."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Zachary Taylor favored the?:",
        "correct_answer": "swift admission of new states from the Mexican Cession, with the issue of slavery decided by the local inhabitants.",
        "distractor1": "exclusion of slavery from all the lands acquired from Mexico.",
        "distractor2": "gradual admission of new states from the Mexican Cession, after giving southerners a chance to move into the area.",
        "distractor3": "creation of only slave states in all the lands acquired from Mexico."
    },
    {
        "question": "The application for California statehood caused turmoil in Congress because?:",
        "correct_answer": "it would upset the balance between the slave and free states in the Senate.",
        "distractor1": "it would disturb the balance in the House between those who favored slavery and those who opposed it.",
        "distractor2": "Democrats would allow no more slave states into the Union.",
        "distractor3": "Whigs would allow no more free states into the Union."
    },
    {
        "question": "Manifest Destiny was based on all of the following ideas EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "conquest of new territory would prove American military superiority.",
        "distractor1": "Anglo-Saxon racial superiority justified American absorption of inferior peoples and their lands.",
        "distractor2": "new lands would extend the domain of free government and free enterprise.",
        "distractor3": "America had a specially ordained mission in the world."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the cause of the increasingly tense relations between the Mexican government and the American residents in",
        "correct_answer": "all of these choices are correct.",
        "distractor1": "the instability of Mexican politics.",
        "distractor2": "attempts by the Mexican government to prohibit importation of slaves.",
        "distractor3": "increasing American immigration."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Senate rejected annexing Texas drawn up by Secretary of State Calhoun because?:",
        "correct_answer": "he defended annexation as a way to protect and defend slavery.",
        "distractor1": "the Texans were not yet ready to give up their independence and join the United States.",
        "distractor2": "the British threatened to break off diplomatic relations if the United States took the territory without compensating them.",
        "distractor3": "Mexico threatened to declare war if the United States stole its province."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Pre-Emption Action of 1841?:",
        "correct_answer": "legalized settlement on federal land prior to its being surveyed.",
        "distractor1": "forced squatters to buy at public auction the land they lived on.",
        "distractor2": "authorized free land grants for homesteaders who improved unsettled federal land.",
        "distractor3": "provided 160 acres of land to veterans of the Mexican War."
    },
    {
        "question": " Ecological Imperialism  can best be described as?:",
        "correct_answer": "the aggressive exploitation of the West's bounty.",
        "distractor1": "the efforts of white settlers to take land from Native Americans.",
        "distractor2": "a desire for the United States to acquire California.",
        "distractor3": "none of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "Advocates of Manifest Destiny claimed the motive for territorial expansion was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "extend American liberty to new territories.",
        "distractor1": "achieve a political balance between North and South.",
        "distractor2": "secure new resources and markets for the United States.",
        "distractor3": "ensure that no foreign powers gained territory in North America."
    },
    {
        "question": "The main issue in James K. Polk's 1844 presidential campaign was his commitment to?:",
        "correct_answer": "territorial expansion of the United States.",
        "distractor1": "increase the tariff.",
        "distractor2": "reducing the cost of western land.",
        "distractor3": "rechartering the Bank of the United States."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Ostend Manifesto, American diplomats called for American?:",
        "correct_answer": "annexation of Cuba by force, if necessary.",
        "distractor1": "support of the Hungarian Revolution against Austria.",
        "distractor2": "diplomatic relations and trade with Japan.",
        "distractor3": "annexation of the kingdom of Hawaii."
    },
    {
        "question": "The fate of the Donner party best illustrates?:",
        "correct_answer": "the hazards faced by pioneers traveling west on the Overland Trail.",
        "distractor1": "the lack of appeal of abolitionism to the majority of immigrants.",
        "distractor2": "the widespread lack of interest among Americans in Henry Clay's American System by the 1840s.",
        "distractor3": "the vicious attacks on Catholics and immigrants that took place in the 1830s and 1840s."
    },
    {
        "question": "Opponents of the war with Mexico included?:",
        "correct_answer": "New England abolitionists.",
        "distractor1": "a majority of the U. S. Congress.",
        "distractor2": "pro-slavery leaders of the South.",
        "distractor3": "residents of Texas and California."
    },
    {
        "question": "One reason for the Anglo-Texan rebellion against Mexican rule was that?:",
        "correct_answer": "the Anglo-Texans wanted to break away from a government that had grown too authoritarian.",
        "distractor1": "the Mexicans opposed slavery.",
        "distractor2": "the Mexican government refused to allow the  Old Three Hundred  to purchase land.",
        "distractor3": "the Anglo-Texans objected to the Mexican government's execution of Stephen Austin.",
        "distractor4": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the Treaty of Guadalupe-Hidalgo, the United States?:",
        "correct_answer": "gained California and New Mexico.",
        "distractor1": "forfeited all claims above the 54o 40' line.",
        "distractor2": "received $15 million from Mexico.",
        "distractor3": "prohibited slavery in Texas."
    },
    {
        "question": "On the question of Oregon?:",
        "correct_answer": "all of these choices are correct.",
        "distractor1": "Polk privately favored compromise with the British.",
        "distractor2": "England did not think the issue worth a war.",
        "distractor3": "most of the border was drawn at the 49th. Parallel."
    },
    {
        "question": "Had it passed, the Wilmot Proviso would have?:",
        "correct_answer": "prohibited slavery in any territory won from Mexico.",
        "distractor1": "divided Texas into five slave states.",
        "distractor2": "extended the Missouri Compromise line to the Pacific.",
        "distractor3": "given legal sanction to the doctrine of popular sovereignty."
    },
    {
        "question": "The prominent issue in national politics in the 1840s was?:",
        "correct_answer": "the westward expansion of U. S. territory.",
        "distractor1": "the abolition of slavery.",
        "distractor2": "the temperance movement.",
        "distractor3": "the creation of a new national bank.",
        "distractor4": "women's rights."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following did NOT occur during the 1760-1826 period in American history?:",
        "correct_answer": "Texas became part of the United States.",
        "distractor1": "a doctrine was formulated concerning American attitudes toward European intervention in the Western Hemisphere.",
        "distractor2": "political parties appeared in the U. S. for the first time.",
        "distractor3": "the first National Bank was established.",
        "distractor4": "two wars against the British were conducted."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these most clearly illustrates the president's power as chief executive?:",
        "correct_answer": "Washington's appointment of a cabinet.",
        "distractor1": "Monroe's policy toward Latin America.",
        "distractor2": "Jefferson's leadership of the Democratic-Republican party.",
        "distractor3": "Marshall's decision in  Marbury v. Madison ."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following resulted from the banking reforms indicated by the Great Depression?:",
        "correct_answer": "Glass-Steagall Act.",
        "distractor1": "Independent Treasury Act.",
        "distractor2": "National Bank Act.",
        "distractor3": "Second Bank of the United States.",
        "distractor4": "Federal Reserve Act."
    },
    {
        "question": "It was the scene of the last major Native American battle against the U. S. Army in 1890. It was also the site of an Indian",
        "correct_answer": "Wounded Knee.",
        "distractor1": "My Lai.",
        "distractor2": "Little Big Horn.",
        "distractor3": "Sand Creek.",
        "distractor4": "Watts."
    },
    {
        "question": "The term  New Immigration  refers to which of the following groups?:",
        "correct_answer": "immigrants from southern and eastern Europe who arrived in the United States after 1880.",
        "distractor1": "English settlers who arrive in America after the Glorious Revolution.",
        "distractor2": "European immigrants who arrived in the United States during the Irish Potato Famine.",
        "distractor3": "the internal immigration of southern blacks to northern urban areas after 1900.",
        "distractor4": "immigrants who arrived in the United States after the National Origins Act of 1924."
    },
    {
        "question": "The doctrine of Manifest Destiny was most clearly associated with which of the following wars involving the United States?:",
        "correct_answer": "Spanish-American War.",
        "distractor1": "Civil War.",
        "distractor2": "War of 1812.",
        "distractor3": "World War I.",
        "distractor4": "Vietnam War."
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the following:                     ",
        "correct_answer": "George Washington,  Farewell Address  (September, 1796).",
        "distractor1": "James Monroe, annual message to Congress (December, 1823).",
        "distractor2": "Thomas Jefferson, first inaugural address (March, 1801).",
        "distractor3": "Theodore Roosevelt, annual message to Congress (December, 1904).",
        "distractor4": "George Washington,  Proclamation of Neutrality  (April, 1793)."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a valid generalization about U. S. relationships with Latin America over the last 100 years?:",
        "correct_answer": "economic interests have generally influenced United States policy toward Latin America.",
        "distractor1": "the success of democracy in Latin America is due largely to United States intervention.",
        "distractor2": "Latin American resentment of the United States is due to Communist influences.",
        "distractor3": "the United States has gradually realized that events in Latin America have little bearing on United States security."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following groups of items are associated with corruption in government?:",
        "correct_answer": "Credit Mobilier --- Teapot Dome.",
        "distractor1": "Dollar Diplomacy --- the Mann Act.",
        "distractor2": "the Hatch Act -- the Comstock law.",
        "distractor3": " Muller v. Oregon  --- Taft-Hartley Act.",
        "distractor4": "Fair Standards Act -- the Granger laws."
    },
    {
        "question": "The largest absolute vote in American history received by a third-party candidate for president was achieved by?:",
        "correct_answer": "Perot in 1992.",
        "distractor1": "Roosevelt in 1912.",
        "distractor2": "La Follette in 1924.",
        "distractor3": "Thomas in 1932.",
        "distractor4": "Weaver in 1892."
    },
    {
        "question": "Women became the major source of employees at New England textile mills at approximately the same time that women?:",
        "correct_answer": "formed temperance and anti-slavery societies.",
        "distractor1": "won the vote.",
        "distractor2": "began to work in munitions factories.",
        "distractor3": "were victims of the Triangle Fire.",
        "distractor4": "became secretaries and typists, replacing male clerks."
    },
    {
        "question": "The foreign policies of Washington, Jefferson, and Monroe were similar in that they?:",
        "correct_answer": "sought to avoid involvement in European affairs.",
        "distractor1": "aided the French Republic.",
        "distractor2": "favored England.",
        "distractor3": "were hostile to England."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is generally considered the most ambitious reform program since the New Deal?:",
        "correct_answer": "Johnson's Great Society.",
        "distractor1": "Truman's Fair Deal.",
        "distractor2": "Kennedy's New Frontier.",
        "distractor3": "Eisenhower's domestic program.",
        "distractor4": "Nixon's New Federalism."
    },
    {
        "question": "Dollars that ranged in value from a few cents to 100 cents were simultaneously circulating in the United States until?:",
        "correct_answer": "Andrew Jackson's issued the Specie Circular.",
        "distractor1": "the Constitution of 1787, prohibiting the states from issuing bills of credit, was ratified.",
        "distractor2": "the first United States Bank was established.",
        "distractor3": "the Independent Treasury System was established.",
        "distractor4": "Congress taxed state bank notes out of existence in 1865."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following pairs of candidates NEVER opposed each other in a presidential election?:",
        "correct_answer": "Truman and Taft.",
        "distractor1": "Nixon and Kennedy.",
        "distractor2": "Ford and Carter.",
        "distractor3": "Reagan and Mondale.",
        "distractor4": "Eisenhower and Stevenson."
    },
    {
        "question": "Between what two men was there the MOST serious controversy over the conduct of a war?:",
        "correct_answer": "Abraham Lincoln --- General McClellan.",
        "distractor1": "Woodrow Wilson --- General Pershing.",
        "distractor2": "Franklin D. Roosevelt --- General Eisenhower.",
        "distractor3": "William McKinley --- Admiral Dewey.",
        "distractor4": "Theodore Roosevelt --- General Wood."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which principle of our federal government is illustrated by the following newspaper headline?:  ",
        "correct_answer": "checks and balances.",
        "distractor1": "impeachment powers.",
        "distractor2": "concurrent powers.",
        "distractor3": "federalism.",
        "distractor4": "imperialism."
    },
    {
        "question": "The following pairs link significant labor unions in American history with a brief description of how they operated in the",
        "correct_answer": "Industrial Workers of the World---&gt;tried to organize craft unions in the mining industry and favored a peaceful, cooperative approach to dealing with",
        "distractor1": "Knights of Labor---&gt;tried to organize a single union for all workers and tried to reform the economy through political campaigns.",
        "distractor2": "Congress of Industrial Organizations---&gt;tried to organize workers by industry and took a militant approach to advancing all of the workers' interests.",
        "distractor3": "American Federation of Labor---&gt;tried to organize workers by craft and concentrated on getting better wages and working conditions."
    },
    {
        "question": "The best evidence that third or minor political parties have had a significant influence on United States history is that",
        "correct_answer": "many of the proposals of third parties have been adopted by a major party and some have been passed into law.",
        "distractor1": "minor political parties have succeeded in dominating most state governments even though they could not control the federal government.",
        "distractor2": "the membership of Congress has been so divided among several political parties that Congress could take no effective action.",
        "distractor3": "a minor party was replaced one of the two major parties in the 20c ."
    },
    {
        "question": "Thomas Jefferson, Andrew Jackson, and Andrew Johnson had which of the following in common?:",
        "correct_answer": "a preference for a federal policy of  laissez-faire  toward economic growth.",
        "distractor1": "a plantation background.",
        "distractor2": "a lifelong dislike of slavery.",
        "distractor3": "a classical education.",
        "distractor4": "an extensive admiration for European culture."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Alliance for Progress in Latin America was most similar in purpose to the?:",
        "correct_answer": "Marshall Plan.",
        "distractor1": "NATO Alliance.",
        "distractor2": "Eisenhower Doctrine.",
        "distractor3": "Truman Doctrine.",
        "distractor4": "creation of the OAU."
    },
    {
        "question": "The President whose election depended upon the decision of an Electoral Commission was?:",
        "correct_answer": "Rutherford B. Hayes.",
        "distractor1": "Richard Nixon.",
        "distractor2": "Benjamin Harrison.",
        "distractor3": "Andrew Jackson.",
        "distractor4": "Grover Cleveland."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was intended to provide a more elastic currency?:",
        "correct_answer": "Federal Reserve Act.",
        "distractor1": "Independent Treasury Act.",
        "distractor2": "Second Bank of the United States.",
        "distractor3": "National Bank Act.",
        "distractor4": "Glass-Steagall Act."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which famous American woman is NOT correctly matched to her accomplishments?:",
        "correct_answer": "Frances Willard advocated better treatment of the insane before the Civil War.",
        "distractor1": "Jane Addams founded Hull House, the first settlement house in America.",
        "distractor2": "Mary Lyon, pioneering woman educator, founded Mount Holyoke College.",
        "distractor3": "Susan B. Anthony advocated women's suffrage.",
        "distractor4": "Frances Perkins was the first woman cabinet member, Secretary of Labor under FDR."
    },
    {
        "question": "Keynesian economic are commonly associated with the?:",
        "correct_answer": "New Deal era.",
        "distractor1": "election of 1896.",
        "distractor2": "Nixon administration.",
        "distractor3": "Roaring Twenties.",
        "distractor4": "Wilson administration."
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of implied powers in the Constitution was established in the case of?:",
        "correct_answer": " McCulloch v. Maryland .",
        "distractor1": " Marbury v. Madison .",
        "distractor2": " Fletcher v. Peck .",
        "distractor3": " Korematsu v. United States .",
        "distractor4": " Roe v. Wade ."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was NOT a reason given by President Franklin Roosevelt in his attempt to  pack  the",
        "correct_answer": "most Supreme Court justices were interpreting the Constitution too broadly.",
        "distractor1": "he believed he had a mandate after the 1936 election.",
        "distractor2": "he wanted to ease the work load of the Court's older members.",
        "distractor3": "most of the Supreme Court justices were conservative.",
        "distractor4": "the Court was declaring too many New Deal programs unconstitutional."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the period of the New Deal, the program of organized labor was most successful in?:",
        "correct_answer": "removing obstacles to unionization.",
        "distractor1": "unifying the labor movement.",
        "distractor2": "restoring full employment to the economy.",
        "distractor3": "securing a nationwide system of workers' compensation.",
        "distractor4": "safeguarding unions from authoritarian control."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Social Security program of 1935 provided which of the following?:",
        "correct_answer": "all of these choices are correct.",
        "distractor1": "federally administered unemployment insurance.",
        "distractor2": "old age pensions paid for by taxes on employers and workers.",
        "distractor3": "unemployment insurance administered by the federal government.",
        "distractor4": "federally administered assistance to the blind and disabled."
    },
    {
        "question": "Most of the rationale for conservative opposition to the New Deal came from the argument that New Deal programs?:",
        "correct_answer": "diminished the liberty of the individual.",
        "distractor1": "raised taxes on the rich.",
        "distractor2": "regulated the stock market.",
        "distractor3": "favored the wealthy.",
        "distractor4": "favored agriculture over big business."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Twenty-First Amendment, ratified in 1933, repealed the?:",
        "correct_answer": "prohibition on the manufacture and sale of alcoholic beverages.",
        "distractor1": "progressive income tax.",
        "distractor2": "poll tax, literacy test, and other discriminatory voting restrictions.",
        "distractor3": " quota system  of immigration limitations."
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary purpose of the Public Works Administration and the Works Progress Administration was?:",
        "correct_answer": "to provide employment through federal deficit spending.",
        "distractor1": "to replace private enterprise, which had failed so dramatically in 1929.",
        "distractor2": "to enable industries to plan production and control prices.",
        "distractor3": "to nationalize the government's control of the work force.",
        "distractor4": "to provide jobs for African Americans and other minorities."
    },
    {
        "question": "The most enduring change that occurred in United States banking during the administration of Franklin Roosevelt was",
        "correct_answer": "federal insurance of bank deposits.",
        "distractor1": "regular and repeated use of  bank holidays. ",
        "distractor2": "nationalization of the banking system.",
        "distractor3": "abolition of branch banking in the states.",
        "distractor4": "rigid exclusion of large banks from the provision of venture capital."
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1933, the purpose of the United States government in devaluing the dollar in terms of gold was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "raise domestic prices and make American goods cheaper abroad.",
        "distractor1": "establish the gold standard.",
        "distractor2": "stop excessive exports of American goods.",
        "distractor3": "lower domestic prices and make American goods more expensive abroad.",
        "distractor4": "reduce the ability of the gold-producing U. S. S. R. to exchange gold for industrial and military goods."
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to putting young men back to work, a principal purpose of the Civilian Conservation Corps was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "promote reforestation and land conservation.",
        "distractor1": "limit population growth.",
        "distractor2": "help young married couples buy homes on easy mortgage terms.",
        "distractor3": "provide an interracial living experience to promote harmony."
    },
    {
        "question": "Dr. Francis Townsend gained notoriety as a critic of the New Deal with his?:",
        "correct_answer": "$200 per month pension plan for the elderly.",
        "distractor1": "share-the-wealth program.",
        "distractor2": "National Union for Social Justice.",
        "distractor3": "running for president against Roosevelt in 1936."
    },
    {
        "question": "Until the 1930s, the Supreme Court objected to social legislation passed by the states to protect workers on the basis that",
        "correct_answer": "interfered with the workers' right of contract.",
        "distractor1": "made American business less competitive.",
        "distractor2": "interfered with the natural order of things.",
        "distractor3": "were reserved to the federal government.",
        "distractor4": "did not contribute to the health and well-being of the citizens."
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following were achieved during the New Deal EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "a balanced budget.",
        "distractor1": "renewed confidence in banks.",
        "distractor2": "a gradual improvement in farm conditions.",
        "distractor3": "a gradual acceptance of labor unions.",
        "distractor4": "a reduction in unemployment."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court declared the National Industrial Recovery Act unconstitutional because it?:",
        "correct_answer": "used an overbroad definition of interstate commerce.",
        "distractor1": "waived antitrust laws for cooperating businesses.",
        "distractor2": "granted public money to private corporations.",
        "distractor3": "applied only to corporations not partnerships and sole proprietorships."
    },
    {
        "question": "The farm policy of the New Deal was designed to?:",
        "correct_answer": "increase prices of farm products by reducing farm output.",
        "distractor1": "decrease federal involvement in agriculture.",
        "distractor2": "reduce prices of farm products to aid factory workers.",
        "distractor3": "enlarge farms by approving corporate mergers."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Wagner Act?:",
        "correct_answer": "allowed labor to organize into labor unions and to act as the workers' sole bargaining agent in the workplace.",
        "distractor1": "imposed unions on agricultural workers who disliked them.",
        "distractor2": "gave labor a minimum wage and retirement benefits.",
        "distractor3": "did more to impose safety standards than any legislation to date."
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following are TRUE about the election of 1936 EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "third-party candidates--Socialist, Communist, and a coalition candidate for Coughlinites, Townsendites, and  Share Our Wealth  advocates--siphoned off",
        "distractor1": "the Republicans recognized the popularity of New Deal policies and simply asserted that they could administer them better.",
        "distractor2": "Roosevelt beat Alf Landon in the most crushing victory since 1820.",
        "distractor3": "the Democrats increased their already top-heavy majorities in the Senate and the House of Representatives."
    },
    {
        "question": "The  Roosevelt coalition  that would allow the Democratic party to dominate politics for several decades rested on",
        "correct_answer": "the farm vote, especially in the Plains states.",
        "distractor1": "traditional solid support in the South.",
        "distractor2": "industrial workers.",
        "distractor3": "city dwellers, especially blacks and white ethnics."
    },
    {
        "question": "Huey Long's  Share Our Wealth  Society advocated?:",
        "correct_answer": "a guaranteed annual income to each family.",
        "distractor1": "government ownership and control of all banks.",
        "distractor2": "a national health insurance plan.",
        "distractor3": "federal education subsidies to all families with college-age children."
    },
    {
        "question": "The most profound and long-lasting effect of the New Deal on American politics was that?:",
        "correct_answer": "the increasing power of the president lessened the power of Congress.",
        "distractor1": "state and local governments became the main vehicles of political power.",
        "distractor2": "cultural issues became more significant to the voting public.",
        "distractor3": "the power of conservative politicians was finally broken."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Indian Reorganization Act of 1934?:",
        "correct_answer": "reversed a 50-year pattern by recognizing tribal life.",
        "distractor1": "promoted assimilation of Indians into the American mainstream.",
        "distractor2": "provided relief for the unemployed on reservations.",
        "distractor3": "centralized administration of the reservation system in a new federal agency."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements comes closest to Franklin D. Roosevelt's meaning of the New Deal?:",
        "correct_answer": "These times call for policies that will bring a decent standard of living to the forgotten people at the bottom of the economic pyramid.",
        "distractor1": "It is time for a change, that will call forth abundant capital to turn the wheels of industry and activate the channels of trade.",
        "distractor2": "Our policy calls for a full dinner pail for every worker. It can be best accomplished by a moderate protective tariff.",
        "distractor3": "The farmer has too long been aided by federal laws. We need a new deal that favors no segment of our people but assures opportunity for all.",
        "distractor4": "Capital and labor should be treated equally by government."
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to deal with the crisis in banking at the time of his inauguration, Franklin Roosevelt?:",
        "correct_answer": "declared a four-day  banking holiday  and prohibited the export of money.",
        "distractor1": "drastically curtailed government spending and cut taxes.",
        "distractor2": "urged Congress to pass legislation banning fractional reserve banking and holding bank trustees responsible for all deposits.",
        "distractor3": "announced a multi-billion dollar federal bailout package.",
        "distractor4": "announced the nationalization of all banks with over $100 million in total assets."
    },
    {
        "question": "The three original programs of Social Security included all of the following EXCEPT that to?:",
        "correct_answer": "provide job security for government employees.",
        "distractor1": "ensure against poverty in old age.",
        "distractor2": "maintain state-operated unemployment insurance programs.",
        "distractor3": "subsidize welfare programs of the states."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the years of the Great Depression and the New Deal, Blacks?:",
        "correct_answer": "benefited from having a friend in the White House, Eleanor Roosevelt, who could speak and act independently in support of black goals.",
        "distractor1": "did not continue to migrate to northern cities because there were no jobs.",
        "distractor2": "benefited from the civil rights bills passed by Congress with Franklin Roosevelt's urging.",
        "distractor3": "tended to vote for the Republican Party because the Democratic Party did not support policies beneficial to blacks.",
        "distractor4": "benefited equally with whites in the programs of the New Deal because Franklin Roosevelt refused to sanction discrimination."
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the loudest complaints of wealthy conservatives against the New Deal was that it?:",
        "correct_answer": "threatened their wealth and their privileged status and moved the country toward a welfare state.",
        "distractor1": "made it easier for minorities to take over the government.",
        "distractor2": "gave too much of their money to programs which benefited new immigrants.",
        "distractor3": "created too much power for the Supreme Court."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Committee for Industrial Organization (CIO) was established?:",
        "correct_answer": "to organize all workers in a particular industry, regardless of race, gender, or degree of skill.",
        "distractor1": "to organize skilled workers.",
        "distractor2": "by industrialists to undermine the power of labor unions.",
        "distractor3": "by President Roosevelt as one of his  alphabet agencies  to address economic problems."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which was a factor considered by the Supreme Court in its decision in  United States v. Butler  (1936)?:",
        "correct_answer": "proper exercise of the taxing power.",
        "distractor1": "violation of the Fourteenth Amendment.",
        "distractor2": "constitutionality of soil conservation practice.",
        "distractor3": "violation of Article IV, Section 2 of the United States Constitution.",
        "distractor4": "delegation of Legislative power by Congress to the Executive."
    },
    {
        "question": "The fundamental failure of the New Deal was its?:",
        "correct_answer": "inability to end unemployment.",
        "distractor1": "excessive reliance on deficit spending.",
        "distractor2": "failure to end extensive government corruption.",
        "distractor3": "overcentralization of power in the President."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which best describes the character of post office murals painted during the Depression?:",
        "correct_answer": "they showed common folk from the region doing common, traditional tasks.",
        "distractor1": "they glorified the worker, subtly criticizing big business.",
        "distractor2": "they featured patriotic symbols to inculcate loyalty to the federal government.",
        "distractor3": "they tended to idealize a better future, rather than sound themes from the past."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the New Deal, blacks became strong supporters of the Democratic party because?:",
        "correct_answer": "the New Deal relief agencies included blacks as recipients.",
        "distractor1": "most believed that Roosevelt fought aggressively for civil rights.",
        "distractor2": "Roosevelt supported legislation to make lynching a federal crime.",
        "distractor3": "Roosevelt tried to persuade Congress to ban the poll tax."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Watergate scandal grew out of the efforts of Nixon's confidants to?:",
        "correct_answer": "assure the re-election of Nixon in 1972.",
        "distractor1": "control all new appointments for the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor2": "tighten the security against leaks to reporters on the Washington Post.",
        "distractor3": "arrest the growing influence and power of Secretary of State Henry Kissinger.",
        "distractor4": "control inflation in the United States during the early 1970s."
    },
    {
        "question": "The invasion of Cambodia by U. S. and South Vietnamese forces int he spring of 1970?:",
        "correct_answer": "revived the domestic antiwar movement in the United States and led to large demonstrations.",
        "distractor1": "resulted in a crushing defeat of the U. S. forces.",
        "distractor2": "was the last major encounter of the war involving U. S. troops.",
        "distractor3": "led to Chinese intervention on the side of the North Vietnamese."
    },
    {
        "question": "Richard Nixon's approach to China was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "open to contact for the first time since 1949 by visiting China and beginning diplomatic relations short of full recognition.",
        "distractor1": "isolate the mainland government because of its support for the north in the Vietnam War.",
        "distractor2": "pressure the nationalist government of Taiwan to seek reunification with the mainland.",
        "distractor3": "try to stir Soviet-Chinese border conflict so that both nations would be preoccupied with each other and reduce tensions with the United States."
    },
    {
        "question": "The impeachment charges agreed upon by the House Judiciary Committee accused Nixon of all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "ordering the Watergate burglary.",
        "distractor1": "obstruction of justice.",
        "distractor2": "misusing the FBI and CIA.",
        "distractor3": "payment of bribes."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is generally regarded as THE major accomplishment of the Nixon administration?:",
        "correct_answer": "d tente with the Soviet Union and China.",
        "distractor1": "economic reforms.",
        "distractor2": "new social programs.",
        "distractor3": "environment regulations.",
        "distractor4": "Supreme Court appointments."
    },
    {
        "question": "The  Saturday Night Massacre ?:",
        "correct_answer": "involved the firing of Archibald Cox, special prosecutor for the Watergate case.",
        "distractor1": "resulted in the deaths of twelve Native American demonstrators.",
        "distractor2": "was the name given the policy assault on student demonstrators at Columbia University.",
        "distractor3": "resulted in the destruction of three Vietnamese villages and the killing of over 100  suspected  Vietcong."
    },
    {
        "question": "Richard M. Nixon won the election of 1968 for all of the following reasons EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "Hubert Humphrey refused to distance himself from Lyndon Johnson's Vietnam policy.",
        "distractor1": "Nixon could criticize the Democrats for involving the United States in Vietnam for four years with no end in sight.",
        "distractor2": "Nixon could attack the wasteful and failed programs of the Great Society.",
        "distractor3": "Nixon could appeal to the non-demonstrating, non-shouting, forgotten Americans."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following best describes the Nixon administration's response to the election of Salvador Allende as",
        "correct_answer": "the administration acted through the CIA to disrupt the Chilean economy and encourage Allende's overthrow.",
        "distractor1": "the administration grudgingly recognized Allende's election once it was evident that the election was valid.",
        "distractor2": "the administration extended supported to Allende in order to woo him away from Soviet influence.",
        "distractor3": "the administration pressured other Latin American nations to join in a total boycott of Chilean goods."
    },
    {
        "question": "American actions in the settlement of the Yom Kippur War of 1973 resulted in?:",
        "correct_answer": "an oil embargo against the United States by the Arab nations.",
        "distractor1": "censure of the United States by the United Nations.",
        "distractor2": "the withdrawal of Israeli troops from Jordan.",
        "distractor3": "the closing of the Suez Canal."
    },
    {
        "question": "The SALT I Agreement?:",
        "correct_answer": "limited the antiballistic missiles of the United States and the Soviet Union.",
        "distractor1": "arranged for the Soviet Union's purchase of at least $750 million in American grain over a three-year period.",
        "distractor2": "brought about the end of the OPEC oil embargo.",
        "distractor3": "called for a phased withdrawal of American missiles and troops in Europe, in exchange for a comparable Soviet withdrawal from Afghanistan."
    },
    {
        "question": "Richard Nixon tried to reverse certain political and social trends of the recent past. His efforts involved all of the",
        "correct_answer": "legislative efforts to expand federal government control over how states spent their allocations from federal revenues.",
        "distractor1": "strategies to discredit student protesters and other critics.",
        "distractor2": "diplomatic initiatives to reduce tensions with those communist regimes that the containment policy had sought to contain.",
        "distractor3": "political maneuvering to get union workers and Southerners to switch to the Republican party."
    },
    {
        "question": "George McGovern, the Democratic nominee for the presidency in 1972, alienated the traditional working-class backbone of",
        "correct_answer": "by appealing to racial minorities, feminists, and other social/political protestors.",
        "distractor1": "by advocating a cut in Social Security.",
        "distractor2": "when he advocated a continuation of the Vietnam War.",
        "distractor3": "when it was discovered that he had undergone psychiatric care."
    },
    {
        "question": "The  Pentagon Papers , published in 1971?:",
        "correct_answer": "exposed the deception that had led the United States into the Vietnam War.",
        "distractor1": "revealed President Nixon's role in the Watergate scandal.",
        "distractor2": "was the first the American public knew of the Nixon Doctrine.",
        "distractor3": "exposed President Nixon's secret bombing war of Cambodia."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Nixon Doctrine stated that the United States would?:",
        "correct_answer": "provide financial and moral support to nations facing communist subversion, but such nations would have to defend themselves.",
        "distractor1": "help to defend, by military means if necessary, the territorial integrity of any nation threatened by communism.",
        "distractor2": "use force, if necessary, to ensure that Latin American nations elected honest, pro-American governments.",
        "distractor3": "work to support human rights around the globe."
    },
    {
        "question": "Secretary of State Kissinger's shuttle diplomacy in the Middle East led to which of the following agreements?:",
        "correct_answer": "Egypt and Israel agreed to accept a United Nations peacekeeping force in the Sinai.",
        "distractor1": "Israel agreed to stop building settlements in occupied lands.",
        "distractor2": "the Arab states agreed to recognize Israel's existence as a nation.",
        "distractor3": "Israel agreed to withdraw from Jerusalem and the West Bank."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Nixon's  Vietnamization  policy sought to?:",
        "correct_answer": "build up South Vietnamese forces to replace American troops.",
        "distractor1": "get the Soviet Union to stop shipping military supplies to North Vietnam.",
        "distractor2": "rely on the United Nations to end the Vietnam War through diplomacy.",
        "distractor3": "build support for the South Vietnamese government through a land redistribution program."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was especially reprehensible about the Watergate affair was that?:",
        "correct_answer": "it represented subversive action against the American political process.",
        "distractor1": "the President was the known leader of a burglary ring.",
        "distractor2": "Democrats exaggerated the scandal and caused a lack of confidence in the political system.",
        "distractor3": "it was justified by radicals in the Democratic party."
    },
    {
        "question": "The most appropriate statement characterizing the Nixon administration's role in domestic affairs is that?:",
        "correct_answer": "it sustained many of the reforms of the 1960s and advanced government's role in some other areas.",
        "distractor1": "it reversed the course of most of the Great Society reforms.",
        "distractor2": "it outperformed the Great Society in only area--eliminating poverty.",
        "distractor3": "it talked a conservative line but played a more liberal role than Kennedy or Johnson did."
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary purpose of the Nixon-Kissinger policy of d tente was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "check Soviet expansion and limit the Soviet arms build-up.",
        "distractor1": "enlarge the influence of the United Nations.",
        "distractor2": "guarantee the self-determination of the Third World.",
        "distractor3": "elevate the international stature of America's European allies."
    },
    {
        "question": "The War Powers Act of 1973 was passed mainly in response to concern that presidents Johnson and Nixon?:",
        "correct_answer": "could involve the nation's armed forces in combat without congressional approval.",
        "distractor1": "he made treaties without informing the Senate.",
        "distractor2": "Congress is not effective in dealing with a constitutional crisis.",
        "distractor3": "the Supreme Court is reluctant to make decisions about matters involving the presidency."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Watergate scandal led to Richard Nixon's downfall primarily because?:",
        "correct_answer": "of his role in directing the cover-up of the Watergate Affair.",
        "distractor1": "of his role in planning and coordinating the Watergate break-in and other illegal campaign activity.",
        "distractor2": "the press, the Democrats, and some liberal Republicans united to rid themselves of Nixon and his conservative philosophy.",
        "distractor3": "he was already so unpopular because of his Vietnam War policies that virtually anything he did wrong would have been used as an excuse to remove him from",
        "distractor4": "of his involvement with organized crime in carrying out political  dirty tricks  against his Democratic opponent, George McGovern."
    },
    {
        "question": "The decision of the Supreme Court in the  New York Times Company v. United States  (1971), the  Pentagon Papers ",
        "correct_answer": "the Court ruled that the First Amendment prevented prior restraint of publication, even against a charge that such publication would jeopardize national",
        "distractor1": "it involved important officials in the U. S. government.",
        "distractor2": "it was widely reported in newspapers throughout the country.",
        "distractor3": "the government's attorneys lost the case in a 6 to 3 decision."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following did NOT contribute to the problems of farmers in the late 19c?:",
        "correct_answer": "lack of available land.",
        "distractor1": "high interest rates.",
        "distractor2": "overpopulation.",
        "distractor3": "high shipping costs.",
        "distractor4": "deflation."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the 1860s and 1870s, the Grangers carried out all of the following activities EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "they forged a political coalition with organized labor.",
        "distractor1": "they established cooperatives.",
        "distractor2": "they supported political candidates sympathetic to the farmers' needs.",
        "distractor3": "they disseminated information about new scientific agricultural techniques."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement BEST describes many of the reforms proposed by the Populist Party?:",
        "correct_answer": "they were won through the efforts of other political parties at a later time.",
        "distractor1": "they were just campaign promises.",
        "distractor2": "they were undesirable in a democratic country.",
        "distractor3": "they disappeared from public interest."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was a major reason that farmers did NOT settle the Great Plains before 1860?:",
        "correct_answer": "they did not know how to cope with the absence of water and trees.",
        "distractor1": "they had enough good land in the East.",
        "distractor2": "they had no way to stop cattle ranchers from using the Great Plains for grazing.",
        "distractor3": "farm families were too small to provide enough labor to plant and harvest crops on the plains."
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the primary beliefs of the Farmers' Alliances was that?:",
        "correct_answer": "too much power was in the hands of a few corporations and financial institutions.",
        "distractor1": "individual competition was the most efficient means of determining fair farm prices.",
        "distractor2": "the ratio of gold to silver should be 18 to 1.",
        "distractor3": "the railroads should be under state, not federal control."
    },
    {
        "question": "Although historians disagree as to their interpretations of Populism, the movement was significant because?:",
        "correct_answer": "it was one of the few third-party movements to gain national influence.",
        "distractor1": "it led to successful radical movements in the early 1900s.",
        "distractor2": "the activists of the party were responsible for the success of the first McKinley administration.",
        "distractor3": "it helped to elect a president at the peak of its power."
    },
    {
        "question": "The basic economic motivation behind the coinage of silver was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "ease the burden of debtors.",
        "distractor1": "encourage reduced production of agricultural products.",
        "distractor2": "increase foreign trade.",
        "distractor3": "encourage increased production of agricultural products."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the late 19c, what was the relationship between the southern agrarian protest movement and southern attitudes toward",
        "correct_answer": "all of these choices are correct.",
        "distractor1": "some populists wanted to build an interracial movement and tried to defend the rights of blacks.",
        "distractor2": "most southern populists were antiblack.",
        "distractor3": "the white elite tried to inflame agrarian racism and stimulate urban black sentiment against agrarian radicalism."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Populists' subtreasury plan called for?:",
        "correct_answer": "the government to advance credit to farmers for crops stored in government storehouses.",
        "distractor1": "a new banking system in America.",
        "distractor2": "a new system of credit for all American workers.",
        "distractor3": "the government to eliminate the crop lien system in the South."
    },
    {
        "question": "After the Granger laws ran into legal problems and were overturned in the case of  Wabash v. Illinois , Congress",
        "correct_answer": "Interstate Commerce Act.",
        "distractor1": "Sherman Antitrust Act.",
        "distractor2": "graduated income tax.",
        "distractor3": "Atlanta Compromise.",
        "distractor4": "Homestead Act."
    },
    {
        "question": "Progressives supported greater participation in the political process through all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "city manager government.",
        "distractor1": "primary elections.",
        "distractor2": "recall.",
        "distractor3": "initiative and referendum.",
        "distractor4": "direct election of senators."
    },
    {
        "question": "John Dewey's theories on  progressive education  advocated all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "knowledge of the facts was the purpose of education.",
        "distractor1": "rote memorization was an ineffective way of earning.",
        "distractor2": "school's developing a student's social outlook.",
        "distractor3": "children best learn by doing.",
        "distractor4": "students should be encouraged to work on group projects."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the federal government's attitude toward trusts during most of the Progressive period?:",
        "correct_answer": "good trusts should be allowed to exist subject to proper governmental regulations.",
        "distractor1": "the government should not interfere with the organization of trusts or their operation.",
        "distractor2": "the wealth that trusts created justified full government support.",
        "distractor3": "all trusts were bad because they stifled competition.",
        "distractor4": "government should support large trusts and business consolidations."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Hepburn Act strengthened the authority of the Interstate Commerce Commission by?:",
        "correct_answer": "giving it the power to set maximum rates that railroads could charge.",
        "distractor1": "declaring that rate discrimination and rebates were legal.",
        "distractor2": "compelling railroads to file tax reports.",
        "distractor3": "declaring the use of Pinkerton detectives by the railroads null and void.",
        "distractor4": "authorizing it to issue injunctions against the railroads."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the presidential election of 1912 is TRUE?:",
        "correct_answer": "it weakened the progressive wing of the Republican party for many years.",
        "distractor1": "it established the Socialist party as the major third party in American politics for many years.",
        "distractor2": "it cracked the Solid South.",
        "distractor3": "it made the Democratic party dominant in Northern cities.",
        "distractor4": "it marked the shift of the black vote from the Republican to the Democratic party."
    },
    {
        "question": "Woodrow Wilson's  New Freedom  and Theodore Roosevelt's  New Nationalism  were similar in that",
        "correct_answer": "expanded the government's role in regulating businesses and business monopolies.",
        "distractor1": "expanded the rights of states to regulate business operations within state borders.",
        "distractor2": "removed restrictions on the rights of women and minorities.",
        "distractor3": "removed restrictions on the rights of unions to organize within the workplace.",
        "distractor4": "expanded the notion of individualism inherent in their laissez-faire economic policies."
    },
    {
        "question": "In general, the women's club movement?:",
        "correct_answer": "played an important role in winning passage of state laws regulating conditions of housing and the workplace.",
        "distractor1": "confined its activities to social and cultural activities.",
        "distractor2": "seldom adopted positions on controversial public issues.",
        "distractor3": "overtly challenged the prevailing assumptions about the proper role of women in society."
    },
    {
        "question": "The anti-immigration movement that emerged during the progressive period was fueled by all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "a completely open immigration policy was contrary to American tradition.",
        "distractor1": "immigrants were creating unmanageable urban problems.",
        "distractor2": "unrestricted immigration was a threat to the nation's racial purity.",
        "distractor3": "the new immigrants were much less assimilable than were earlier immigrants."
    },
    {
        "question": "Lincoln Steffens, in his series of articles entitled  The Shame of the Cities ?:",
        "correct_answer": "unmasked the corrupt alliance between big business and municipal government.",
        "distractor1": "attacked the United States Senate.",
        "distractor2": "exposed the deplorable conditions of blacks in urban areas.",
        "distractor3": "laid bare the practices of the stock market."
    },
    {
        "question": "When Woodrow Wilson became president in 1912, the most serious shortcoming in the country's financial structure was that the?:",
        "correct_answer": "currency was inelastic.",
        "distractor1": "large banks were scattered too widely around the country.",
        "distractor2": "Bank of the United States had been greatly weakened.",
        "distractor3": "banking system had been overregulated by the federal government."
    },
    {
        "question": "Ratification of the Seventeenth Amendment is considered a progressive victory because by?:",
        "correct_answer": "providing for the direct election of United States senators, it took their election out of the hands of state legislatures.",
        "distractor1": "establishing a regulatory commission for all industry, it furthered the concept of a planned economy.",
        "distractor2": "providing for the income tax, it had the effect of redistributing wealth in the United States.",
        "distractor3": "making the manufacture and sale of alcoholic beverages illegal, it furthered the progressive goal of moral purity."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Federal Reserve System has improved on the earlier national banking system by providing for?:",
        "correct_answer": "greater elasticity of credit and currency.",
        "distractor1": "a national bank under the direct control of the federal government.",
        "distractor2": "complete control over all United States banks.",
        "distractor3": "a system for control of consumer credit.",
        "distractor4": "insurance of bank deposits."
    },
    {
        "question": "Theodore Roosevelt's chief criticism of the muckrakers was that they?:",
        "correct_answer": "were more adept at exposing abuses than at constructive efforts.",
        "distractor1": "influenced only a limited number of voters.",
        "distractor2": "supplied the Democrats with good political issues.",
        "distractor3": "undermined reforms already in progress.",
        "distractor4": "lacked sufficient documentation for many of their writings."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Progressive movement's attitude toward monopoly was one of?:",
        "correct_answer": "advocating the end of corporate privileges in government and the regulation or destruction of trusts.",
        "distractor1": "advocating a cooperative economy.",
        "distractor2": "encouraging the progressive development of trusts which had a social conscience.",
        "distractor3": "ignoring the subject as of minor importance in comparison with dishonest politics and corrupt morals.",
        "distractor4": "desiring the institution of profit-sharing."
    },
    {
        "question": "The main purpose of initiative, referendum, and recall was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "enlarge citizens' control over state and local governments.",
        "distractor1": "reduce federal control over local government.",
        "distractor2": "stimulate economic growth.",
        "distractor3": "restore the balance between state and federal power."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Clayton Anti-Trust Act?:",
        "correct_answer": "explicitly legalized strikes and peaceful picketing.",
        "distractor1": "held that trade unions fell under the anti-monopoly restraints of the Sherman Act.",
        "distractor2": "regarded labor as an article of commerce.",
        "distractor3": "helped Congress to control interstate commerce."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Nineteenth Amendment granting women the right to vote was embraced by many Progressives because?:",
        "correct_answer": "the higher moral character of women would help clean up politics.",
        "distractor1": "a large minority of American voters now favored it.",
        "distractor2": "the women agitating for it moderated the radicalism of their campaign.",
        "distractor3": "it could offset growing jingoism and militarism, especially once World War I began."
    },
    {
        "question": "According to John Dewey, schools should?:",
        "correct_answer": "become the instruments of reform by embracing the new ethic of social interdependence.",
        "distractor1": "guard against experimentalism and preserve the role of the teacher as the unquestioned authority.",
        "distractor2": "teach self-reliance, hard work, and honesty.",
        "distractor3": "serve as the handmaidens of industry by teaching subjects that were most needed by the business world."
    },
    {
        "question": "What happened to bring about the passage in 1906 of the Pure Food and Drug Act and the Meat Inspection Act?:",
        "correct_answer": "all of these choices are correct.",
        "distractor1": "the revelation that Colden's Liquid Beef Tonic contained 26.5% alcohol.",
        "distractor2": "the disgusting descriptions found in  The Jungle .",
        "distractor3": "proregulation pressure from the larger food-processing, meatpacking, and medicinal companies."
    },
    {
        "question": "Jane Addams opened a settlement house for which of the following two reasons?:",
        "correct_answer": "to help her neighbors and to create meaningful work opportunities for educated women.",
        "distractor1": "to earn rent money and to fight the political bosses.",
        "distractor2": "to create a home base for launching a political career and to fight neighborhood crime.",
        "distractor3": "to clean up Halsted Street and to become the first female war boss."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Niagara Movement, founded in 1905 by W. E. B. Du Bois, fought for?:",
        "correct_answer": "universal suffrage and civil rights for African Americans.",
        "distractor1": "cheaper electricity in the St. Lawrence-upper New York region.",
        "distractor2": "greater public involvement in the electricity monopoly.",
        "distractor3": "woman suffrage."
    },
    {
        "question": "As a result of the increasing demands for reform in medicine by the progressives, the medical profession?:",
        "correct_answer": "established the American Medical Association, to represent the field as a whole.",
        "distractor1": "fought against the passage of state and local laws requiring the licensing of all physicians.",
        "distractor2": "opened the field to all practitioners in the field.",
        "distractor3": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an accurate contrast between the Populists and politically active Progressives?:",
        "correct_answer": "Populist supporters were largely Southern or Western agrarians, Progressive supporters were largely middle class urban professionals.",
        "distractor1": "the Populists sought to limit the power of government, the Progressives expanded the power of government to address social needs.",
        "distractor2": "the Populists made some political gains at the state level, but failed in national politics; the Progressives, ignoring state politics, enjoyed success at the",
        "distractor3": "the Populist Party never won a presidential election, between 1900 and 1920, the Progressive Party never lost one."
    },
    {
        "question": "Most urban working people opposed the actions of the progressives against the party machines because?:",
        "correct_answer": "the machines were a source of jobs and services.",
        "distractor1": "the bosses tended to be of the same nationality as the progressives.",
        "distractor2": "they felt that the progressives were meddling, middle-class snobs who did not understand their lives.",
        "distractor3": "they had been threatened with violence by the bosses if they supported the progressives."
    },
    {
        "question": "The income tax amendment to the Constitution adopted in 1913?:",
        "correct_answer": "recovered revenue lost by reducing the tariff.",
        "distractor1": "applied the same tax rate to all incomes.",
        "distractor2": "redistributed wealth from the rich to the poor.",
        "distractor3": "paid for the social-welfare programs of the Wilson administration.",
        "distractor4": "was repealed at the beginning of the Depression."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following does NOT correctly describe the Progressives?:",
        "correct_answer": "they represented farmers and the working class.",
        "distractor1": "they favored government regulation of business on behalf of the public interest.",
        "distractor2": "they were concerned with the social and economic conditions of the city.",
        "distractor3": "they advocated a more orderly and efficient society.",
        "distractor4": "they called for a stronger state and federal government."
    },
    {
        "question": "Jacob Coxey's 1894 march on Washington, D. C. called for?:",
        "correct_answer": "an increase in the supply of paper money.",
        "distractor1": "tougher immigration restrictions.",
        "distractor2": "a government takeover of the railroads.",
        "distractor3": "recognition of the legitimacy of labor unions.",
        "distractor4": "generosity in granting pensions to Civil War veterans."
    },
    {
        "question": "The advocates of women's suffrage significantly increased their general public support during the Progressive Era when they",
        "correct_answer": "enhance the likelihood of the successful enactment of other progressive reform causes.",
        "distractor1": "lead to full social and economic power for women within a generation.",
        "distractor2": "increase political power and office-holding opportunities available to women.",
        "distractor3": "bring more women into the industrial work force, thereby countering recession."
    },
    {
        "question": "With respect to government-controlled public lands, Roosevelt generally favored?:",
        "correct_answer": "conservation with carefully managed development.",
        "distractor1": "absolute preservation in their natural states.",
        "distractor2": "leasing for unrestricted private exploitation.",
        "distractor3": "outright sale to private developers who could use the land in any way they wished."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement describes both the  Square Deal  and the  New Freedom ?:",
        "correct_answer": "they were the legislative programs of reforming presidents.",
        "distractor1": "they stressed the importance of conservation.",
        "distractor2": "they were chiefly supported by Republicans.",
        "distractor3": "they included only political and legal reforms, not economic reforms."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements best summarizes Theodore Roosevelt's position on trusts?:",
        "correct_answer": "good trusts should be tolerated while bad trusts are prevented from manipulating markets.",
        "distractor1": "trusts are an economic evil and should be destroyed in every case.",
        "distractor2": "only trusts in the railroad and oil industries are acceptable.",
        "distractor3": "only trusts in the meatpacking industry should be broken up.",
        "distractor4": "anything that stands in t he way of complete and unrestricted economic competition is evil and should be removed."
    },
    {
        "question": "The progressive-inspired city-manager system of government?:",
        "correct_answer": "was designed to remove politics from municipal administration.",
        "distractor1": "brought democracy to urban dwellers.",
        "distractor2": "was developed in Wisconsin.",
        "distractor3": "made giant strides under the leadership of Hiram Jackson."
    },
    {
        "question": "Woodrow Wilson's New Freedom?:",
        "correct_answer": "favored small enterprise and entrepreneurship.",
        "distractor1": "advocated social-welfare programs.",
        "distractor2": "opposed fragmentation of big industrial combines.",
        "distractor3": "supported minimum-wage laws."
    },
    {
        "question": "The ideology of progressivism, insofar as it had one, generally?:",
        "correct_answer": "mixed a liberal concern for the poor with a conservative wish to control social disorder.",
        "distractor1": "called for redistribution of incomes from wealthy to poor and a socialist approach to government.",
        "distractor2": "was rooted in firm and fixed standards of morality and truth.",
        "distractor3": "stressed trying to meet the special needs of each identifiable private interest."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was, in large part, a consequence of Upton Sinclair's 1906 book,  The Jungle ?:",
        "correct_answer": "President Theodore Roosevelt supported passage of the Meat Inspection Act.",
        "distractor1": "drug manufacturers agreed to stop selling impure merchandise.",
        "distractor2": "railroad rate-making was taken out of the hands of the railroad industry and put into the hands of the ICC.",
        "distractor3": "President Roosevelt supported legislation to guarantee the rights of workers to bargain collectively."
    },
    {
        "question": " Reaganomics  was based upon which of the following theories?:",
        "correct_answer": "cutting taxes would stimulate investment which would in turn increase employment and tax revenue.",
        "distractor1": "government must  prime  the economic pump by large expenditures in order to produce prosperity.",
        "distractor2": "the United States was an undertaxed country where taxes must be increased substantially and the money spent on public needs.",
        "distractor3": "the government must institute wage and price controls in order to control inflation.",
        "distractor4": "the government must turn to tight controls on the money supply in order to cut inflation."
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following contributed to President Ronald Reagan's election victory in 1980 EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "President Carter's Vietnam policy.",
        "distractor1": "the Iranian hostage crisis.",
        "distractor2": "the state of the domestic economy.",
        "distractor3": "the Carter policy toward Afghanistan.",
        "distractor4": "Reagan's personal charisma."
    },
    {
        "question": "The  supply-side  economic theory that President Reagan sought to implement early in his administration called for?:",
        "correct_answer": "cutting taxes to encourage new investment.",
        "distractor1": "increasing government spending to stimulate consumption.",
        "distractor2": "maintaining high interest rates to control inflation.",
        "distractor3": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the national elections of 1984, the Democrats made electoral history by, for the first time, nominating a vice",
        "correct_answer": "female.",
        "distractor1": "Jewish.",
        "distractor2": "Hispanic.",
        "distractor3": "Afro-American.",
        "distractor4": "Native American."
    },
    {
        "question": "The so-called Iran Contra Scandal involved the Reagan administration in?:",
        "correct_answer": "selling weapons to the anti-American government in Iran and using the profit to aid the pro-American Contras in Nicaragua.",
        "distractor1": "a secret CIA effort to arm Iranian exiles and stage an invasion.",
        "distractor2": "planting misleading intelligence information with the governments of Iran and Iraq in order to stir up a war between them.",
        "distractor3": "a scheme to divert frozen Iranian assets into the campaign coffers of a republican senate candidate in Virginia."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Reagan doctrine of American activism in the Third World was most particularly exercised in?:",
        "correct_answer": "Grenada and Nicaragua.",
        "distractor1": "Iran and Saudi Arabia.",
        "distractor2": "El Salvador and Chile.",
        "distractor3": "the Philippines and South Africa.",
        "distractor4": "Venezuela and the Dominican Republic."
    },
    {
        "question": "The costly and highly criticized Reagan program known as the Strategic Defense Initiative ( Star Wars ) proposed",
        "correct_answer": "create a defensive missile system in space to shield the U. S. from any foreign missile attack.",
        "distractor1": "arm the Contras in order to bring down the Sandinista regime.",
        "distractor2": "place Marines in the Middle East in order to defend access to Middle East oil.",
        "distractor3": "move beyond limiting the growth of nuclear weapons to negotiating actual reductions."
    },
    {
        "question": "Ronald Reagan's political objectives as president included all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "the expansion of the welfare state.",
        "distractor1": "an increase in military spending.",
        "distractor2": "a balanced budget.",
        "distractor3": "the appointment of a conservative judiciary."
    },
    {
        "question": "Reagan and Gorbachev met three times in three years, with discussions focusing on?:",
        "correct_answer": "arms reduction.",
        "distractor1": "environmental issues.",
        "distractor2": "the sharing of computer technology.",
        "distractor3": "space program collaborations.",
        "distractor4": "arts and cultural exchanges."
    },
    {
        "question": "After arriving in Lebanon in 1982 as a peacekeeping force, American troops?:",
        "correct_answer": "became involved in the hostilities between warring Lebanese factions.",
        "distractor1": "allied with the Israeli troops remaining in Lebanon.",
        "distractor2": "brought peace and stability to the war-ravaged country.",
        "distractor3": "consistently maintained a strictly neutral position in the Lebanese civil war."
    },
    {
        "question": "In his first year in office, President Reagan tackled the issue of inflation by?:",
        "correct_answer": "encouraging Congress to pass a new tax law reducing income taxes.",
        "distractor1": "establishing a Department of Energy.",
        "distractor2": "stopping U. S. military and economic aid to Taiwan.",
        "distractor3": "repealing the minimum wage law.",
        "distractor4": "increasing military support for terrorist activities."
    },
    {
        "question": "During his second term, President Reagan faced his gravest foreign policy challenge from Congress over his support for?:",
        "correct_answer": "the Contras.",
        "distractor1": "Iraq.",
        "distractor2": "the Sandinistas.",
        "distractor3": "Margaret Thatcher.",
        "distractor4": "the MX missile system."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act, passed in late 1985, included what  automatic  measure designed to achieve a",
        "correct_answer": "across-the-board budget cuts.",
        "distractor1": "tax increases.",
        "distractor2": "postponement of interest payments on the national debt.",
        "distractor3": "reduction of entitlement benefits."
    },
    {
        "question": "The stunning victory of the Republican party in the 1980 election was due primarily to the fact that?:",
        "correct_answer": "the political pendulum that started its swing toward conservatism a decade earlier was still moving to the right.",
        "distractor1": "many Democratic votes were siphoned off by third party candidates.",
        "distractor2": "Ronald Reagan was more effective in debating than Jimmy Carter.",
        "distractor3": "after twelve years of Democratic rule the voters were ready for a change."
    },
    {
        "question": "The conservative movement by 1980 was supported by all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "advocates of gun control.",
        "distractor1": "Moral Majority.",
        "distractor2": "opponents of affirmative action.",
        "distractor3": "critics of  secular humanism. ",
        "distractor4": "citizens against increased taxes."
    },
    {
        "question": "The INF Treaty?:",
        "correct_answer": "eliminated intermediate-range nuclear missiles.",
        "distractor1": "was between Italy, the Netherlands, France, and the United States.",
        "distractor2": "doubled the amount of wheat sold annually to the Soviet Union.",
        "distractor3": "concerned whaling rights in the Pacific."
    },
    {
        "question": "The savings and loan crisis of the mid-1980s occurred, in part, because of?:",
        "correct_answer": "reductions in the number of federal regulators and too many S &amp; L investments in high-risk ventures.",
        "distractor1": "the lack of reform in the banking industry.",
        "distractor2": "corrupt practices on the part of government banking inspectors.",
        "distractor3": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Reagan Doctrine, the Reagan administration declared that it would?:",
        "correct_answer": "openly support anti-Communist forces fighting the Soviets or Soviet-backed governments.",
        "distractor1": "end restrictive international trade policies.",
        "distractor2": "allow all nations to determine their own political and economic future.",
        "distractor3": "respect the sovereignty of all nations."
    },
    {
        "question": "The election of 1984 demonstrated that the?:",
        "correct_answer": "New Deal coalition was in shambles.",
        "distractor1": "political power of the Sunbelt was waning.",
        "distractor2": "American electorate wanted a repeal of the New Deal.",
        "distractor3": "South was still a solidly Democratic stronghold."
    },
    {
        "question": "To weaken the Sandinista government in Nicaragua, the Reagan administration?:",
        "correct_answer": "used the CIA to initiate an anti-Sandinista campaign of sabotage and destruction.",
        "distractor1": "endorsed the Contradora peace plan backed by other Latin American nations.",
        "distractor2": "relied on peaceful persuasion to encourage the Nicaraguan people to question their government.",
        "distractor3": "secured the agreement of European allies to cut off trade with Nicaragua."
    },
    {
        "question": "What two issues lay at the heart of Reconstruction?:",
        "correct_answer": "the future of political and economic power for freed slaves, and the future of North-South economic and political relations.",
        "distractor1": "whether the federal or state government was ultimately sovereign, and whether Africa-Americans or Native Americans were the most oppressed",
        "distractor2": "which party would gain the ascendance, and how the government could regulate the economy.",
        "distractor3": "rebuilding the North's shattered economy and restoring the South's shattered society."
    },
    {
        "question": "The  grandfather clause ?:",
        "correct_answer": "denied black Americans the franchise in the South.",
        "distractor1": "resulted in the election of Rutherford B. Hayes in 1876.",
        "distractor2": "required federal troops to supervise voting in Southern elections.",
        "distractor3": "determined whether or not an ex-slave was a freedman."
    },
    {
        "question": "Under new President Andrew Johnson, presidential Reconstruction?:",
        "correct_answer": "made it possible for former high-ranking Confederates to assume positions of power in the reconstructed southern governments.",
        "distractor1": "would implement a harsher program on the South than Lincoln had called for.",
        "distractor2": "adhered substantially to the views of Congressional leaders.",
        "distractor3": "never was implemented because Congress passed its own program before Johnson's could go into effect."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Supreme Court case of  United States v. Cruikshank  (1876), the Supreme Court ruled that the Fourteenth Amendment?:",
        "correct_answer": "covered only violations of civil rights by the states, and not violations by private individuals.",
        "distractor1": "applied the Bill of Rights to all the states.",
        "distractor2": "guaranteed the vote to all Blacks.",
        "distractor3": "provided that separate but equal facilities were constitutionally permissible."
    },
    {
        "question": "The North interpreted Black Codes as?:",
        "correct_answer": "evidence that the South sought to keep freemen in an economically dependent and legally inferior status.",
        "distractor1": "evidence that the South, by granting limited rights such as allowing jury service, was slowly accommodating to an improved status for former slaves.",
        "distractor2": "a realistic solution by the South to the problems created by sudden emancipation.",
        "distractor3": "dangerous experiment by the South that could lead to social equality for blacks in the North."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was NOT a feature of Abraham Lincoln's  10 Percent Plan ?:",
        "correct_answer": "southern plantations were to be confiscated and divided among the blacks who had formerly worked there as slaves.",
        "distractor1": "state governments could be formed when at least 10% of those who had voted in 1860 had sworn allegiance to the Union and accepted emancipation.",
        "distractor2": "Confederate officials and army and naval officers needed presidential pardons before they could participate in the new governments.",
        "distractor3": "freedmen were excluded from participation because they had not been voters in 1860."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the Reconstruction, what groups was the backbone of the Republican party in the South, providing eight out of ten",
        "correct_answer": "freedmen.",
        "distractor1": "scalawags.",
        "distractor2": "carpetbaggers.",
        "distractor3": "Redeemers.",
        "distractor4": "Ku Klux Klaners."
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1867, Secretary of State Seward accomplished an enduring success in foreign relations for the Johnson administration when",
        "correct_answer": "purchased Alaska from Russia.",
        "distractor1": "commissioned the building of an all-new ironclad navy.",
        "distractor2": "recognized the independent republic of Hawaii.",
        "distractor3": "called for American aid to republican rebels in Cuba.",
        "distractor4": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the presidential election of 1868, Ulysses S. Grant?:",
        "correct_answer": "owed his victory to the votes of former slaves.",
        "distractor1": "transformed his personal popularity into a large majority in the popular vote.",
        "distractor2": "gained his victory by winning the votes of the majority of whites.",
        "distractor3": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "Americans in the post-Civil War decades who waved the bloody shirt were?:",
        "correct_answer": "Republicans reviving the memory of southern Democratic disloyalty during the Civil War.",
        "distractor1": "Republicans denouncing corruption in office.",
        "distractor2": "southern Democrats reviving the sectional spirit of the Confederacy.",
        "distractor3": "Union Army veterans claiming their pensions.",
        "distractor4": "labor supporters protesting the Haymarket riot."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Fourteenth Amendment to the Constitution was important because it?:",
        "correct_answer": "guaranteed equal protection under the law for every American citizen.",
        "distractor1": "prohibited slavery within the United States.",
        "distractor2": "prohibited any state from denying an American citizen the right to vote based on race/ethnic background, color, or having previously been a slave.",
        "distractor3": "provided Congress with the power to establish and collect income taxes.",
        "distractor4": "prohibited any state from denying women the right to vote."
    },
    {
        "question": "The president associated with the  Sellout of 1876  was?:",
        "correct_answer": "Rutherford B. Hayes.",
        "distractor1": "U. S. Grant.",
        "distractor2": "Andrew Johnson.",
        "distractor3": "William Howard Taft.",
        "distractor4": "James Buchanan."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Reconstruction policies of the Radical Republicans were probably motivated by?:",
        "correct_answer": "all of these choices are correct.",
        "distractor1": "a humanitarian concern for the former slaves.",
        "distractor2": "hopes for Republican power in the South.",
        "distractor3": "bitterness over having to fight the costly war."
    },
    {
        "question": "Andrew Johnson narrowly avoided conviction on impeachment charges because?:",
        "correct_answer": "some Republicans feared that removal would set a bad precedent for using impeachment as a political weapon against the Presidency.",
        "distractor1": "of his earlier cooperative attitude toward Congress.",
        "distractor2": "Radical Republicans were beginning to support his policies.",
        "distractor3": "only a minority of the Senate voted to convict."
    },
    {
        "question": "The refusal of the South to ratify the Fourteenth Amendment?:",
        "correct_answer": "forced the Republicans to abolish the existing southern governments, form new governments, and extend the vote to freedmen.",
        "distractor1": "caused most northerners to support the Radicals' demand that more economic opportunity be extended to freedmen.",
        "distractor2": "caused a thorough restructuring of southern society.",
        "distractor3": "led to general land reform in the South."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following best describes the defeat of the Ku Klux Klan?:",
        "correct_answer": "President Grant and the Justice Department used the Enforcement Acts of 1870 and 1871 to put an end to Klan activity.",
        "distractor1": "public outcry against Klan activities forced the Klan to disband.",
        "distractor2": "the Justice Department, prosecuting under the Civil Rights Act of 1866, threw most of the Klan leaders in jail, thus breaking the back of the movement.",
        "distractor3": "militias formed by the Radical regimes in the southern states chased the Klan from the cities and its membership then quickly declined."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the years after the Civil War, most freedmen ended up working as?:",
        "correct_answer": "farmers under a sharecropper system.",
        "distractor1": "farmers on land they owned.",
        "distractor2": "wage laborers in the new textile mills.",
        "distractor3": "itinerant day laborers in domestic and service jobs."
    },
    {
        "question": "What brought the Radical and moderate Republicans together in an alliance against President Johnson?:",
        "correct_answer": "the president's vetoes of the Freedmen's Bureau bill and the Civil Rights Act of 1866.",
        "distractor1": "realization by congressional Republicans that Johnson was delaying readmission of the former Confederate states.",
        "distractor2": "the president's proposal for an agency that would provide relief, rations, and medical care for impoverished southerners.",
        "distractor3": "a desire to send a message to northern Democrats that they could work together to rebuild the South."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Thirteenth Amendment established?:",
        "correct_answer": "the legal end of slavery in America.",
        "distractor1": "the right to vote for the ex-slaves.",
        "distractor2": "the two-term presidency.",
        "distractor3": "the income tax.",
        "distractor4": "female suffrage."
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of the Freedman's Bureau was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "feed, adjust, and educate the former slaves, thus aiding their adjustment to freedom.",
        "distractor1": "gain the vote for the freed slave.",
        "distractor2": "provide 40 acres and a mule for each slave.",
        "distractor3": "get radical Republicans in positions of power in the South.",
        "distractor4": "work against the Black Codes."
    },
    {
        "question": "By the end of his presidency, Ulysses S. Grant's popularity had declined substantially because of?:",
        "correct_answer": "the corruption evident in his administration.",
        "distractor1": "his harsh and brutal policies toward the South.",
        "distractor2": "his support for  greenback  monetary policies.",
        "distractor3": "revelations about his poor military leadership during the Civil War.",
        "distractor4": "his refusal to support the Radicals in Congress."
    },
    {
        "question": "The  Compromise of 1877  did which of the following?:",
        "correct_answer": "ended federal military support of Republican administrations in the South.",
        "distractor1": "secured political rights for the freedmen.",
        "distractor2": "granted political amnesty to former Confederate leaders.",
        "distractor3": "provided for a new method of counting the presidential electoral vote.",
        "distractor4": "restored the Southern states to the Union."
    },
    {
        "question": "This Amendment to the Constitution abolished slavery?:",
        "correct_answer": "Thirteenth.",
        "distractor1": "Twelfth.",
        "distractor2": "Fourteenth.",
        "distractor3": "Fifteenth.",
        "distractor4": "Sixteenth."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Oneida Community?:",
        "correct_answer": "believed it liberated women from the demands of male  lust  and from traditional bonds of family.",
        "distractor1": "advocated  free love  to redefine gender roles.",
        "distractor2": "called for celibacy and attracted members of conversion.",
        "distractor3": "was widely accepted and had almost no critics."
    },
    {
        "question": "In his Essay,  Resistance to Civil Government , Henry David Thoreau claimed that an individual should?:",
        "correct_answer": "refuse to obey unjust laws.",
        "distractor1": "no pay poll taxes.",
        "distractor2": "live in isolation and as simply as possible.",
        "distractor3": "obey only legitimately elected government officials.",
        "distractor4": "reject the artificial constraints of government."
    },
    {
        "question": "After 1830, which of the following reform movements began to overshadow the others?:",
        "correct_answer": "antislavery.",
        "distractor1": "women's rights.",
        "distractor2": "temperance.",
        "distractor3": "education.",
        "distractor4": "prison and penal reform."
    },
    {
        "question": "Transcendentalists believed that?:",
        "correct_answer": "each individual should strive to  transcend  the limits of intellect and allow emotions to create an  original relation to the universe. ",
        "distractor1": "understanding  was more important than  reason.",
        "distractor2": "man should repress instinct and strive for externally imposed learning.",
        "distractor3": "individuals should avoid anything that would bring one too close to the natural world."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 1820s and 1830s, Protestant revival evangelists like Charles Grandison Finney?:",
        "correct_answer": "all of these choices are correct.",
        "distractor1": "proclaimed the possibility of salvation for all by individual effort.",
        "distractor2": "called for a crusade against personal immorality.",
        "distractor3": "worked for the reform of the larger society."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the 1800s, members of the temperance movement agreed almost unanimously that?:",
        "correct_answer": "all of these choices are correct.",
        "distractor1": "abstinence should promote the moral self-improvement of individuals.",
        "distractor2": "state governments should restrict the sale and consumption of alcohol.",
        "distractor3": "abstinence should include not only hard liquor, but also beer and wine."
    },
    {
        "question": "Ralph Waldo Emerson's transcendentalist philosophy included all of the following beliefs EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "rejection of the existence of God.",
        "distractor1": "an intimate connection between man and nature.",
        "distractor2": "the sanctity of the individual.",
        "distractor3": "self-reliance and independence of spirit."
    },
    {
        "question": "Before the Civil War, the movement for women's rights was particularly strong among the?:",
        "correct_answer": "Quakers.",
        "distractor1": "Baptists.",
        "distractor2": "Mormons.",
        "distractor3": "Methodists.",
        "distractor4": "Catholics."
    },
    {
        "question": "The asylum movement of the 1800s incorporated the principle of?:",
        "correct_answer": "firm, yet humane, treatment to rehabilitate the criminal and the insane.",
        "distractor1": "freedom from strict discipline for prisoners and mental hospital inmates.",
        "distractor2": "the swift return of social deviants to the mainstream of society.",
        "distractor3": "using lessons from Indian life to improve the rest of American society."
    },
    {
        "question": "Antebellum feminists were generally?:",
        "correct_answer": "active in other reform movements as well.",
        "distractor1": "devoted to the issue of women's rights to the exclusion of all else.",
        "distractor2": "indifferent to political issues while attentive to social causes.",
        "distractor3": "united in their goals and methods."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following did NOT characterize the early 19c religious movement known as the Second Great Awakening?:",
        "correct_answer": "acceptance of slavery as ordained by God.",
        "distractor1": "extreme displays of emotion.",
        "distractor2": "an emphasis on individual convention.",
        "distractor3": "increased interest in social reforms such as the temperance movement.",
        "distractor4": "extensive involvement by women and African-Americans."
    },
    {
        "question": "Most founders of utopian communities believed that?:",
        "correct_answer": "if social arrangements could be perfected, the ills of society could be eliminated.",
        "distractor1": "if men and women lived together without being married, the population would decline.",
        "distractor2": "if perfect communities were created, the government would be forced to abolish slavery.",
        "distractor3": "if the natural defects of human society could be outlawed, men and women could live in harmony."
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the Proclamation of 1763?:",
        "correct_answer": "settlers were prohibited from crossing the Appalachians.",
        "distractor1": "colonial militiamen were required to put down Pontiac's Rebellion.",
        "distractor2": "colonial paper money could not be printed.",
        "distractor3": "contact between colonials and Indians was strictly forbidden.",
        "distractor4": "speculators were allowed to purchase certain lands from trans-Appalachian tribes."
    },
    {
        "question": "Thomas Paine's Common Sense?:",
        "correct_answer": "blamed George III for the colonies' problems and urged Americans to declare their independence.",
        "distractor1": "was a call for the abolition of slavery.",
        "distractor2": "insisted that the British allow the colonies to elect their own representatives to Parliament.",
        "distractor3": "criticized the weaknesses of the Articles of Confederation.",
        "distractor4": "demanded that a strong executive be included in the Constitution."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Intolerable Acts of 1774 included all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "new taxes on glass, tea, lead, and paper.",
        "distractor1": "the closing of Boston harbor.",
        "distractor2": "making the Massachusetts council and judiciary appointive.",
        "distractor3": "allowing trials of accused colonial officials to be moved to England.",
        "distractor4": "authorizing the governor to limit town meetings to as few as one a year."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Stamp Act Congress was significant because it?:",
        "correct_answer": "marked an important step toward the unity of the colonies.",
        "distractor1": "demonstrated that the colonies were loyal to Parliament.",
        "distractor2": "repealed the Stamp Act.",
        "distractor3": "led directly to the First Continental Congress.",
        "distractor4": "failed to persuade Parliament of colonial discontent."
    },
    {
        "question": "Benjamin Franklin epitomized which movement in colonial America?:",
        "correct_answer": "the Enlightenment.",
        "distractor1": "the Great Awakening.",
        "distractor2": "the loyalist movement.",
        "distractor3": "the abolitionist movement.",
        "distractor4": "the Glorious Revolution."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which was NOT a result of the French and Indian War (Seven Years' War)?:",
        "correct_answer": "Great Britain gained Louisiana.",
        "distractor1": "France lost Canada.",
        "distractor2": "Great Britain incurred high war costs.",
        "distractor3": "Great Britain saw a need to tighten its administrative system.",
        "distractor4": "Great Britain made a decision to reinvigorate the mercantile system."
    },
    {
        "question": "A historian compared tax lists for the years 1687 and 1771. What changes do you think he found in the Boston of 1771 compared",
        "correct_answer": "a more stratified social structure.",
        "distractor1": "an increase in the number of indentured servants entering Boston from abroad.",
        "distractor2": "a decline in the number of people considered poor and propertyless.",
        "distractor3": "an economy controlled by large landowners rather than by merchants.",
        "distractor4": "a stable population with little geographical, occupational, economic, or generational mobility."
    },
    {
        "question": "The ideology of revolutionary republicanism?:",
        "correct_answer": "borrowed ideas from a variety of former Whig and Enlightenment thinkers.",
        "distractor1": "reflected common colonial interests and experiences.",
        "distractor2": "originated in the struggle of American colonists against imperial despotism.",
        "distractor3": "provided a coherent doctrine to which all colonists could subscribe."
    },
    {
        "question": "Colonial Committees of Correspondence were created to?:",
        "correct_answer": "publicize grievances against England.",
        "distractor1": "keep colonial intellectuals in contact with each other.",
        "distractor2": "improve the writing skills of young gentlemen.",
        "distractor3": "correspond with English radicals who supported the American cause."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is typical of the role that colonial women played during the Townshend crisis?:",
        "correct_answer": "organizing spinning bees.",
        "distractor1": "remaining at home to ensure that family affairs continued to function in an orderly fashion.",
        "distractor2": "providing refreshments at Sons of Liberty meetings.",
        "distractor3": "encouraging the men to be moderate and peaceful."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is an accurate description of the Sons of Liberty, created in 1765?:",
        "correct_answer": "this inter-colonial association was created by the elite in an attempt to channel crowd action into acceptable forms of resistance.",
        "distractor1": "the organization was founded by colonists who opposed the colonial resistance movement.",
        "distractor2": "this inter-colonial association was founded by a group of newspaper editors who composed a series of essays on the subject of liberty.",
        "distractor3": "the organization was strongest in the South and was composed of radicals who demanded separation from Great Britain."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements best expressed the argument presented by John Dickinson in Letters From a Farmer in",
        "correct_answer": "Parliament may not use its power to regulate colonial trade for the purpose of raising revenue.",
        "distractor1": "Parliament may regulate colonial trade only with the concurrence of the colonial legislatures.",
        "distractor2": "parliament has no authority over the colonies.",
        "distractor3": "Parliament does not have the power to regulate colonial trade."
    },
    {
        "question": "The most important consequence of the Boston Tea Party was the?:",
        "correct_answer": "enactment by Parliament of the Coercive Act.",
        "distractor1": "repeal of the tax on tea.",
        "distractor2": "failure of other colonies to support Boston's action.",
        "distractor3": "opening of negotiations between Britain and Massachusetts.",
        "distractor4": "reopening of the Port of Boston to foreign trade."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following had the least significance in providing experience and concepts that were used by the colonists in their",
        "correct_answer": "the development by the colonists of crops for export.",
        "distractor1": "French and Indian War.",
        "distractor2": "New England town meetings.",
        "distractor3": "use of the  Power of the Purse  by the Virginia House of Burgesses.",
        "distractor4": "the Albany Plan."
    },
    {
        "question": "The British response to the American claim of no taxation without representation was that?:",
        "correct_answer": "members of Parliament represented the interests of all people in the British Empire.",
        "distractor1": "colonial assemblies would be permitted to vote on all new taxes.",
        "distractor2": "monies raised through taxes would be used for internal improvements in the colonies.",
        "distractor3": "American approval was necessary for internal taxes.",
        "distractor4": "Parliament agreed it had no authority to impose taxes on the colonies."
    },
    {
        "question": "England passed the Stamp Act in 1765 to?:",
        "correct_answer": "raise money to reduce England's national debt.",
        "distractor1": "punish Americans for protests to the Sugar Act.",
        "distractor2": "control the American press.",
        "distractor3": "allow for illegal search-and-seizure of smugglers.",
        "distractor4": "allow Americans to settle the Ohio River Valley."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Declaratory Act of 1766?:",
        "correct_answer": "stated that parliament had the power to make laws binding on the colonies.",
        "distractor1": "required the colonists to provide barracks and supplies for British troops.",
        "distractor2": "forbade the American colonists to issue paper money.",
        "distractor3": "established a new duty on molasses.",
        "distractor4": "established a tax on licenses, legal documents, and newspapers."
    },
    {
        "question": "One accomplishment of the First Continental Congress was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "petition the king to recognize the colonists' rights.",
        "distractor1": "enact the Declaration of Independence.",
        "distractor2": "raise an army to resist British aggression in Massachusetts.",
        "distractor3": "provide funds for Fort Ticonderoga.",
        "distractor4": "secure an alliance with France."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Molasses Act was intended to enforce England's mercantilist policies by?:",
        "correct_answer": "forcing the colonists to buy sugar from other British colonies rather than from foreign producers.",
        "distractor1": "forcing the colonists to export solely to Great Britain.",
        "distractor2": "forbidding the colonists to engage in manufacturing activity in competition with British industries.",
        "distractor3": "providing a favorable market for the products of the British East India Company.",
        "distractor4": "creating an economic situation in which gold tended to flow from the colonies to the mother country."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following states the principle of  virtual representation , as it was argued during the 18c?:",
        "correct_answer": "all English subjects, including those who are not allowed to vote, are represented in Parliament.",
        "distractor1": "paper money has value even though it is inherently worth very little.",
        "distractor2": "slave populations must be counted when figuring Congressional apportionment, even though slaves may not vote.",
        "distractor3": "American property-holding colonists may, if they so desire, join their state legislatures.",
        "distractor4": "all English subjects are entitled to a trial before a jury of their peers."
    },
    {
        "question": "A writ of assistance?:",
        "correct_answer": "allowed the British to ransack a colonial merchant's house in search of illegal goods.",
        "distractor1": "helped colonial merchants cut through the red tape of imperial trade regulations.",
        "distractor2": "required prosecutors to present evidence of probable cause for suspicion of smuggling.",
        "distractor3": "required that specified colonial products be landed in Britain before being shipped to other countries."
    },
    {
        "question": "Events in the late 1760s and early 1770s helped to bring about a new consensus in the colonies. What was the consensus?:",
        "correct_answer": "that Parliament had no lawmaking authority over the colonies except for the right to regulate imperial commerce.",
        "distractor1": "that the government could not tax the colonies because they were not represented in Parliament.",
        "distractor2": "that the British constitution could be altered by the passage of new laws.",
        "distractor3": "that the American colonies would be free from tyranny only when they were independent of British rule."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the early 1770s, the patriots sought freedom from parliamentary authority but continued to pledge allegiance to the",
        "correct_answer": "in the British mind the king was part of Parliament and the two could not be separated.",
        "distractor1": "the British felt more allegiance to Parliament than to the king.",
        "distractor2": "the British wanted to replace the king with an elected head of state.",
        "distractor3": "in the British mind Parliament was divinely inspired."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the 1760s and 1770s the most effective American tactic in gaining the repeal of the Stamp and Townshend Acts was?:",
        "correct_answer": "boycotting British goods.",
        "distractor1": "tarring and feathering British tax agents.",
        "distractor2": "sending petitions to the king and Parliament.",
        "distractor3": "destroying private property, such as tea, on which a tax to be levied.",
        "distractor4": "using death threats to intimidate British tax agents."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following characterized the economy of the 1920s?:",
        "correct_answer": "a shift to the production of consumer goods.",
        "distractor1": "an emphasis on heavy industry, such as the production of locomotives.",
        "distractor2": "a drop in the real wages of workers.",
        "distractor3": "increasing wealth for the agricultural sector.",
        "distractor4": "an emphasis on cash rather than credit purchases."
    },
    {
        "question": "Prohibition failed because?:",
        "correct_answer": "many Americans believed the law interfered with their personal freedom.",
        "distractor1": "organized crime controlled illegal liquor production.",
        "distractor2": "rural America failed to support it.",
        "distractor3": "it adversely affected American productivity.",
        "distractor4": "the costs of enforcing it were too expensive."
    },
    {
        "question": "By the end of the 1920s, what had become the nation's largest industry?:",
        "correct_answer": "automobiles.",
        "distractor1": "steel.",
        "distractor2": "railroads.",
        "distractor3": "oil.",
        "distractor4": "chemicals."
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following characterized the writing of the  Lost Generation  EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "an acceptance of decadence as the best way to survive in post-World War I society.",
        "distractor1": "disillusionment with materialism and consumerism.",
        "distractor2": "heroes as flawed as the villains they struggle against.",
        "distractor3": "a sense of lost values and purpose.",
        "distractor4": "repugnance at the loss of spirituality in society."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following best describes the administrations of Warren harding and Calvin Coolidge?:",
        "correct_answer": "The business of government is business!",
        "distractor1": "The trusts must be broken!",
        "distractor2": "The only thing we have to fear is fear itself!",
        "distractor3": "The taste of empire is in the mouths of the people!",
        "distractor4": "The world must be made safe for democracy!"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most important problem faced by the Democratic party in the 1920s was?:",
        "correct_answer": "a serious split between urban and rural wings of the party.",
        "distractor1": "the party was losing its traditional strength in the South.",
        "distractor2": "the fact that recent immigrants no longer tended to support the party.",
        "distractor3": "the restriction of immigration reduced the number of recruits to the party."
    },
    {
        "question": "The conclusion of the Sacco and Vanzetti case suggested that?:",
        "correct_answer": "many Americans had an unreasonable fear of radicals and foreigners.",
        "distractor1": "the two men were clearly guilty.",
        "distractor2": "African Americans could not get a fair trial in most southern states.",
        "distractor3": "the two men needed better legal representation."
    },
    {
        "question": "The union movement weakened in the 1920s because?:",
        "correct_answer": "all of these choices are correct.",
        "distractor1": "overall wage rates rose steadily in the 1920s.",
        "distractor2": "the older craft-based pattern of union organization was ill-suited to the new mass-production industries.",
        "distractor3": "management was hostile to labor organizing."
    },
    {
        "question": "A major cause of the Great Depression was?:",
        "correct_answer": "the inability of wages to keep pace with production increases.",
        "distractor1": "the stock market crash.",
        "distractor2": "reliance upon a single metallic base for currency.",
        "distractor3": "the inability of production to keep pace with wage increases.",
        "distractor4": "federal budget increases during the New Deal."
    },
    {
        "question": "An important result of the Hawley-Smoot Tariff Act was?:",
        "correct_answer": "tariff reprisals from a number of foreign countries.",
        "distractor1": "an increase in farm income.",
        "distractor2": "a great increase in the development of foreign trade.",
        "distractor3": "a general improvement in business conditions.",
        "distractor4": "new prosperity for factory workers in the United States."
    },
    {
        "question": "The mood of  normalcy  invoked by President Warren G. Harding connoted?:",
        "correct_answer": "turning away from Europe and away from the programs of the Progressive Era.",
        "distractor1": "a return to the Jeffersonian ideal of an agrarian republic.",
        "distractor2": "strict government regulation of business.",
        "distractor3": "U. S. assertiveness and leadership in world affairs.",
        "distractor4": "a progressive government that would care for the needs of the common man."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the significance of the Immigration Acts of 1921 and 1924?:",
        "correct_answer": "they set quotas on immigration from certain areas of Europe, Asia, and Africa.",
        "distractor1": "they limited immigration from Mexico for the first time.",
        "distractor2": "they created a category of  special immigrants,  which included relatives of U. S. citizens living abroad.",
        "distractor3": "they made immigration requirements qualitative, rather than quantitative.",
        "distractor4": "they based annual quotas on a flat one-sixth of one percent of the national population in 1920."
    },
    {
        "question": "The rapid growth of the automobile industry was made possible by?:",
        "correct_answer": "a ready market created by the rising standard of living and the increase of leisure time of the average American.",
        "distractor1": "the introduction by Henry Ford of an eight-hour day and a minimum wage of $5 a day in 1914.",
        "distractor2": "cooperation of labor and management in the trucking industry.",
        "distractor3": "failure of trolleys and railroads to maintain a high standard in their facilities and operations."
    },
    {
        "question": "I remarked,  The man who builds a factory builds a temple; the man who works there, worships there ?:",
        "correct_answer": "Calvin Coolidge.",
        "distractor1": "Warren G. Harding.",
        "distractor2": "Robert La Follette.",
        "distractor3": "Henry Ford.",
        "distractor4": "Andrew Carnegie."
    },
    {
        "question": "American foreign policy toward Europe during the 1920s was characterized by a?:",
        "correct_answer": "trend toward isolationism, except for a willingness to enter into a treaty to curtail a naval arms race.",
        "distractor1": "willingness to forgive and forget the World War I debts owed to the U. S. government by former allies.",
        "distractor2": "desire to lead and dominate the League of Nations.",
        "distractor3": "refusal to participate in the League of Nations but a willingness to join the World Court and abide by its decisions."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is most consistent with the philosophy of Marcus Garvey's Universal Negro Improvement",
        "correct_answer": "blacks should separate themselves from corrupt white American society.",
        "distractor1": "blacks should demand integration in all areas of American society.",
        "distractor2": "blacks must elect their own candidates to state and national offices in order to become an integral part of white society.",
        "distractor3": "blacks must prove their ability at manual jobs in order to achieve upward mobility."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following methods of fighting the Depression did President Herbert Hoover oppose throughout his",
        "correct_answer": "federal welfare programs to give relief directly to the poor.",
        "distractor1": "an increase of taxes on wealthy individuals and corporations.",
        "distractor2": "loans by the government to big businesses to keep them from failing.",
        "distractor3": "increased state and local spending for public works programs.",
        "distractor4": "continued promotion of cooperation and conferences between government and business."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the eyes of John Maynard Keynes, the ultimate responsibility for full employment rested with the?:",
        "correct_answer": "central government.",
        "distractor1": "good will of businessmen.",
        "distractor2": "gold-producing countries.",
        "distractor3": "trade unions.",
        "distractor4": "natural forces of economic variables."
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the major problems facing farmers in the 1920s was?:",
        "correct_answer": "overproduction.",
        "distractor1": "the inability to purchase modern farm equipment.",
        "distractor2": "passage of the McNary-Haugen Bill.",
        "distractor3": "the prosecution of cooperatives under anti-trust laws."
    },
    {
        "question": "Part of the reason for the stock market crash was?:",
        "correct_answer": "the buying of great amounts of stock  on margin. ",
        "distractor1": "the high rate of deflation in the 1920s.",
        "distractor2": "the tax policies of the 1920s, which especially hurt the wealthy who might otherwise have brought more stocks.",
        "distractor3": "the low tariff, which allowed imports to corner several important American markets."
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following were part of American economic policy during the 1920s EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "support of public works projects.",
        "distractor1": "lower taxes on the wealthy.",
        "distractor2": "high tariffs.",
        "distractor3": "limits on regulation of business.",
        "distractor4": "opposition to parity prices for farmers."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 1920s, the United States government did all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "guarantee Franco-German and Belgian-German boundaries.",
        "distractor1": "co-author an international pact that outlawed war as an instrument of national policy.",
        "distractor2": "sponsor international plans to solve the reparations problem.",
        "distractor3": "authorize loans to Germany.",
        "distractor4": "participate in some agencies of the League of Nations."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Kellog-Briand Pact of 1928 pledged the signatory nations to?:",
        "correct_answer": "renounce war as an instrument of national policy.",
        "distractor1": "join the League of Nations.",
        "distractor2": "respect the Open Door Policy in China.",
        "distractor3": "create a binding regional security military alliance with one another."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Republicans returned to power with the election of Warren G. Harding in 1920. The new president's call for a",
        "correct_answer": "isolationism and protectionism.",
        "distractor1": "low tariffs and high taxes.",
        "distractor2": "a huge increase in government expenditures.",
        "distractor3": "active participation in international affairs."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Coolidge administration?:",
        "correct_answer": "worked to help wealthy Americans through tax cuts and other pro-business activities.",
        "distractor1": "recognized the laborer's right to bargain collectively and to unionize.",
        "distractor2": "formed a coalition with farmers to raise agricultural prices.",
        "distractor3": "passed federal regulations to protect child labor."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Harlem Renaissance refers to?:",
        "correct_answer": "the movement of African-American artists, poets, and writers who expressed their pride in being black.",
        "distractor1": "the  Lost Generation  of writers who moved to Europe during the 1920s.",
        "distractor2": "the most famous jazz ensemble during the 1920s.",
        "distractor3": "the name of the shipping company owned by the United Negro Improvement Association, promoting a  Back-To-Africa  movement.,"
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the most important economic transformations in the years after World War I was?:",
        "correct_answer": "the shift in production from heavy industry to consumer goods and services.",
        "distractor1": "the move from the Northeast and Midwest to the West Coast as the country's industrial heartland.",
        "distractor2": "a change from a more cooperative to a more adversarial relationship between government and business.",
        "distractor3": "the shift from industry's reliance on railroads to reliance on the automobile."
    },
    {
        "question": "One effect of the Great Depression on women was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "strengthen the belief that a woman's place was in the home.",
        "distractor1": "open up new opportunities for women in the professions.",
        "distractor2": "drive most women out of the labor force by the time the economic crisis was over.",
        "distractor3": "gain increased public support for such feminist organizations as the National Woman's Party."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Reconstruction Finance Corporation?:",
        "correct_answer": "offered emergency loans to banks, farm mortgage associations, building and loan societies, and other such businesses to prevent bankruptcies.",
        "distractor1": "was passed over Hoover's veto.",
        "distractor2": "was criticized for its alleged favoritism to farmers and workers.",
        "distractor3": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "One result of the  Dust Bowl  was that?:",
        "correct_answer": "several million people on the Plains abandoned their farms and moved West.",
        "distractor1": "California became the most populous state in the Union.",
        "distractor2": "Mexican-Americans and African-Americans took advantage of the opportunity to settle abandoned land.",
        "distractor3": "big, industrial agricultural cooperatives broke up into smaller units."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about blacks in American society during the 1970s and 1980s is supported by the evidence?:",
        "correct_answer": "two black Americas emerged during these years, one consisting of very poor blacks and the other of an increasingly affluent black middle class.",
        "distractor1": "socially and economically, black Americans were as thoroughly integrated into American society as was possible.",
        "distractor2": "integration in America was so advanced that federal intervention was no longer necessary to continue the process.",
        "distractor3": "blacks had become such a crucial voting bloc in all regions of the nation that the gains of the civil rights movement could never be undone."
    },
    {
        "question": "The right-to-life movement succeeded in?:",
        "correct_answer": "helping to defeat pro-choice politicians and achieving restrictions on abortions.",
        "distractor1": "creating a constitutional amendment banning abortions.",
        "distractor2": "getting the  Stewart v. Freeman  case to the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor3": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Women's Strike of 1970 and the women's movement of the 1970s centered on three central demands. Which one was NOT one of",
        "correct_answer": "the removal of the  glass ceiling  in 20% of all corporate management positions.",
        "distractor1": "equality for women in employment and education.",
        "distractor2": "child care centers throughout the nation.",
        "distractor3": "women's control over their bodies, including the right to abortion."
    },
    {
        "question": "In  Bakke v. University of California , the Supreme Court?:",
        "correct_answer": "outlawed quotas and upheld the principle of affirmative action.",
        "distractor1": "upheld quotas and outlawed the principle of affirmative action.",
        "distractor2": "outlawed quotas and the principle of affirmative action.",
        "distractor3": "upheld quotas and the principles of affirmative action."
    },
    {
        "question": "By 1980, the American economy was beginning to show a pattern of?:",
        "correct_answer": "a significant shift from industrial to service employment.",
        "distractor1": "increased per-worker productivity.",
        "distractor2": "massive reinvestment in capital industry.",
        "distractor3": "permanent prosperity."
    },
    {
        "question": "The most important method of the 1970s designed to overcome segregation in the schools was?:",
        "correct_answer": "federal court-ordered busing.",
        "distractor1": "state court-mandated desegregation of the real estate market.",
        "distractor2": "voluntary desegregation of schools, with a state court oversight.",
        "distractor3": "federal court-mandated desegregation of the real estate market."
    },
    {
        "question": "The baby-boom generation will create a major problem in the future by?:",
        "correct_answer": "placing an enormous strain on the Social Security system.",
        "distractor1": "producing an even larger generation of children than itself.",
        "distractor2": "creating a housing surplus.",
        "distractor3": "causing immigration restrictions to be imposed upon many deserving people."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is most consistent with the Supreme Court's ruling in  Roe v. Wade ?:",
        "correct_answer": "the Constitution protects a woman's decision about whether to have an abortion up to the last three months of pregnancy.",
        "distractor1": "there is no inherent right to privacy embodied in the Constitution; thus, a state may prohibit the sale of contraceptives.",
        "distractor2": "the right to privacy is guaranteed by the Constitution; thus, a state does not have the power to regulate sexual acts between consenting adults.",
        "distractor3": "the Constitution protects the rights of the fetus over the rights of the mother after the first three months of pregnancy."
    },
    {
        "question": "A striking feature of the new wealth of the 1980s was?:",
        "correct_answer": "the degree to which wealth came from moving assets around rather than from creating goods.",
        "distractor1": "the extent to which people put their money into savings accounts.",
        "distractor2": "how many new industries were created during the decade.",
        "distractor3": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "Anti-feminism achieved its greatest victory in?:",
        "correct_answer": "blocking ratification of the Equal Rights Amendment.",
        "distractor1": "getting governments to refuse to pay for abortions under Medicaid.",
        "distractor2": "creating the National Organization for Women.",
        "distractor3": "getting Congress to pass the Dependent Woman Tax Act, giving tax benefits to dependent women."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 1985 case of  County of Oneida v. Oneida Indian Nation , the Supreme Court's decision raised the possibility",
        "correct_answer": "Native Americans might reclaim land lost when the federal government violated old treaties.",
        "distractor1": "social discrimination against Native Americans might be outlawed by Congress.",
        "distractor2": "Native Americans might gain full civil rights under the Constitution.",
        "distractor3": "tribal laws might gain full legal sanction within reservations."
    },
    {
        "question": "Evangelical Protestants and conservative Catholics in the 1980s and 1990s generally agreed on all of the following",
        "correct_answer": "political participation by the clergy.",
        "distractor1": "federal aid to religious schools.",
        "distractor2": "opposition to abortion.",
        "distractor3": "the AIDS disease might be understood as the consequences of immorality."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was true of women in American society by the mid-1980s?:",
        "correct_answer": "most adult women worked for pay outside the home.",
        "distractor1": "they no longer had to contend with occupational segregation.",
        "distractor2": "the earnings gap between women workers and men workers disappeared.",
        "distractor3": "most new mothers left the job market permanently."
    },
    {
        "question": "Sources of discomfort among youth during the decade of the 1960s included all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "failure of the Johnson administration to face the social and economic problems of the underclass.",
        "distractor1": "the unpopular war in Vietnam.",
        "distractor2": "the unequal treatment of blacks and other minorities.",
        "distractor3": "resentment against the traditional practices of college and university administrations which were conceived as authoritarian."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is most consistent with the belief expressed by Stokely Carmichael in his 1966 call for",
        "correct_answer": "to be truly free from white oppression, blacks must control their own economic, political, and social institutions.",
        "distractor1": "to right the wrongs done against them, blacks should move to several southern states, take them over, and push white residents out.",
        "distractor2": "blacks can gain independence and dignity only be returning en masse to Africa.",
        "distractor3": "blacks must seek revenge for the wrongs done against them by forming vigilante groups to assassinate prominent whites."
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following contributed to a  sexual revolution  during the 1960s EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "the elimination of all state laws infringing on a woman's right to an abortion during the first trimester of pregnancy.",
        "distractor1": "waning fear of unwanted pregnancy because of the availability of contraceptives, particularly the Pill.",
        "distractor2": "greater permissiveness and openness about sexual activity.",
        "distractor3": "the counter-culture's  do your own thing  attitude."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Stonewall riots helped forge a new sense of solidarity among?:",
        "correct_answer": "gay Americans.",
        "distractor1": "women.",
        "distractor2": "African-Americans.",
        "distractor3": "the elderly.",
        "distractor4": "Native Americans."
    },
    {
        "question": "              We are the people of",
        "correct_answer": "was the manifesto of the Students for a Democratic Society.",
        "distractor1": "was written by Malcolm X.",
        "distractor2": "was called  the hippie's creed. ",
        "distractor3": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "The National Organization for Women was created?:",
        "correct_answer": "as a civil rights organization for women, working against sex discrimination in employment.",
        "distractor1": "to elect women on the state, local, and national levels to political office.",
        "distractor2": "to promote women for top corporate executive positions.",
        "distractor3": "none of these choices are correct. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement concerning African-Americans' movement for civil rights in the 1960s is accurate?:",
        "correct_answer": "it stimulated the growth of other reform movements.",
        "distractor1": "its leaders failed to use the U. S. Congress as a means of achieving its goals.",
        "distractor2": "white support and participation was rejected from the very beginning of the movement.",
        "distractor3": "the movement failed to achieve significant progress."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Commission on Civil Disorders issued a report in 1968 that recommended?:",
        "correct_answer": "massive spending to improve conditions in the ghettos.",
        "distractor1": "increased law enforcement in the ghettos.",
        "distractor2": "federal legislation to protect urban dwellers.",
        "distractor3": "more coercive measures to halt violence."
    },
    {
        "question": "In  Miranda v. Arizona , the Supreme Court declared that?:",
        "correct_answer": "police had to advise a suspect of his or her constitutional right to remain silent.",
        "distractor1": "state laws prohibiting marriage between persons of different races were unconstitutional.",
        "distractor2": "the federal courts possessed jurisdiction over state apportionment systems to ensure that the votes of all citizens carry equal weight.",
        "distractor3": "states could not establish racially segregated schools even if the schools were supposed to have equal facilities."
    },
    {
        "question": "The counter-culture of the 1960s promoted all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "a new emphasis on religion.",
        "distractor1": "tolerant attitudes regarding sexual morality.",
        "distractor2": "desires for greater self-fulfillment.",
        "distractor3": "the questioning of government and other authority."
    },
    {
        "question": "By 1964 what had become the major thrust of young African-American activists?:",
        "correct_answer": "voter registration drives in southern states.",
        "distractor1": "mass lobbying for the legal prohibition of discrimination in public accommodations and facilities.",
        "distractor2": "encouragement of economic opportunity for African-Americans by making Small Business Administration loans available for minority-owned companies.",
        "distractor3": "encouragement of the development of a separate and distinct sense of African culture and heritage among African-Americans."
    },
    {
        "question": "The essential element of the policy of containment was?:",
        "correct_answer": "a commitment to holding communism within the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe.",
        "distractor1": "a commitment to rolling back communism.",
        "distractor2": "a rejection of involvement in affairs outside the Western Hemisphere.",
        "distractor3": "a commitment to working with the Soviet Union.",
        "distractor4": "a commitment to fight a defensive war against the Japanese while taking the offensive against Germany."
    },
    {
        "question": "Truman's response to the Berlin Blockade was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "airlift all necessary supplies into Berlin for almost a year.",
        "distractor1": "abandon the Western-occupied portions of Berlin.",
        "distractor2": "give up plans for uniting the three Western zones of Germany.",
        "distractor3": "use military force to break the blockade of land routes into Berlin."
    },
    {
        "question": "The main economic problem faced by President Truman in his first term was?:",
        "correct_answer": "inflation.",
        "distractor1": "falling prices.",
        "distractor2": "a dwindling money supply.",
        "distractor3": "tight credit.",
        "distractor4": "deflation."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Marshall Plan could be be understood as part of an American desire to?:",
        "correct_answer": "make communism less appealing to Europeans creating economic prosperity.",
        "distractor1": "assemble a military alliance against the Soviet Union.",
        "distractor2": "maintain Western Europe in a state of permanent economic dependence on the United States.",
        "distractor3": "permanently eliminate the possibility of a threat from an industrialized Germany.",
        "distractor4": "end the nation's postwar depression by creating viable economic competitors in Europe."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Truman contributed to the anti-Communist fear after the Second World War by?:",
        "correct_answer": "ordering investigations into the loyalty of federal employees.",
        "distractor1": "recommending that  pro-Communist  books be removed from the nation's libraries and bookstores.",
        "distractor2": "claiming that all liberal Democrats were Communist sympathizers.",
        "distractor3": "releasing classified information revealing an international Communist conspiracy."
    },
    {
        "question": "Harry Truman aided the cause of civil rights by?:",
        "correct_answer": "desegregating the armed forces.",
        "distractor1": "denouncing Southern support in the 1948 presidential election.",
        "distractor2": "integrating the public schools.",
        "distractor3": "ordering non-discrimination in a all defense contracts.",
        "distractor4": "integrating restaurants, movie theaters, and interstate travel."
    },
    {
        "question": "The United Nations was able to provide military assistance to South Korea in 1950 because?:",
        "correct_answer": "the USSR boycotted the session of the Security Council at which the decision was made.",
        "distractor1": "the USSR opposed the North Korean invasion of the South.",
        "distractor2": "the United States outvoted the Soviet Union.",
        "distractor3": "the General Assembly approved the decision.",
        "distractor4": "other nations in Southeast Asia pledged their support."
    },
    {
        "question": "The removal of General Douglas MacArthur from command of the United States-United Nations forces during the Korean War",
        "correct_answer": "civilian control of the military.",
        "distractor1": "separation of powers.",
        "distractor2": "federal supremacy.",
        "distractor3": "freedom of speech.",
        "distractor4": "impeachment for high crimes and misdemeanors."
    },
    {
        "question": "Most of Truman's Fair Deal program?:",
        "correct_answer": "met defeat at the hands of a coalition of Republicans and Southern Democrats.",
        "distractor1": "was defeated by filibuster tactics.",
        "distractor2": "was passed by a combination of liberal Republicans and Northern Democrats.",
        "distractor3": "was passed after long debate."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Taft-Harley Act of 1947 provided for all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "permitting union contributions to political campaigns.",
        "distractor1": "permitting employers to sue unions.",
        "distractor2": "requiring a sixty-day cooling off period before strikes.",
        "distractor3": "requiring unions to make public financial statements.",
        "distractor4": "requiring union leaders to take oaths that they were not Communist party members."
    },
    {
        "question": "All of these statements about the 1948 presidential campaign are true EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "Truman was a heavy favorite to defeat his Republican rival, Governor Thomas Dewey of New York.",
        "distractor1": "the Dixiecrats were a special group of Southern Democrats who would not support Truman.",
        "distractor2": "Henry Wallace broke from the Democratic party and became a candidate on the Progressive party ticket.",
        "distractor3": "not only did Truman win the election, but his party made gains in both houses of Congress and picked up most of the governorships.",
        "distractor4": "the Democrats lost electoral votes from the states once known as the  Solid South. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The legal basis for Truman's order for American air and naval forces to support South Korea was?:",
        "correct_answer": "the federal Constitution.",
        "distractor1": "an inherent power of the presidency.",
        "distractor2": "a joint resolution of Congress.",
        "distractor3": "the United Nations Charter.",
        "distractor4": "the United States treaty with the Republic of Korea."
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1947, President Truman told Congress that  the United States could not realize its postwar objectives unless we",
        "correct_answer": "Greece and Turkey.",
        "distractor1": "Berlin.",
        "distractor2": "Hungary and Iran.",
        "distractor3": "Korea.",
        "distractor4": "China and Japan."
    },
    {
        "question": "The  G. I. Bill of Rights  refers to?:",
        "correct_answer": "legislation passed by Congress pertaining to education, unemployment compensation, loans for home building, and provisions for medical care of veterans.",
        "distractor1": "an amendment to the Constitution adopted shortly after the end of World War II.",
        "distractor2": "rights of veterans affirmed by the Supreme Court in a series of post-war decisions.",
        "distractor3": "guarantees for employment of veterans in federal government departments and agencies."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Truman administration's decision to oppose the invasion of South Korea by North Korea in June, 1950 was made?:",
        "correct_answer": "without congressional approval.",
        "distractor1": "after the United States Senate declared war on North Korea.",
        "distractor2": "at the insistence of General Douglas MacArthur.",
        "distractor3": "because the United Nations refused to act.",
        "distractor4": "because of pressure from Republican conservatives such as Robert Taft."
    },
    {
        "question": "While there was a large gap between what Harry Truman said about civil rights and what he was able to do, his greatest",
        "correct_answer": "using the prestige and visibility of his office to educate the public and set a moral agenda for future civil rights progress.",
        "distractor1": "integrating the civil service.",
        "distractor2": "creating a national anti-lynching law.",
        "distractor3": "creating a national anti-poll tax law."
    },
    {
        "question": "The House Un-American Activities Committee was?:",
        "correct_answer": "responsible for a series of highly publicized hearings designed to expose communist influence in American life.",
        "distractor1": "the name that Senator Joseph McCarthy gave to the House Armed Services Committee.",
        "distractor2": "declared by the Supreme Court to be in violation of basic civil liberties and therefore unconstitutional.",
        "distractor3": "shut down by President Truman as a signal to the nation that the crusade against communist subversion would be directed from the White House."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the struggle in China between nationalists and communists after World War II, the United States?:",
        "correct_answer": "continued to support Chiang Kai-shek with money and weapons even when it became clear his cause was lost.",
        "distractor1": "supported the communist leader Mao Zedong hoping that a communist China friendly to the United States would help stop Soviet aggression.",
        "distractor2": "supported Ho Chi Minh, a compromise leader.",
        "distractor3": "intervened militarily to put an end to the struggle."
    },
    {
        "question": "At the beginning of the Cold War, U. S. policy toward the Soviet Union tended to follow the ideas of George F. Kennan, that",
        "correct_answer": "a policy of containment of Soviet expansionist tendencies.",
        "distractor1": "an isolationist policy that took no notice of Soviet expansionism.",
        "distractor2": "an aggressive policy of rolling back the gains already made by the Soviet Union.",
        "distractor3": "active aid to nationalist movements attempting to throw off Soviet domination.",
        "distractor4": "strict enforcement of the Monroe Doctrine with regard to Soviet expansionism in the Western Hemisphere."
    },
    {
        "question": "Under President Truman, the Department of Justice?:",
        "correct_answer": "intervened in Supreme Court cases on behalf of organizations seeking to end segregation.",
        "distractor1": "argued that the Supreme Court did not have the authority to end segregation.",
        "distractor2": "persuaded Congress to pass legislation prohibiting racial bias in home sales and rentals.",
        "distractor3": "vigorously prosecuted cases arising under the new anti-lynching legislation."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following did NOT contribute to the end of the open range cattle industry?:",
        "correct_answer": "railroads.",
        "distractor1": "droughts.",
        "distractor2": "farming.",
        "distractor3": "barbed wire.",
        "distractor4": "sheep herding."
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States' policy toward the Native American changed dramatically with the passage in 1887 of the Dawes Act, which?:",
        "correct_answer": "wiped out tribal ownership of property and granted 160 acres to heads of families.",
        "distractor1": "treated the tribes as independent nations.",
        "distractor2": "established new and larger reservations for all tribes.",
        "distractor3": "granted full citizenship to all tribal members.",
        "distractor4": "forbade selling alcohol or guns on reservations."
    },
    {
        "question": "The historian Frederick Jackson Turner argued that the frontier shaped America by?:",
        "correct_answer": "stimulating individualism, nationalism, and democracy.",
        "distractor1": "killing off many of the most adventurous individuals.",
        "distractor2": "producing institutions very much like those of Europe.",
        "distractor3": "creating new opportunities for women."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the late 1800s, farmers supported free and unlimited coinage of silver mainly because they believed that it would",
        "correct_answer": "higher prices for farm products.",
        "distractor1": "the establishment of government farm price supports.",
        "distractor2": "the lowering of rates charged by railroads.",
        "distractor3": "lower prices for consumer goods."
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States government's outlawing of the Indian Sun (Ghost) Dance in 1890 resulted in the?:",
        "correct_answer": "Battle of Wounded Knee.",
        "distractor1": "Battle of Little Big Horn.",
        "distractor2": "Battle of Potowanamie Creek.",
        "distractor3": "Dawes Severality Act.",
        "distractor4": "Massacre at Sand Creek."
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the new view of the environment that was developing in the late 19c?:",
        "correct_answer": "nature existed to be tamed and conquered.",
        "distractor1": "humans tended to be disturbers of nature.",
        "distractor2": "natural resources were abundant and existed to be exploited.",
        "distractor3": "natural wildlife management would help to stabilize the buffalo population."
    },
    {
        "question": "The two factors that did most to stimulate rapid western settlement were?:",
        "correct_answer": "the Homestead Act and the railroad.",
        "distractor1": "removal of the buffalo and Native Americans from the plains.",
        "distractor2": "the gold rushes and the rise of the great cattle kingdoms.",
        "distractor3": "the removal of the Indians and the gold rushes."
    },
    {
        "question": "The mining towns which developed between 1860 and 1890?:",
        "correct_answer": "all of these choices are correct.",
        "distractor1": "were often abandoned after the mines closed.",
        "distractor2": "were predominantly settled by men.",
        "distractor3": "frequently suffered from lawlessness."
    },
    {
        "question": "The rapid development of railroads in the United States was accomplished?:",
        "correct_answer": "with the help of some of the largest government subsidies ever granted.",
        "distractor1": "in large measure through the investment of European banking firms.",
        "distractor2": "exclusively through the support of large numbers of small investors.",
        "distractor3": "almost totally through the investment of a handful of shrewd millionaires."
    },
    {
        "question": "Open-range ranching came to an end due to?:",
        "correct_answer": "fencing of the plains with barbed wire.",
        "distractor1": "overproduction of beef and declining prices.",
        "distractor2": "federal support for irrigated agriculture.",
        "distractor3": "the range wars between cattlemen and sheepherders.",
        "distractor4": "increase in cattle production in the Midwest and East."
    },
    {
        "question": "After the Civil War, the West favored the issue of greenbacks because?:",
        "correct_answer": "inflation and cheap dollars would favor the farmers, who were in debt.",
        "distractor1": "this would increase the market for silver.",
        "distractor2": "the war had raised the prices of food outrageously.",
        "distractor3": "the government was unable to raise funds by marketing bonds.",
        "distractor4": "it wanted hard money backed by the gold standard."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Homestead Act provided?:",
        "correct_answer": "160 acres of free land within the public domain to any head of household who would settle on it and improve it over a period of five years.",
        "distractor1": "that Indians should henceforth own their lands as individuals rather than collectively as tribes.",
        "distractor2": "large amounts of federal government land to Great Plains cattle ranchers who would contract to provide beef for the Union army.",
        "distractor3": "40 acres of land to each former slave above the age of 21.",
        "distractor4": "that the land of former Confederates should not be confiscated."
    },
    {
        "question": "The railroads influenced the cattle industry by?:",
        "correct_answer": "all of these choices are correct.",
        "distractor1": "helping to make the  long drive  economically feasible.",
        "distractor2": "transporting cattle to markets in the North and the East.",
        "distractor3": "bringing in farmers who fenced the Plains, eventually ending the open-range form of cattle ranching."
    },
    {
        "question": "The federal government's Indian policy between 1876 and 1900 was characterized by?:",
        "correct_answer": "a movement to encourage the Indians to learn the ways of white society.",
        "distractor1": "an attempt to compensate the Indians for past mistreatment.",
        "distractor2": "a concern for the preservation of a tribal lifestyle among the Indians.",
        "distractor3": "a program to protect and maintain the buffalo herds."
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of the Dawes Severalty Act of 1887 was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "weaken tribes, allot land to individual Indians, and promote assimilation.",
        "distractor1": "geographically disperse the reservations so it would be more difficult for Indian warrior forces to unite.",
        "distractor2": "increase tribal loyalty and reduce violence by allowing chiefs and tribal councils to act autonomously on the reservations.",
        "distractor3": "restore economic viability to the nomadic way of Plains Indian life by revitalizing the bison herds."
    },
    {
        "question": "Six states were created from the western territories in 1889 and 1890. These states were not admitted before 1889 because?:",
        "correct_answer": "Democrats in Congress were reluctant to create states out of territories that were heavily Republican.",
        "distractor1": "the lawlessness of many western towns discouraged Congress from admitting the territories as states.",
        "distractor2": "polygamy, as practiced by the Mormons in the West, was unacceptable to Congress.",
        "distractor3": "if large mining firms had been forced to pay state taxes, they would have to close down."
    },
    {
        "question": "The cattle boom on the Great Plains ended in part because?:",
        "correct_answer": "severe weather conditions and overgrazing wiped out many ranchers.",
        "distractor1": "many ranchers preferred raising sheep.",
        "distractor2": "too few people were willing to risk investment.",
        "distractor3": "new breeds of cattle made ranching less profitable."
    },
    {
        "question": "The federal government aided settlement into the Great Plains region by all of the following means EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "giving cash bonuses to every settler who established residency in the new territories.",
        "distractor1": "offering settlers large areas of land at very small fees if they would live there for five years.",
        "distractor2": "making it easy to establish western territorial governments.",
        "distractor3": "changing federal land law frequently to adjust to western circumstances."
    },
    {
        "question": "Helen Hunt Jackson's book entitle  A Century of Dishonor  (1880) recounted?:",
        "correct_answer": "the long record of broken treaties and injustices against American Indians.",
        "distractor1": "American imperialism and its effects on the middle class.",
        "distractor2": "discriminatory practices employed by the United States government against African-Americans.",
        "distractor3": "the atrocities of the Spanish-American War.",
        "distractor4": "the abuses involving big business trusts in America."
    },
    {
        "question": "After the boom of the 1870s and early 1880s, agriculture in the West?:",
        "correct_answer": "experienced a long period of economic decline.",
        "distractor1": "went into a period of stable growth.",
        "distractor2": "enjoyed a further boom until the 1910s.",
        "distractor3": "changed little for the next decade."
    },
    {
        "question": "American involvement in World War I brought about which of the following social and economic changes in the United States?:",
        "correct_answer": "extensive black migration to the North.",
        "distractor1": "decline of trade unions.",
        "distractor2": "a loosening of controls on freedom of speech.",
        "distractor3": "reduction of the number of women in the workplace.",
        "distractor4": "a strengthening of anti-trust laws."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was most crucial in bringing about U. S. participation in World War I?:",
        "correct_answer": "German use of submarines against merchant and passenger ships.",
        "distractor1": "British propaganda.",
        "distractor2": "revelation of a German proposal to Mexico for a joint war against the United States.",
        "distractor3": "German violation of Belgian neutrality.",
        "distractor4": "German atrocities against French and Belgian civilians in the occupied areas of those countries."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Sedition Act of 1918 was most often used to punish?:",
        "correct_answer": "persons who criticized the war effort.",
        "distractor1": "rich progressives who did not contribute money to the war effort.",
        "distractor2": "groups organized by George Creel to drive Bolsheviks and Germans out of the cities.",
        "distractor3": "members of the press from the Hearst and Pulitzer syndicates.",
        "distractor4": "Egyptians, Iranians, and others emigrating from the Middle East to the United States."
    },
    {
        "question": "Germany's notorious Zimmermann telegram?:",
        "correct_answer": "proposed an alliance with Mexico if the United States declared war on Germany.",
        "distractor1": "promised a temporary halt to submarine warfare.",
        "distractor2": "apologized for the sinking of the  Lusitania .",
        "distractor3": "warned the United States not to send merchant ships to belligerent nations.",
        "distractor4": "rejected U. S. efforts for a truce in the fighting."
    },
    {
        "question": "Woodrow Wilson failed to obtain ratification of the Versailles Treaty because?:",
        "correct_answer": "he was unwilling to make any compromise with Senator Henry Cabot Lodge.",
        "distractor1": "a majority of the senators opposed the Treaty and the League of Nations under any circumstances.",
        "distractor2": "he made too many compromises with the Republican opposition.",
        "distractor3": "the Republican senators wanted a stronger League of Nations.",
        "distractor4": "he was unwilling to publicly campaign for the Treaty."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Red Scare of 1919 was influenced by all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "the continuation of World War I.",
        "distractor1": "the October Russian Revolution.",
        "distractor2": "labor strikes in several areas of the United States.",
        "distractor3": "terrorist bombings.",
        "distractor4": "formation of the American Communist Party."
    },
    {
        "question": "Evidence that labor played a key role during World War I may be supported by all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "despite labor cooperation, there were thousands of strikes (none of them major) during World War I.",
        "distractor1": "the AFL, led by Samuel Gompers, actively supported the war effort.",
        "distractor2": "women for the first time entered the labor force in large numbers during the war.",
        "distractor3": "blacks came North in large numbers to fill the ranks of labor in mining, steel production, and transportation."
    },
    {
        "question": "As a result of their work supporting the war effort, women?:",
        "correct_answer": "finally received the right to vote.",
        "distractor1": "in large numbers secured a permanent foothold in the work force.",
        "distractor2": "were allowed to join the Air Force.",
        "distractor3": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the first few years after World War I, relations between blacks and whites in America were generally characterized by?:",
        "correct_answer": "extreme resentment, race riots, and numerous lynchings.",
        "distractor1": "grudging acceptance due to common economic distress.",
        "distractor2": "relative cordiality due to the gallant service of blacks in the war.",
        "distractor3": "notable improvement due to new legal safeguards for blacks, which had been enacted during the Progressive Era."
    },
    {
        "question": "All were true of the impact of World War I on the federal government EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "the Supreme Court struck down acts of Congress that curtailed American civil liberties.",
        "distractor1": "centralized management along the lines of Roosevelt's Square Deal accelerated the creation of the modern bureaucratic state.",
        "distractor2": "the national debt multiplied tenfold.",
        "distractor3": "government-sponsored propaganda promoted psychological and social conformity."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is most consistent with the Supreme Court's ruling in  Schenck v. U. S. ?:",
        "correct_answer": "the government can restrict the First Amendment right to free speech in time of war.",
        "distractor1": "the government's seizure and operation of the railroad industry is a constitutional use of its wartime powers.",
        "distractor2": "the government's prohibition of the manufacture and sale of distilled liquor is a constitutional use of its wartime powers.",
        "distractor3": "the government does have the power to compel young men to serve in the armed forces during time of war."
    },
    {
        "question": "From the Red Scare of 1919 and 1920, it became clear that?:",
        "correct_answer": "people's fears of disloyalty could lead to the erosion of civil liberties.",
        "distractor1": "large numbers of Soviet agents had infiltrated the federal government.",
        "distractor2": "communism tended to gain influence in times of economic prosperity.",
        "distractor3": "loyalty oaths helped to prevent espionage."
    },
    {
        "question": "Those who question whether U. S. policy from 1914-1916 was truly neutral point to?:",
        "correct_answer": "increased U. S. trade with Britain and France.",
        "distractor1": "the sinking of unarmed ships by German submarines.",
        "distractor2": "the president's prejudices on racial issues.",
        "distractor3": "the reelection of President Woodrow Wilson.",
        "distractor4": "Germany's secret diplomacy with Mexico."
    },
    {
        "question": "During World War I, thousands of blacks moved north because?:",
        "correct_answer": "the best-paying jobs were located in the industrialized North.",
        "distractor1": "they would be better protected by northern anti-lynching laws.",
        "distractor2": "northern cities had finally started to desegregate.",
        "distractor3": "southerners finally allowed them to leave."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement best describes the  Irreconcilables  during the debate over the Treaty of Versailles?:",
        "correct_answer": "they were opposed to American participation in the League of Nations on any terms.",
        "distractor1": "they opposed the Treaty because it failed to adequately protect national minorities in eastern Europe.",
        "distractor2": "they supported the Treaty if certain changes were made on the reparations issue.",
        "distractor3": "they were willing to accept the Treaty if limitations were placed on U. S. participation in the League of Nations.",
        "distractor4": "they accepted the Treaty as presented by Wilson but refused to make any changes."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Creel Commission during World War I represented the United States' first successful attempt at large-scale",
        "correct_answer": "propaganda.",
        "distractor1": "armament manufacture.",
        "distractor2": "food production.",
        "distractor3": "shipbuilding.",
        "distractor4": "railroad management."
    },
    {
        "question": "Such expressions as  liberty cabbage  and  liberty sausage,  as used during World War I, were an",
        "correct_answer": "American hostile reaction to things German.",
        "distractor1": "food shortages.",
        "distractor2": "American food relief to Belgium.",
        "distractor3": "American patriotic fervor to increase the food supply by planting home  victory gardens. "
    },
    {
        "question": "President Woodrow Wilson viewed America's entry into World War I as an opportunity for the United States to?:",
        "correct_answer": "shape a new international order based on the ideals of democracy.",
        "distractor1": "reestablish the balance of power in European diplomacy.",
        "distractor2": "expand America's territorial holdings.",
        "distractor3": "rebuild its dangerously small military and naval forces."
    },
    {
        "question": "Under the Espionage and Sedition Acts of 1917-1918?:",
        "correct_answer": "criticism of government leaders or war policies was a crime.",
        "distractor1": "there were 25 prosecutions and 10 convictions.",
        "distractor2": "speaking and writing against Germany and Italy was a crime.",
        "distractor3": "censorship was aimed more at  middle America  than at Socialists or other radicals."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Wilson's response to the sinking of the  Lusitania ?:",
        "correct_answer": "included a speech in which he said that if Germany was responsible for the killing of any more Americans, then a state of war would exist between the United",
        "distractor1": "was to sever diplomatic ties with Germany.",
        "distractor2": "was a series of notes demanding that Germany stop such actions and pay reparations.",
        "distractor3": "was conciliatory."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Woodrow Wilson sent thousands of troops to Russia in 1918 to?:",
        "correct_answer": "subvert the new Russian Bolshevik government.",
        "distractor1": "act as a peacekeeping force in the Russian civil war.",
        "distractor2": "aid the new Russian government against Japanese aggression.",
        "distractor3": "counter Russian aggression against Hungary and Czechoslovakia."
    },
    {
        "question": "The global Spanish flu epidemic of 1918?:",
        "correct_answer": "killed five times the number of Americans as died of combat deaths in France.",
        "distractor1": "struck the United States earlier in 1913.",
        "distractor2": "ended suddenly in 1914.",
        "distractor3": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Red Scare of 1919-1920 was most influenced by?:",
        "correct_answer": "the tremendous growth of the Socialist party during World War I.",
        "distractor1": "massive steel strikes in western Pennsylvania.",
        "distractor2": "the shock of the Bolshevik Revolution in Russia and the actions of a  lunatic fringe  in the U. S.",
        "distractor3": "the demobilization of the American army."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the primary focus of United States foreign policy in the decade after World War I?:",
        "correct_answer": "to defend the price of freedom of the seas.",
        "distractor1": "to reduce United States commitments to other nations.",
        "distractor2": "to contain the spread of communism in Eastern Europe.",
        "distractor3": "to fulfill collective security agreements with Western European nations."
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States during World War II adopted all of the following strategies EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "use of atomic bombs on Germany and Japan.",
        "distractor1": "unconditional surrender.",
        "distractor2": "an eventual second front by invading Europe.",
        "distractor3": "victory in the European area first.",
        "distractor4": "support of de Gaulle's Free French forces."
    },
    {
        "question": "During World War II, women did all of the following EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "reaffirm traditional patterns for women's lives.",
        "distractor1": "work in factories.",
        "distractor2": "establish themselves as a vital part of the economy.",
        "distractor3": "participate in the war effort.",
        "distractor4": "define a new role in society."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Battles of the Coral Sea and Midway were significant in?:",
        "correct_answer": "stemming the tide of Japanese advances in the Pacific.",
        "distractor1": "saving the Philippines from being invaded.",
        "distractor2": "thwarting the Japanese army's drive through Burma.",
        "distractor3": "driving the last vestiges of American sea power from the Pacific."
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the most important domestic results of the war effort was?:",
        "correct_answer": "the swift ending of the Great Depression.",
        "distractor1": "complete employment for minority Americans.",
        "distractor2": "the end of discrimination for African Americans.",
        "distractor3": "the revitalization of the Federal Reserve System and the Securities and Exchange System."
    },
    {
        "question": "Attitudes in the United States toward Jews fleeing persecution in Europe during World War II were reflected in the?:",
        "correct_answer": "refusal to relax immigration restrictions for Jews.",
        "distractor1": "emotional welcome given the passengers aboard the  St. Louis .",
        "distractor2": "monetary and legal assistance given to Jews for immigration.",
        "distractor3": "acceptance of Jews in the United States."
    },
    {
        "question": "Franklin D. Roosevelt departed from Woodrow Wilson's wartime practices when he?:",
        "correct_answer": "included members of both political parties in the delegation to the San Francisco Conference.",
        "distractor1": "made public our general war aims before the enemy's surrender.",
        "distractor2": "traveled overseas to make plans for the peace settlement.",
        "distractor3": "engaged actively in political campaigning during the war.",
        "distractor4": "put great emphasis on a postwar international organization to preserve peace."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the Second World War, African Americans?:",
        "correct_answer": "fought in a segregated military.",
        "distractor1": "moved from the North to the South to fill vacated agricultural jobs.",
        "distractor2": "received support from the Roosevelt administration for civil rights legislation.",
        "distractor3": "were not allowed to fight in the military."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was agreed to at the Yalta Conference (1945)?:",
        "correct_answer": "an agreement to divide Germany into four military zones.",
        "distractor1": "the invasion of Sicily.",
        "distractor2": "the establishment of a Council of Foreign Ministers to draft peace treaties.",
        "distractor3": "a commitment to open a second front in France.",
        "distractor4": "the Soviet Union agreed to enter the war against Japan once Germany was defeated."
    },
    {
        "question": "To ensure that Russia would join the war against Japan, President Roosevelt in 1945?:",
        "correct_answer": "made certain secret agreements concerning Russian territorial demands.",
        "distractor1": "threatened to use the atomic bomb on Russian targets.",
        "distractor2": "gave Russia the secrets of the American atomic bomb.",
        "distractor3": "promised to assume half of the Russian war debt."
    },
    {
        "question": "The increase in the number of Mexican Americans employed in the United States during the early 1940s resulted from?:",
        "correct_answer": "wartime labor shortages.",
        "distractor1": "better relations between them and the Anglo-American population.",
        "distractor2": "better living conditions in the cities.",
        "distractor3": "large-scale government programs to reduce discrimination."
    },
    {
        "question": "What happened to the New Deal during World War II?:",
        "correct_answer": "an anti-New Deal coalition moved to end many New Deal programs, and the president adapted to the new political environment.",
        "distractor1": "since wartime spending brought recovery, neither Roosevelt nor Congress thought the New Deal was needed any more.",
        "distractor2": "although cloaked in wartime labels, several additional New-Deal style agencies were in fact created to provide relief, recovery, and reform.",
        "distractor3": "all of these choices are correct."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was the MAJOR reason President Truman used to justify his decision to drop the atomic bomb on Hiroshima",
        "correct_answer": "he felt it would shorten the war and eliminate the need for an invasion of Japan.",
        "distractor1": "he wanted to send a strong warning message to the Russians to watch their step in the Pacific after Japan was defeated.",
        "distractor2": "he believed it would be an appropriate revenge for the Japanese attack on Pearl Harbor.",
        "distractor3": "he felt it would end up saving Japanese civilian lives, when compared to the casualties expected from an invasion of Japan.",
        "distractor4": "once the bomb was completed, Truman felt he had to use it in order to justify the huge investments in time, resources, scientific expertise, and expense"
    },
    {
        "question": "World War II brought about all of the following changes EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "increasing the gap between the wealthiest and the poorest Americans.",
        "distractor1": "increasing the number of Americans who moved from rural areas to cities.",
        "distractor2": "accelerating long-developing social changes for black Americans.",
        "distractor3": "dramatic changes in the roles and expectations of women.",
        "distractor4": "accelerating the legal migration of Mexicans to southern California."
    },
    {
        "question": "In World War II the Allied strategy, agreed upon by the U. S. and Great Britain, was to?:",
        "correct_answer": "concentrate on defeating Germany first before turning on Japan.",
        "distractor1": "concentrate on defeating Japan first before turning to Germany.",
        "distractor2": "divide all resources equally between the war against Japan and that against Germany.",
        "distractor3": "fight only against Japan, leaving the Russians to fight Germany alone.",
        "distractor4": "take a passive role and limit operations to reacting to Axis moves."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Yalta Conference produced agreements on all of the following topics EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "the Allied invasion of Normandy.",
        "distractor1": "the organization of the United Nations.",
        "distractor2": "the Soviet war declaration on Japan in exchange for Soviet possession of the Kurile Islands.",
        "distractor3": "a self-determination agreement for the war-torn countries of Eastern Europe."
    },
    {
        "question": "Issued by President Roosevelt in 1941, Executive Order No. 8802?:",
        "correct_answer": "required defense industries to make jobs available without discrimination based on race, creed, color, or national origin.",
        "distractor1": "fully integrated the United States armed forces.",
        "distractor2": "assisted blacks attempting to move out of the South.",
        "distractor3": "created a presidential commission to study and recommend ways to alleviate wage discrimination based on race and sex."
    },
    {
        "question": "In waging war against Japan, the United States relied mainly on a strategy of?:",
        "correct_answer": " island hopping  from the South Pacific to within striking distance of Japan.",
        "distractor1": "heavy bombing from Chinese air bases.",
        "distractor2": "invading Japanese strongholds in Southeast Asia.",
        "distractor3": "fortifying China by transporting supplies from India over the Himalayan  hump. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following made the Soviet Union suspicious of the motives of the United States and Great Britain during World",
        "correct_answer": "the delay in opening the second front in Europe.",
        "distractor1": "the refusal to grant the Soviet Union lend-lease aid.",
        "distractor2": "the American monopoly on atomic bomb technology.",
        "distractor3": "the adoption of the Europe-first strategy.",
        "distractor4": "the failure of the West to accept changes in the borders of Poland."
    },
    {
        "question": "The development of the atomic bomb that was dropped on Hiroshima?:",
        "correct_answer": "was the responsibility of the Manhattan Project team of scientists and engineers at Los Alamos, NM.",
        "distractor1": "was opposed by most Americans.",
        "distractor2": "began in the spring of 1945.",
        "distractor3": "was the responsibility of a group of scientists headed by Albert Einstein code named Operation Overlord."
    },
    {
        "question": "At the Casablanca Conference in January 1943, the Allies agreed to?:",
        "correct_answer": "an invasion of Italy in the spring, invasion of France in 1944, and the concept of  unconditional surrender. ",
        "distractor1": "the division of Poland.",
        "distractor2": "fight until the world was made  safe for democracy. ",
        "distractor3": "the creation of a United Nations organization after the war."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which does NOT describe the internment of Japanese-Americans during World War II?:",
        "correct_answer": "outside California, there was strong public opposition to the internment policy.",
        "distractor1": "the Supreme Court upheld their evacuation from the West Coast.",
        "distractor2": "reparations were finally paid to evacuees about forty years after the end of the war.",
        "distractor3": "many if the evacuees were United States citizens."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Dumbarton Oaks Conference involved primarily?:",
        "correct_answer": "the formation of the United Nations.",
        "distractor1": "the trial and punishment of Nazi war criminals.",
        "distractor2": "the decision on whether or not to use the atomic bomb.",
        "distractor3": "startling revelations of the Nazi atrocities against the Jews.",
        "distractor4": "American plans for redrawing the map of Eastern Europe."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Truman used the atom bomb against Japan for all of the following reasons EXCEPT?:",
        "correct_answer": "he believed the bomb was an appropriate response to Pearl Harbor.",
        "distractor1": "his basic motivation was to save American lives.",
        "distractor2": "he believed the bomb's power would convince the Soviets not to challenge American supremacy after the war.",
        "distractor3": "he believed the use of the bomb would make a military invasion of Japan unnecessary."
    },
    {
        "question": "At the end of both World War I and World War II, the United States?:",
        "correct_answer": "entered a period of extreme anti-communism that led to the persecution of many suspected radicals.",
        "distractor1": "joined a multinational organization aimed at preserving world peace.",
        "distractor2": "formed military alliances with its allies to guard against invasion by mutual enemies.",
        "distractor3": "suffered through a recession that made the transition to peace time difficult."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city is paired with the geographical feature that directly contributed to its growth?",
        "correct_answer": "New Orleans   Mississippi River",
        "distractor1": "San Francisco   Rocky Mountains",
        "distractor2": "Pittsburgh   Hudson River",
        "distractor3": "Cleveland   Atlantic Coastal Plain"
    },
    {
        "question": "The best source of information for identifying the location of the major mountain ranges in the United States is:",
        "correct_answer": "an atlas",
        "distractor1": "an encyclopedia",
        "distractor2": "an almanac",
        "distractor3": "a dictionary"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the 1990 census, which two areas of the United States include the most densely populated parts of the nation?",
        "correct_answer": "the Northeast and southern California",
        "distractor1": "the Great Plains and Texas",
        "distractor2": "the South and the Rocky Mountain states",
        "distractor3": "the Appalachian states and the Midwest"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which geographic advantage did the United States gain by purchasing the Louisiana Territory from France in 1803?",
        "correct_answer": "full control of the Mississippi River",
        "distractor1": "warm-water ports on the Atlantic coast",
        "distractor2": "rich fishing areas in the Great Lakes",
        "distractor3": "vast coal reserves in the region west of Pennsylvania"
    },
    {
        "question": "Population data from the census of 2000 was used to determine the number of",
        "correct_answer": "electoral college votes from each state",
        "distractor1": "states in the Union",
        "distractor2": "Senators from each state",
        "distractor3": "Supreme Court justices"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which group benefited most from the United States acquisition of the port of New Orleans?",
        "correct_answer": "farmers in the Ohio River Valley",
        "distractor1": "Native American Indians in the Southwest",
        "distractor2": "fur trappers in the Columbia River Valley",
        "distractor3": "gold miners in northern California"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which geographic factor had the greatest influence on early patterns of industrialization in the United States?",
        "correct_answer": "availability of waterpower to operate machines",
        "distractor1": "scarcity of flat land on which to build factories",
        "distractor2": "shortages of timber and coal",
        "distractor3": "desire of workers to live in mild climates"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of map shows the most detailed information about Earth s natural features, such as rivers, lakes, and mountain ranges?",
        "correct_answer": "physical",
        "distractor1": "political",
        "distractor2": "demographic",
        "distractor3": "weather"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which region of the United States is correctly paired with an industry that is dominant in that region?",
        "correct_answer": "Great Plains   grain crops",
        "distractor1": "Southwest   timber",
        "distractor2": "Pacific Northwest   citrus crops",
        "distractor3": "Atlantic Coastal Plain   iron mining"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the early 1800 s, the need for a water route to help farmers ship their products to market was one reason for the",
        "correct_answer": "Louisiana Purchase",
        "distractor1": "Gadsden Purchase",
        "distractor2": "Mexican Cession",
        "distractor3": "Missouri Compromise"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which United States foreign policy action resulted from the close geographic relationship between the United States and Latin America?",
        "correct_answer": "Monroe Doctrine",
        "distractor1": "Truman Doctrine",
        "distractor2": "Marshall Plan",
        "distractor3": "Open Door policy"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the United States, regional differences in economic development are primarily due to",
        "correct_answer": "geographic factors in various parts of the nation",
        "distractor1": "settlement patterns of immigrant groups",
        "distractor2": "pressure from various religious groups",
        "distractor3": "state and federal election laws"
    },
    {
        "question": "Because of fertile land and a long growing season, plantations in the thirteen colonies developed in",
        "correct_answer": "the South",
        "distractor1": "New England",
        "distractor2": "the Middle Atlantic region",
        "distractor3": "the upper Mississippi River valley"
    },
    {
        "question": "What would be the best title for this map?",
        "correct_answer": "Colonial Trade Routes",
        "distractor1": "British Domination of the Americas",
        "distractor2": "Spanish Colonies in the New World",
        "distractor3": "The United States in 1750"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the best title for this series of maps?",
        "correct_answer": "Shifting Frontier of the United States",
        "distractor1": "Industrialization of the United States",
        "distractor2": "Sectional Conflicts in the United States",
        "distractor3": "Transportation Revolution in the United States"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which geographic feature is primarily responsible for the lowest population the area shown on the map?",
        "correct_answer": "Rocky Mountains",
        "distractor1": "Columbia River",
        "distractor2": "Pacific Ocean",
        "distractor3": "Mississippi River Valley"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which section of early 19th-century America was the plantation system an important feature?",
        "correct_answer": "the South",
        "distractor1": "New England",
        "distractor2": "the Middle Atlantic states",
        "distractor3": "the West"
    },
    {
        "question": "Acquiring New Orleans as part of the Louisiana Purchase was considered important to the development of the Mississippi and Ohio River valleys because the city",
        "correct_answer": "served as a port for American agricultural goods",
        "distractor1": "provided protection from attacks by the Spanish",
        "distractor2": "provided migrant workers for river valley farms",
        "distractor3": "served as the cultural center for the nation"
    },
    {
        "question": "Farmers in the Ohio River valley gained the greatest economic benefit when the United States acquired the",
        "correct_answer": "Louisiana Territory",
        "distractor1": "Oregon Territory",
        "distractor2": "Gadsden Purchase",
        "distractor3": "Mexican Cession"
    },
    {
        "question": "Since the late 1700s, the Mississippi River has been a vital waterway because it",
        "correct_answer": "provided farmers and merchants an outlet to the Gulf of Mexico",
        "distractor1": "divided the northern territories from the southern territories",
        "distractor2": "allowed American farmers direct access to Canadian markets",
        "distractor3": "connected the Great Lakes to the Atlantic Ocean"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the first half of the 1800s, geographic factors influenced the economy of New England by",
        "correct_answer": "promoting the growth of trade and manufacturing",
        "distractor1": "encouraging the establishment of large plantations",
        "distractor2": "increasing the region s reliance on slave labor",
        "distractor3": "supporting rice and indigo farming"
    },
    {
        "question": "The information on the map supports the conclusion that African American migration between 1940 and 1970 was mainly from the",
        "correct_answer": "south to the north",
        "distractor1": "urban areas to rural areas ",
        "distractor2": "Mountain states to the West Coast",
        "distractor3": "Sun Belt to the Great Plains"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Colonial Era, developments such as the New England town meetings and the establishment of the Virginia House of Burgesses represented",
        "correct_answer": "steps in the growth of representative democracy",
        "distractor1": "colonial attempts to build a strong national government",
        "distractor2": "efforts by the British to strengthen their control over the colonies",
        "distractor3": "early social reform movements"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the Declaration of Independence, the people have the right to alter or abolish a government if that government",
        "correct_answer": "violates natural rights",
        "distractor1": "is a limited monarchy",
        "distractor2": "becomes involved in entangling alliances",
        "distractor3": "favors one religion over another"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which fundamental political idea is expressed in the Declaration of Independence?",
        "correct_answer": "If the government denies its people certain basic rights, that government can be overthrown.",
        "distractor1": "The government should guarantee every citizen economic security.",
        "distractor2": "The central government and state governments should have equal power.",
        "distractor3": "Rulers derive their right to govern from God and are therefore bound to govern in the nation s best interest."
    },
    {
        "question": " The only representatives of the people of these colonies are persons chosen therein by themselves; and that no taxes ever have been, or can be constitutionally imposed on them but by their respective legislatures. ",
        "correct_answer": "Only the colonists  elected representatives should have the power to levy taxes.",
        "distractor1": "The colonial legislatures should be appointed by the English King with the consent of Parliament.",
        "distractor2": "The English King should have the right to tax the colonists.",
        "distractor3": "The colonists should be opposed to all taxation."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Mayflower Compact is important to the concept of a democratic society because it represents",
        "correct_answer": "a clear step toward self-government",
        "distractor1": "an effort by the colonists to use force to resist the King",
        "distractor2": "an early attempt to establish universal suffrage",
        "distractor3": "an attempt by the colonists to establish freedom of religion"
    },
    {
        "question": "The British system of mercantilism was opposed by many American colonists because it",
        "correct_answer": "placed restrictions on trading",
        "distractor1": "placed quotas on immigration",
        "distractor2": "discouraged the export of raw materials to England",
        "distractor3": "encouraged colonial manufacturing"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Mayflower Compact, House of Burgesses, and Fundamental Orders of Connecticut are all examples of the efforts of colonial Americans to",
        "correct_answer": "use democratic practices in government",
        "distractor1": "protest British land policies",
        "distractor2": "establish religious freedom",
        "distractor3": "overthrow British royal governors"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Mayflower Compact of 1620 is considered an important step in the development of democracy in America because it",
        "correct_answer": "expressed the importance of self-government",
        "distractor1": "established freedom of religion",
        "distractor2": "created the first colonial judiciary",
        "distractor3": "granted all males the right to vote"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the Revolutionary War period, Thomas Paine s Common Sense was important because it",
        "correct_answer": "convinced many Americans who had been undecided to support independence",
        "distractor1": "described a military plan for the defeat of England",
        "distractor2": "contained a detailed outline for a new form of government",
        "distractor3": "argued for the addition of a bill of rights to the Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Virginia House of Burgesses was important to the development of democracy in the thirteen colonies because it",
        "correct_answer": "provided an example of a representative form of government",
        "distractor1": "created the first written constitution in America",
        "distractor2": "provided for direct election of senators",
        "distractor3": "began the practice of legislative override of executive vetoes"
    },
    {
        "question": " It is not the cause of one poor printer, nor of New York alone, which you are now trying. No!",
        "correct_answer": "freedom of the press",
        "distractor1": "trial by jury",
        "distractor2": "equal voting rights",
        "distractor3": "protection of private property"
    },
    {
        "question": "The pamphlet Common Sense, by Thomas Paine, aided the American cause in the Revolutionary War because it",
        "correct_answer": "persuaded individuals who were undecided to support independence",
        "distractor1": "convinced France to join in the fight against England",
        "distractor2": "led to the repeal of the Stamp Act",
        "distractor3": "created a new system of government for the United States"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conclusion about the American Revolutionary War is most clearly supported by information in this chart?",
        "correct_answer": "The thirteen colonies had few, but important advantages in the war with England.",
        "distractor1": "England had few advantages in a war with her American colonies.",
        "distractor2": "The thirteen colonies had more advantages than disadvantages upon entering the war.",
        "distractor3": "England did not believe that the thirteen colonies were worth the expense of a war."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which important reason for the American victory in the Revolutionary War is missing from the chart?",
        "correct_answer": "aid from foreign nations",
        "distractor1": "naval superiority of the thirteen colonies",
        "distractor2": "control of railroads and canals",
        "distractor3": "greater number of Indian allies"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Mayflower Compact and the House of Burgesses were important to the development of democracy in colonial America because they",
        "correct_answer": "promoted self-government",
        "distractor1": "expanded freedom of religion",
        "distractor2": "protected private ownership of property",
        "distractor3": "granted voting rights to all white males"
    },
    {
        "question": "Court decisions in the trial of John Peter Zenger (1735) and the case of New York Times Co. v. United States (1971) strengthened",
        "correct_answer": "freedom of the press",
        "distractor1": "freedom of religion",
        "distractor2": "due process rights",
        "distractor3": "the right to counsel"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which heading best completes the partial outline below?",
        "correct_answer": "Colonial Responses to British Mercantile Policies",
        "distractor1": "Protests Against Slavery in the American Colonies",
        "distractor2": "British Parliamentary Actions to Punish Colonial Americans",
        "distractor3": "Colonial Attempts to End the British Policy of Salutary Neglect"
    },
    {
        "question": "In its economic relationship with its North American colonies, Great Britain followed the principles of 18th-century mercantilism by",
        "correct_answer": "limiting the colonies  trade with other nations",
        "distractor1": "outlawing the African slave trade",
        "distractor2": "encouraging the development of manufacturing in the colonies",
        "distractor3": "establishing laws against business monopolies"
    },
    {
        "question": ". . . I challenge the warmest advocate [supporter] for reconciliation, to shew [show], a single",
        "correct_answer": "mercantilism",
        "distractor1": "capitalism",
        "distractor2": "direct democracy",
        "distractor3": "representative government"
    },
    {
        "question": "A major argument for American independence found in the Declaration of Independence was that the British",
        "correct_answer": "deprived Americans of their natural rights",
        "distractor1": "stopped participating in the slave trade",
        "distractor2": "refused to sell products to Americans",
        "distractor3": "censored American representatives in Parliament"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is most accurate about the movement for independence in the thirteen colonies?",
        "correct_answer": "Protests against British colonial policies gradually led to demands for independence.",
        "distractor1": "The independence movement began soon after the founding of the Plymouth Colony.",
        "distractor2": "The King of England required the colonists to become economically self-sufficient.",
        "distractor3": "The movement for independence was equally strong in all of the colonies."
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the Declaration of Independence, the fundamental purpose of government is to",
        "correct_answer": "protect people s natural rights",
        "distractor1": "equalize opportunities for all citizens",
        "distractor2": "provide for the defense of the nation",
        "distractor3": "establish a system of free public education"
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the principles stated in the Declaration of Independence is that government should",
        "correct_answer": "be based upon the consent of the governed",
        "distractor1": "guarantee economic equality among citizens",
        "distractor2": "have unlimited power to rule the people",
        "distractor3": "be led by educated citizens"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the colonial period, the British Parliament used the policy of mercantilism to",
        "correct_answer": "limit manufacturing in America",
        "distractor1": "prevent criticism of royal policies",
        "distractor2": "deny representation to the colonists",
        "distractor3": "force colonists to worship in the Anglican Church"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Mayflower Compact and the Virginia House of Burgesses are examples of",
        "correct_answer": "steps toward representative government",
        "distractor1": "equal opportunities for women during the colonial period",
        "distractor2": "economic agreements between the colonists and Native American Indians",
        "distractor3": "limitations placed on colonial Americans by the British government"
    },
    {
        "question": "The system shown in the diagram was developed under the Articles of Confederation in order to",
        "correct_answer": "provide an orderly system of development for the Northwest Territory",
        "distractor1": "divide lands seized from the Loyalists",
        "distractor2": "remove Native American Indians to areas west of the Appalachian Mountains",
        "distractor3": "extend slavery as the nation grew"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which area did good harbors, abundant forests, rocky soil, and a short growing season most influence the colonial economy?",
        "correct_answer": "New England colonies",
        "distractor1": "Southern colonies",
        "distractor2": "Middle Atlantic region",
        "distractor3": "Northwest Territory"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Mayflower Compact, New England town meetings, and the Virginia House of Burgesses are examples of",
        "correct_answer": "early colonial efforts in self-government",
        "distractor1": "colonial protests against British taxation",
        "distractor2": "governments imposed by Parliament",
        "distractor3": "attempts to limit democracy"
    },
    {
        "question": "The British benefited from their mercantilist relationship with the American colonies primarily by",
        "correct_answer": "buying raw materials from the colonies and selling them finished products",
        "distractor1": "supporting the growth of colonial industries",
        "distractor2": "prohibiting colonists from fishing and fur trading",
        "distractor3": "taking large amounts of gold and silver from the southern colonies"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main reason Great Britain established the Proclamation Line of 1763 was to",
        "correct_answer": "avoid conflicts between American colonists and Native American Indians",
        "distractor1": "make a profit by selling the land west of the Appalachian Mountains",
        "distractor2": "prevent American industrial development in the Ohio River valley",
        "distractor3": "allow Canada to control the Great Lakes region"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Declaration of Independence (1776) has had a major influence on peoples throughout the world because it",
        "correct_answer": "provides justification for revolting against unjust governments",
        "distractor1": "guarantees universal suffrage",
        "distractor2": "establishes a basic set of laws for every nation",
        "distractor3": "describes the importance of a strong central government"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 1780 s, mqany  Americans distrusted a strong central government. This distrust is best shown by the",
        "correct_answer": "plan of government set up by the Articles of Confederation",
        "distractor1": "lack of debate over the ratification of the United States Constitution",
        "distractor2": "development of a Federal court system",
        "distractor3": "constitutional provision for a strong President"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"We hold these truths to be self-evident: That all men are created equal; that they are endowed by their creator with certain unalienable rights; that among these are life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness; . . .\"",
        "correct_answer": "reflections of the philosophies of the European Enlightenment.",
        "distractor1": "limitations of the principles underlying most European governments of the 1700 s.",
        "distractor2": "adaptations of the laws of Spanish colonial governments in North America.",
        "distractor3": "adoptions of rules used by the Holy Roman Empire."
    },
    {
        "question": "The authors of the United States Constitution believed that the voice of the people should be heard frequently. Which part of the Government was instituted to respond most directly to the will of the people?",
        "correct_answer": "House of Representatives",
        "distractor1": "Senate",
        "distractor2": "Supreme Court",
        "distractor3": "Presidency"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the United States, the use of implied powers, the amending process, and Supreme Court interpretations have resulted in",
        "correct_answer": "the Constitution being adapted to fit changing times",
        "distractor1": "a general loss of individual rights",
        "distractor2": "a strengthening of the principle of separation of powers",
        "distractor3": "the limiting of Presidential power in domestic affairs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which quotation from the United States Constitution provides for a Federal system of government?",
        "correct_answer": " The powers not delegated to the United States . . . are reserved to the states . . . ",
        "distractor1": " He shall have power . . . with the advice and consent of the Senate, . . . and . . . shall appoint . . . ",
        "distractor2": " Every bill . . . shall, before it becomes a law, be presented to the President of the United States; . . .\"",
        "distractor3": " Full faith and credit shall be given in each state to the public acts, records, and judicial proceedings of every other state. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The system of checks and balances is best illustrated by the power of",
        "correct_answer": "the President to veto a bill passed by Congress",
        "distractor1": "Congress to censure one of its members",
        "distractor2": "a governor to send the National Guard to stop a riot",
        "distractor3": "state and Federal gov-ernments to levy and collect taxes"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Presidential action is an example of the unwritten constitution?",
        "correct_answer": "consulting with the Cabinet",
        "distractor1": "appointing Justices to the Supreme Court",
        "distractor2": "granting pardons for Federal crimes",
        "distractor3": "submitting a treaty to the Senate for ratification"
    },
    {
        "question": "A lasting impact of the United States Supreme Court under Chief Justice John Marshall is that the Court s decisions",
        "correct_answer": "expanded the power of the Federal Government",
        "distractor1": "extended the Bill of Rights to enslaved persons",
        "distractor2": "restricted the authority of Congress",
        "distractor3": "promoted the views of the President"
    },
    {
        "question": "The major role of political parties in the United States is to",
        "correct_answer": "nominate candidates for public office and conduct campaigns",
        "distractor1": "protect the American public from corrupt public officials",
        "distractor2": "insure that free and honest elections are held",
        "distractor3": "meet constitutional requirements for choosing the President"
    },
    {
        "question": "Adherence to a strict interpretation of the Constitution would have prevented President Thomas Jefferson from",
        "correct_answer": "making the Louisiana Purchase",
        "distractor1": "writing  State of the Union  messages",
        "distractor2": "receiving ambassadors",
        "distractor3": "commissioning military officers"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which factor has made the strongest contribution to the development of religious freedom in the United States?",
        "correct_answer": "Guarantees in the Constitution have encouraged religious expression and toleration.",
        "distractor1": "Most citizens have shared the same religious beliefs.",
        "distractor2": "Religious groups have remained politically unified.",
        "distractor3": "School prayer has been ruled constitutional by the Supreme Court."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which phrase from the Declaration of Independence most clearly reflects the idea that the people are the source of government?",
        "correct_answer": " . . . deriving their just powers from the consent of the governed. . . ",
        "distractor1": " . . . that all men are created equal,... ",
        "distractor2": " . .. all men are . . . endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable rights",
        "distractor3": " . . . governments long established should not be changed for light and transient causes . . ."
    },
    {
        "question": "One way in which the United States Constitution differed from the Articles of Confederation was that the Constitution",
        "correct_answer": "created a national government having three branches",
        "distractor1": "provided for the direct election of the President by the voters",
        "distractor2": "made the amendment process more difficult",
        "distractor3": "increased the powers of the states"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the Constitutional Convention of 1787, delegates from the small states most strongly supported the idea of",
        "correct_answer": "equal representation for the states in the national legislature",
        "distractor1": "establishing a strong national executive",
        "distractor2": "levying taxes on exports",
        "distractor3": "popular election of Senators"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which argument did the authors of the United States Constitution use when they insisted that revenue bills originate in the House of Representatives?",
        "correct_answer": "Frequent elections would make members of the House more responsive to the wishes of the voters.",
        "distractor1": "Members of the House would have a superior understanding of economics.",
        "distractor2": "The national budget should be determined solely by the House of Representatives.",
        "distractor3": "Political parties would have less influence on Members of the House than on Senators."
    },
    {
        "question": "One way in which the authors of the Constitution tried to create  limited government  was by providing for",
        "correct_answer": "a division of power between the national and state governments",
        "distractor1": "a loyal opposition through a two-party system",
        "distractor2": "the establishment of naturalization laws",
        "distractor3": "the popular election of Federal judges"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which action is an example of the unwritten constitution?",
        "correct_answer": "selection of a Presidential candidate by a nominating convention",
        "distractor1": "the Senate ratifying a peace treaty",
        "distractor2": "Congress passing a law regulating interstate commerce",
        "distractor3": "the President removing an Army officer from command for insubordination"
    },
    {
        "question": "The elastic clause, the amending process, and judicial review are all methods by which",
        "correct_answer": "the Constitution may be adapted to meet changing conditions",
        "distractor1": "Congress may check the power of the executive branch",
        "distractor2": "the wording of the original Constitution may be altered",
        "distractor3": "state governments may limit the power of the Federal Government"
    },
    {
        "question": " The most stringent protection of free speech would not protect a man in falsely shouting fire in a theater and causing a panic.   -Justice Oliver Wendell Holmes   ",
        "correct_answer": "Constitutional protections of liberty are not absolute.",
        "distractor1": "The needs of the government are more important than civil liberties.",
        "distractor2": "The Supreme Court can eliminate freedoms listed in the Bill of Rights.",
        "distractor3": "The Bill of Rights does not safeguard individual liberties."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which action was necessary to change from the indirect to the direct election of United States Senators?",
        "correct_answer": "ratification of a constitutional amendment",
        "distractor1": "passage of a Federal law",
        "distractor2": "a Supreme Court decision",
        "distractor3": "a national referendum"
    },
    {
        "question": "The  Dred Scott  decision on the issue of slavery upheld the Southern viewpoint that",
        "correct_answer": "Congress could not pass a law depriving territorial residents of their property",
        "distractor1": "the power of the Supreme Court does not extend to cases of race",
        "distractor2": "a national vote should be held to decide the legality of slavery",
        "distractor3": "the economic well-being of the western states depended on slave labor"
    },
    {
        "question": "The decisions of the United States Supreme Court in  Miranda v. Arizona ,  Gideon v. Wainwright , and  Escobedo v. Illinois  all advanced the",
        "correct_answer": "rights of accused persons",
        "distractor1": "voting rights of minorities",
        "distractor2": "guarantees of free speech and press",
        "distractor3": "principle of separation of church and state"
    },
    {
        "question": "An immediate result of the Supreme Court decision in  Schechter Poultry Corporation v. United States  (1935) and  United States v. Butler  (1936) was that",
        "correct_answer": "some aspects of the New Deal were declared unconstitutional",
        "distractor1": "State governments took over relief agencies",
        "distractor2": ") Congress was forced to abandon efforts to improve the economy",
        "distractor3": "the constitutional authority of the President was greatly expanded"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under Chief Justice Earl Warren, the Supreme Court was considered \"activist\" because of its",
        "correct_answer": "expansion of individual rights in criminal cases",
        "distractor1": "reluctance to overturn state laws",
        "distractor2": "insistence on restricting freedom of speech to spoken words",
        "distractor3": "refusal to reconsider the issues of the Plessy v. Ferguson case"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"clear and present danger\" ruling of the Supreme Court in  Schenck v. United States  illustrates the continuing conflict between",
        "correct_answer": "free speech and governmental authority",
        "distractor1": "the use of search warrants and the rights of the accused",
        "distractor2": "state powers and Federal powers",
        "distractor3": "religious freedom and separation of church and state"
    },
    {
        "question": " The most stringent protection of free speech would not protect a man in falsely shouting fire in a theater and causing a panic.\" -Justice Oliver Wendell Holmes",
        "correct_answer": "Constitutional protections of liberty are not absolute.",
        "distractor1": "The needs of the government are more important than civil liberties.",
        "distractor2": "The Supreme Court can eliminate freedoms listed in the Bill of Rights.",
        "distractor3": "The Bill of Rights does not safeguard individual liberties."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which generalization is consistent with the ruling of the United States Supreme Court in  Schenck v. United States ?",
        "correct_answer": "Individual rights can be limited in the national interest",
        "distractor1": "The freedoms guaranteed in the Bill of Rights are virtually unlimited",
        "distractor2": "Government has the right to suspend any rights at any time.",
        "distractor3": "The balance between individual rights and the general social welfare almost always favors individual rights."
    },
    {
        "question": "The significance of the Supreme Court case  Marbury v. Madison  is that the decision",
        "correct_answer": "established the power of judicial review",
        "distractor1": "advanced civil rights for minorities",
        "distractor2": "upheld the constitutionality of a national bank",
        "distractor3": "limited Presidential control of foreign policy"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Separate educational facilities are inherently unequal.\"  - Brown v. Board of Education  ",
        "correct_answer": "require the integration of public schools",
        "distractor1": "establish affirmative action programs in higher education",
        "distractor2": "desegregate the armed forces and the military academies",
        "distractor3": "force states to spend an equal amount on each public school student"
    },
    {
        "question": "The decision of the United States Supreme Court in Marbury v. Madison (1803) established the power of the",
        "correct_answer": "Supreme Court to determine the constitutionality of laws",
        "distractor1": "House of Representatives to impeach the president",
        "distractor2": "Congress to override a presidential veto",
        "distractor3": "president to veto congressional legislation"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the result of many of the Supreme Court decisions made under Chief Justice John Marshall between 1801 and 1835?",
        "correct_answer": "The federal government was strengthened.",
        "distractor1": "The system of slavery was weakened.",
        "distractor2": "The rights of workers were supported.",
        "distractor3": "Antitrust laws were upheld."
    },
    {
        "question": "Supreme Court decisions in Mapp v. Ohio, Gideon v. Wainwright, and Miranda v. Arizona affected individual liberties by",
        "correct_answer": "expanding the constitutional rights of people accused of crimes",
        "distractor1": "eliminating the poll tax as a voting requirement",
        "distractor2": "preventing the use of organized prayer in public schools",
        "distractor3": "requiring equal pay for men and women performing the same job"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a result of the Supreme Court ruling in Miranda v. Arizona (1966), a person accused of a crime is entitled to",
        "correct_answer": "a reading of his or her rights at the time of arrest",
        "distractor1": "a speedy trial",
        "distractor2": "reasonable bail",
        "distractor3": "protection against cruel or unusual punishment"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court decisions in Mapp v. Ohio, Gideon v. Wainright, and Miranda v. Arizona all expanded",
        "correct_answer": "rights of the accused",
        "distractor1": "integration of public facilities",
        "distractor2": "presidential powers",
        "distractor3": "equality in the workplace"
    },
    {
        "question": "The police enter an individual s home without invitation or a warrant and seize evidence to be used against the individual. Which Supreme Court decision may be used to rule this evidence inadmissible in court?",
        "correct_answer": "Mapp v. Ohio",
        "distractor1": "Baker v. Carr",
        "distractor2": "Gideon v. Wainwright",
        "distractor3": "Roe v. Wade"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court decisions in Gideon v. Wainwright (1963) and Miranda v. Arizona (1966) have been criticized because these rulings",
        "correct_answer": "expanded the rights of the accused",
        "distractor1": "granted more powers to federal judges",
        "distractor2": "lengthened prison sentences for the guilty",
        "distractor3": "reinstated the use of capital punishment"
    },
    {
        "question": "The case of John Peter Zenger (1735) and New York Times Co. v. United States (1971) both involved a government s attempt to limit",
        "correct_answer": "freedom of the press",
        "distractor1": "freedom of religion",
        "distractor2": "the right to bear arms",
        "distractor3": "the right to counsel"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court cases of Tinker v. Des Moines and New Jersey v. TLO involved the issue of",
        "correct_answer": "the rights of students in school",
        "distractor1": "freedom of the press",
        "distractor2": "freedom of religion",
        "distractor3": "the rights of prison inmates"
    },
    {
        "question": "The decisions of the United States Supreme Court in Tinker v. Des Moines and New York Times Co. v. United States were based on interpretations of the",
        "correct_answer": "rights guaranteed by the 1st amendment",
        "distractor1": "meaning of a republican form of government",
        "distractor2": "powers delegated specifically to Congress",
        "distractor3": "president s right to executive privilege"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court decision in Roe v. Wade (1973) was based on the constitutional principle of",
        "correct_answer": "right to privacy",
        "distractor1": "protection of property rights",
        "distractor2": "freedom of speech",
        "distractor3": "freedom of religion"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court decisions in New York Times Co. v. United States (1971) and United States v. Nixon (1974) reinforced the principle that the president of the United States",
        "correct_answer": "is not above the law",
        "distractor1": "has unlimited use of the veto power",
        "distractor2": "is protected from unfair media criticism",
        "distractor3": "may not be convicted of a crime"
    },
    {
        "question": "When John Marshall was Chief Justice, United States Supreme Court decisions tended to strengthen the power of",
        "correct_answer": "the National Government",
        "distractor1": "state and local governments",
        "distractor2": "labor unions",
        "distractor3": "trusts and monopolies"
    },
    {
        "question": "Alexander Hamilton s argument that the government has the power to create a National Bank is based on which part of the Constitution?",
        "correct_answer": "the elastic clause",
        "distractor1": "the Preamble",
        "distractor2": "guarantees to the States",
        "distractor3": "the Bill of Rights"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"All communities divide themselves into the few and the many. The first are the rich and well born, the other the mass of the people. . . . The people are turbulent and changing. . . . Give therefore to the first class a distinct permanent share in the government. They will check the unsteadiness of the second.\"",
        "correct_answer": "the common people cannot be trusted to run a stable government",
        "distractor1": "the will of the majority should guide public policy",
        "distractor2": "wealthy people are too preoccupied to rule well",
        "distractor3": "poorer people must work harder to gain access to economic and political power"
    },
    {
        "question": "Actions and policies of the Government under President George Washington generally resulted in the",
        "correct_answer": "strengthening of the Federal Government",
        "distractor1": "establishment of strong political ties with other nations",
        "distractor2": "liberation of many enslaved persons",
        "distractor3": "failure to create a sound financial program for the country"
    },
    {
        "question": "  Speaker A:  \"We must take action even if we are not sure it will work. To do nothing to stop them would be a repeat of the Munich mistake.\"",
        "correct_answer": "Speaker D",
        "distractor1": "Speaker A",
        "distractor2": "Speaker B",
        "distractor3": "Speaker C"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Our true policy is to steer clear of permanent alliances . . . .\"",
        "correct_answer": "European military conflicts",
        "distractor1": "international trade",
        "distractor2": "the race for overseas colonies",
        "distractor3": "westward expansion"
    },
    {
        "question": "The significance of the Supreme Court case  Marbury v. Madison  is that the decision",
        "correct_answer": "established the power of judicial review",
        "distractor1": "advanced civil rights for minorities",
        "distractor2": "upheld the constitutionality of a national bank",
        "distractor3": "limited Presidential control of foreign policy"
    },
    {
        "question": "Alexander Hamilton urged Congress to pass a protective tariff to encourage the growth of",
        "correct_answer": "manufacturing",
        "distractor1": "labor unions",
        "distractor2": "agriculture",
        "distractor3": "slavery"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the result of many of the Supreme Court decisions made under Chief Justice John Marshall between 1801 and 1835?",
        "correct_answer": "The federal government was strengthened.",
        "distractor1": "The system of slavery was weakened.",
        "distractor2": "The rights of workers were supported.",
        "distractor3": "Antitrust laws were upheld."
    },
    {
        "question": " It is emphatically the province and duty of the judicial department to say what the law is. . . . ",
        "correct_answer": "the power of judicial review belongs to the courts",
        "distractor1": "courts must abide by a strict interpretation of the Constitution",
        "distractor2": "federal laws must be approved by the courts before they can take effect",
        "distractor3": "the judicial branch must have a role in the amendment process"
    },
    {
        "question": "Alexander Hamilton s financial plan helped to establish the credit of the United States government by",
        "correct_answer": "providing for the payment of the nation s debts",
        "distractor1": "taxing only the people most able to pay",
        "distractor2": "favoring agriculture over industry",
        "distractor3": "encouraging spending for national defense"
    },
    {
        "question": "One factor that led to the formation of the first two political parties in the United States in the 1790s was the conflict over the",
        "correct_answer": "distribution of power between the federal and state governments",
        "distractor1": "spread of slavery into the western territories",
        "distractor2": "control of interstate commerce",
        "distractor3": "acquisition of lands from France and Spain"
    },
    {
        "question": "One major reason that Alexander Hamilton proposed a national bank was to",
        "correct_answer": "improve the economic position of the United States government",
        "distractor1": "help state governments collect taxes",
        "distractor2": "make loans available to owners of small farms",
        "distractor3": "reduce foreign investment in the United States"
    },
    {
        "question": "A major reason the Antifederalists opposed the ratification of the United States Constitution was because the Constitution",
        "correct_answer": "changed the balance of power between the state and national governments",
        "distractor1": "created a national bank",
        "distractor2": "lacked a provision for a federal court system",
        "distractor3": "failed to provide for the direct election of members of the House of Representatives"
    },
    {
        "question": "President George Washington pursued a foreign policy of neutrality during his administration primarily because he believed that",
        "correct_answer": "the United States needed time to gain economic and military strength",
        "distractor1": "treaties were prohibited by the Constitution",
        "distractor2": "the United States should not expand by force",
        "distractor3": "alliances should be established with both France and England"
    },
    {
        "question": "At times, the United States Government has passed protective tariffs to",
        "correct_answer": "help the nation s manufacturers",
        "distractor1": "encourage foreign trade",
        "distractor2": "reduce the cost of consumer goods",
        "distractor3": "improve the quality of goods"
    },
    {
        "question": " . . . the American continents, by the free and independent condition which they have assumed",
        "correct_answer": "Theodore Roosevelt",
        "distractor1": "Abraham Lincoln",
        "distractor2": "Harry Truman",
        "distractor3": "Richard Nixon"
    },
    {
        "question": "A major reason for the issuance of the Monroe Doctrine (1823) was to",
        "correct_answer": "prevent further European colonization in the Caribbean region",
        "distractor1": "discourage United States trade with Latin America",
        "distractor2": "defend the Panama Canal from Great Britain",
        "distractor3": "provide economic aid to Latin American nations"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the presidency of Andrew Jackson, the spoils system resulted in",
        "correct_answer": "elected officials rewarding their supporters with government jobs",
        "distractor1": "federal laws being nullified by the states",
        "distractor2": "all free males being given the right to vote",
        "distractor3": "the end of political corruption in the federal government"
    },
    {
        "question": "One way in which the Kentucky and Virginia Resolutions (1798) and the South Carolina Ordinance of Nullification (1832) are similar is that each",
        "correct_answer": "claimed that individual states have the right to interpret federal laws",
        "distractor1": "formed part of the unwritten constitution",
        "distractor2": "supported the federal government s power to declare war",
        "distractor3": "provided a way for new states to enter the Union"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the early 1800s, which factor contributed the most to the start of the Industrial Revolution in the United States?",
        "correct_answer": "an abundance of natural resources",
        "distractor1": "a restriction on European immigration",
        "distractor2": "the end of the slave labor system",
        "distractor3": "the availability of electricity"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was an immediate effect of the completion of the Erie Canal in 1825?",
        "correct_answer": "Farmers could more easily ship grain to eastern markets.",
        "distractor1": "Prices increased for food products along the Atlantic Coast.",
        "distractor2": "A territorial conflict began with Canada over the Great Lakes.",
        "distractor3": "Railroads were forced to reduce their shipping rates."
    },
    {
        "question": "The legal basis for the United States purchase of the Louisiana Territory was the",
        "correct_answer": "power granted to the President to make treaties",
        "distractor1": "President s power as Commander in Chief",
        "distractor2": "authority of Congress to declare war",
        "distractor3": "Senate s duty to approve the appointment of ambassadors"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Compromise Enables Maine and Missouri To Enter Union\" (1820)",
        "correct_answer": "extension of slavery",
        "distractor1": "enactment of protective tariffs",
        "distractor2": "voting rights for minorities",
        "distractor3": "universal public education"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Louisiana Purchase had great geographic significance for the United States because it",
        "correct_answer": "focused the United States on westward expansion",
        "distractor1": "reduced British control of North America",
        "distractor2": "extended United States control over Mexico",
        "distractor3": "decreased tensions with Native American Indians"
    },
    {
        "question": "The phrase  by military conquest, treaty, and purchase  best describes the",
        "correct_answer": "methods used to expand the territory of the United States",
        "distractor1": "steps in the growth of American industry",
        "distractor2": "major parts of President Woodrow Wilson s Fourteen Points",
        "distractor3": "causes of the United States entry into the Korean War"
    },
    {
        "question": "When President Thomas Jefferson acquired the Louisiana Territory from France, he demonstrated that he had modified his belief that",
        "correct_answer": "the Constitution should be strictly interpreted",
        "distractor1": "the federal government should limit individual rights",
        "distractor2": "adding territory would lead to regional rivalries",
        "distractor3": "commercial development was the main goal of the federal government"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the early 1800s, the United States placed few restrictions on immigration because",
        "correct_answer": "the industrial economy was creating new jobs",
        "distractor1": "the Constitution did not allow restrictions",
        "distractor2": "labor unions welcomed the new workers",
        "distractor3": "southern landowners needed additional workers"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before the Civil War, the principle of popular sovereignty was proposed as a means of",
        "correct_answer": "deciding the legalization of slavery in a new state",
        "distractor1": "allowing states to secede from the Union",
        "distractor2": "permitting voters to nullify federal laws",
        "distractor3": "overturning unpopular decisions of the Supreme Court"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which geographic advantage did the United States gain by purchasing the Louisiana Territory from France in 1803?",
        "correct_answer": "full control of the Mississippi River",
        "distractor1": "warm-water ports on the Atlantic coast",
        "distractor2": "rich fishing areas in the Great Lakes",
        "distractor3": "vast coal reserves in the region west of Pennsylvania"
    },
    {
        "question": "As the United States acquired more land between 1803 and 1850, controversy over these territories focused on the",
        "correct_answer": "expansion of slavery",
        "distractor1": "need for schools and colleges",
        "distractor2": "failure to conserve natural resources",
        "distractor3": "construction of transcontinental railroads"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Seneca Falls Convention of 1848 was mainly concerned with",
        "correct_answer": "expanding women s rights",
        "distractor1": "ending slavery in all the states",
        "distractor2": "reducing consumption of alcoholic beverages",
        "distractor3": "improving treatment of the mentally ill"
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1862, the Homestead Act and the Pacific Railway Act were passed primarily to",
        "correct_answer": "develop the Midwest and western parts of the country",
        "distractor1": "achieve Northern victory in the Civil War",
        "distractor2": "improve the lives of freed slaves",
        "distractor3": "expand overseas markets to Asia and Europe"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Louisiana Purchase initially presented a dilemma for President Thomas Jefferson because he believed it would",
        "correct_answer": "violate his strict constructionist view of the Constitution",
        "distractor1": "lead to war with Great Britain",
        "distractor2": "bankrupt the new nation",
        "distractor3": "force Native American Indians off their lands"
    },
    {
        "question": "The rapid westward migration caused by the discovery of gold in California led directly to",
        "correct_answer": "the adoption of the Compromise of 1850",
        "distractor1": "the start of the Civil War",
        "distractor2": "increased trade through the Panama Canal",
        "distractor3": "control of the United States Senate by the slave states"
    },
    {
        "question": "Manifest Destiny was used to justify an American desire to",
        "correct_answer": "expand the United States to the Pacific Ocean",
        "distractor1": "limit the number of immigrants entering the country",
        "distractor2": "control the area located east of the Appalachian Mountains",
        "distractor3": "warn European countries against colonizing Latin America"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 1850s, the phrase  Bleeding Kansas  was used to describe clashes between",
        "correct_answer": "proslavery and antislavery groups",
        "distractor1": "Spanish landowners and new American settlers",
        "distractor2": "Chinese and Irish railroad workers",
        "distractor3": "Native American Indians and white settlers"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which argument did President Abraham Lincoln use against the secession of the Southern States?",
        "correct_answer": "The government was a union of people and not of states.",
        "distractor1": "Slavery was not profitable",
        "distractor2": "The Southern States did not permit their people to vote on secession.",
        "distractor3": "As the Commander in Chief, he had the duty to defend the United States against foreign invasion."
    },
    {
        "question": "The abolitionist movement, the women s suffrage movement, and the 1960 s civil rights movement are all examples of reform efforts that",
        "correct_answer": "developed significant popular support",
        "distractor1": "succeeded without causing major controversy",
        "distractor2": "achieved their goals without government action",
        "distractor3": "failed to affect the nation as a whole"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement best explains President Abraham Lincoln s justification for the Civil War?",
        "correct_answer": "President Lincoln s oath of office required him to defend and preserve the Union.",
        "distractor1": "As an abolitionist, President Lincoln wanted to end slavery in the United States.",
        "distractor2": "President Lincoln wanted to keep the South economically dependent on the industrial North.",
        "distractor3": "To keep the support of Great Britain and France, President Lincoln had to try to end slavery immediately."
    },
    {
        "question": "A major result of the Civil War was that the",
        "correct_answer": "Federal Government s power over the States was strengthened",
        "distractor1": "economic system of the South came to dominate the United States economy",
        "distractor2": "members of Congress from Southern States gained control of the legislative branch",
        "distractor3": "nation s industrial development came to a standstill"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sectional differences developed in the United States largely because",
        "correct_answer": "economic conditions and interests in each region varied",
        "distractor1": "the Federal Government adopted a policy of neutrality",
        "distractor2": "only northerners were represented at the Constitutional Convention",
        "distractor3": "early Presidents favored urban areas over rural areas"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"By the 1850 s, the Constitution, originally framed as an instrument of national unity, had become a source of sectional discord.\"",
        "correct_answer": "vast differences of opinion existed over the issue of States rights",
        "distractor1": "the Federal Government had become more interested in foreign affairs than in domestic problems",
        "distractor2": "the Constitution had no provisions for governing new territories",
        "distractor3": "the Southern States continued to import slaves"
    },
    {
        "question": "Early in his Presidency, Abraham Lincoln declared that his primary goal as President was to",
        "correct_answer": "preserve the Union",
        "distractor1": "enforce the Emancipation Proclamation",
        "distractor2": "end slavery throughout the entire country",
        "distractor3": "encourage sectionalism"
    },
    {
        "question": "The rulings of the Supreme Court in  Dred Scott v. Sanford  (1857),  Plessy v. Ferguson  (1896), and  Korematsu v. United States  (1944) all demonstrate that the Supreme Court has",
        "correct_answer": "sometimes failed to protect the rights of minorities",
        "distractor1": "continued to extend voting rights to minorities",
        "distractor2": "protected itself from internal dissent",
        "distractor3": "often imposed restrictions on free speech during wartime"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Compromise Enables Maine and Missouri To Enter Union\" (1820)",
        "correct_answer": "extension of slavery",
        "distractor1": "enactment of protective tariffs",
        "distractor2": "voting rights for minorities",
        "distractor3": "universal public education"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before the Civil War, slavery expanded in the South rather than in the North because",
        "correct_answer": "geographic conditions in the South encouraged the development of large plantations",
        "distractor1": "the Constitution contained a clause that outlawed the importation of slaves into the Northern states",
        "distractor2": "Congress passed a law forbidding slavery in the North",
        "distractor3": "Northern states passed affirmative action legislation"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which phrase best completes the title for the partial outline shown below?",
        "correct_answer": "Secession of Southern States from the Union",
        "distractor1": "Start of the Revolutionary War",
        "distractor2": "Adoption of the Bill of Rights",
        "distractor3": "Failure of the Whiskey Rebellion"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Although important strides were made, Reconstruction failed to provide lasting guarantees of the civil rights of the freedmen.  Which evidence best supports this statement",
        "correct_answer": "passage of Jim Crow laws in the latter part of the 19th century",
        "distractor1": "ratification of the 13th, 14th, and 15th amendments",
        "distractor2": "refusal of Southern States to allow sharecropping",
        "distractor3": "passage of the Civil Rights Acts of 1866"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about the philosophies of Booker T. Washington and W.E.B. Du Bois is most accurate?",
        "correct_answer": "They differed as to the best way that African Americans could effectively achieve equality.",
        "distractor1": "Both demanded programs that would provide for immediate social equality.",
        "distractor2": "Both believed that vocational training would provide the most important kind of education for African Americans.",
        "distractor3": "Neither wanted the Federal Government to play a major role in protecting the civil rights of African Americans."
    },
    {
        "question": "\"[Buffalo hunters] have done more in the last two years, and will do more in the next year, to settle the . . . Indian question than the entire regular army has done in the last thirty years. . . . For the sake of peace let them kill, skin, and sell until the buffalo are destroyed.     General Philip Sheridan   ",
        "correct_answer": "The disappearance of their economic base helped drive Native American Indians onto reservations.",
        "distractor1": "Native American Indians were granted farmland under the Homestead Act.",
        "distractor2": "Many Native American Indians moved to Eastern cities to work in factories.",
        "distractor3": "Most Native American Indians migrated to Canada to find new ways to earn a living."
    },
    {
        "question": "The passage of the Homestead Act and the completion of the transcontinental railroad helped to fulfill the United States commitment to",
        "correct_answer": "manifest destiny",
        "distractor1": "Reconstruction",
        "distractor2": "racial equality",
        "distractor3": "conservation of natural resources"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the period from 1860 to 1900, the Federal Government encouraged the settlement of the West by",
        "correct_answer": "granting tracts of land to railroad companies to encourage construction",
        "distractor1": "passing an increased number of liberal immigration laws",
        "distractor2": "selling the most fertile public land to Native American Indians",
        "distractor3": "providing free transportation to settlers moving to the frontier"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Up to our own day American history is the history of the colonization of the Great West. The existence of an area of free land, . . . and the advance of American settlement westward explain American development.\"",
        "correct_answer": "has had a positive effect on the growth of the United States",
        "distractor1": "should be preserved for free use by all the people",
        "distractor2": "has mirrored European values and social   patterns",
        "distractor3": "will continue indefinitely as a region to be colonized"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the late 1800 s, the goal of the Federal Government s policy toward Native American Indians was to",
        "correct_answer": "destroy tribal bonds and thus weaken their traditional cultural values",
        "distractor1": "grant them full citizenship and due process",
        "distractor2": "give their tribal groups authority over their own affairs",
        "distractor3": "increase the land holdings of western tribes"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which characteristic of the American frontier continues to be an important part of life in the United States today?",
        "correct_answer": "significant opportunities for social and economic mobility",
        "distractor1": "widespread support for the Populist Party",
        "distractor2": "necessity for families to have many children",
        "distractor3": "a predominantly agricultural and mining economy"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which pair of events did the first event most directly influence the second?",
        "correct_answer": "building of the transcontinental railroad --> disappearance of the frontier",
        "distractor1": "discovery of gold in California --> Louisiana Purchase",
        "distractor2": "settling of the Oregon Territory --> passage of the Homestead Act",
        "distractor3": "assimilation of Native American Indians into American society --> passage of the Dawes Act"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"I am tired of fighting.... Hear me, my chiefs. I am tired. My heart is sick and sad. From where the sun now stands, I shall fight no more forever!\"",
        "correct_answer": "forcing Native American Indians to assimilate into American culture",
        "distractor1": "placing Native American Indian tribes on reservations",
        "distractor2": "requiring Native American Indians to settle west of the Mississippi River",
        "distractor3": "granting immediate citizenship to Native American Indians"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Indian Wars that occurred between 1860 and 1890 were mainly the result of",
        "correct_answer": "the movement of settlers onto the Great Plains",
        "distractor1": "disputes over the spread of slavery",
        "distractor2": "conflict with Mexico over Texas and California",
        "distractor3": "the search for gold in California"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aim of the Dawes Act of 1887 was to",
        "correct_answer": "assimilate Native American Indians into American culture",
        "distractor1": "restore previously taken land to Native American Indian tribes",
        "distractor2": "maintain traditional Native American Indian cultures",
        "distractor3": "end all governmental contact with Native American Indians"
    },
    {
        "question": "The passage of the Dawes Act in 1887 was primarily an attempt by the United States government to",
        "correct_answer": "encourage Native American Indians to give up their traditional cultures",
        "distractor1": "limit the power of the Bureau of Indian Affairs",
        "distractor2": "return eastern land to Native American Indian tribes",
        "distractor3": "hire Native American Indians as military scouts"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of the Homestead Act of 1862, which provided free federal land, was to",
        "correct_answer": "encourage settlement of the West",
        "distractor1": "set up reservations for Native American Indians",
        "distractor2": "establish land-grant agricultural colleges",
        "distractor3": "assist in the construction of transcontinental railroads"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Homestead Act was important in the growth of the West because it",
        "correct_answer": "encouraged settlement of the Great Plains",
        "distractor1": "set aside reservations for Native American Indians",
        "distractor2": "created the Department of Agriculture to aid farmers",
        "distractor3": "provided land to build a canal system"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Homestead Act of 1862 helped the development of the West by",
        "correct_answer": "providing free land to settlers",
        "distractor1": "granting land for construction of transcontinental railroads",
        "distractor2": "allowing slavery to spread to the territories",
        "distractor3": "placing Native American Indians on reservations"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the late 1800s, many North American Indian tribes were sent to reservations that were located",
        "correct_answer": "in sparsely populated regions of the West",
        "distractor1": "along the major rivers and lakes of the Midwest",
        "distractor2": "near large cities in the Northwest",
        "distractor3": "east of the Mississippi River"
    },
    {
        "question": "The closing of the frontier and the growth of industry in the late 1800s are two factors often associated with the",
        "correct_answer": "rise of United States imperialism",
        "distractor1": "reduction of exports to Asian nations",
        "distractor2": "restoration of a plantation economy in the South",
        "distractor3": "formation of alliances with other nations"
    },
    {
        "question": "Speaker A: Nature should be left as it is found. All unsettled land should be off limits to",
        "correct_answer": "Native American Indians",
        "distractor1": "western farmers",
        "distractor2": "railroad companies",
        "distractor3": "European immigrants"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Homestead Act, the mass killing of buffalo, and the completion of the transcontinental railroad are most closely associated with the",
        "correct_answer": "decline of the Plains Indians",
        "distractor1": "rise of organized labor",
        "distractor2": "building of the Erie Canal",
        "distractor3": "northern migration of African Americans"
    },
    {
        "question": "The mechanization of agriculture in the United States led directly to",
        "correct_answer": "an increase in production",
        "distractor1": "less dependence on railroads by farmers",
        "distractor2": "fewer agricultural exports",
        "distractor3": "the decreasing size of the average farm"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the period from 1865 to 1900, the United States Government aided the development of the West by",
        "correct_answer": "granting land to railroad companies",
        "distractor1": "maintaining free and unlimited coinage of silver",
        "distractor2": "offering low-interest loans to businesses",
        "distractor3": "providing price supports for farm products"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the United States, the main purpose of antitrust legislation is to",
        "correct_answer": "increase competition in business",
        "distractor1": "protect the environment",
        "distractor2": "encourage the growth of monopolies",
        "distractor3": "strengthen the rights of workers"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to 1890, United States businesses made few foreign investments mainly because",
        "correct_answer": "investment opportunities were better in the United States",
        "distractor1": "state governments discouraged foreign investments",
        "distractor2": "foreign investments were prohibited by Congress",
        "distractor3": "foreign nations did not accept investments from United States businesses"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Federal Trade Commission, the Interstate Commerce Commission, and the Federal Communications Commission are similar in that each",
        "correct_answer": "has the power to formulate and enforce regulations",
        "distractor1": "represents the interests of big business",
        "distractor2": "is specifically provided for in the United States Constitution",
        "distractor3": "must get approval from the states to carry out national laws"
    },
    {
        "question": " Prices and wages should be determined by the marketplace.  The author of this statement would most probably support",
        "correct_answer": "laissez-faire capitalism",
        "distractor1": "government ownership of utilities",
        "distractor2": "minimum-wage laws",
        "distractor3": "wage and price controls"
    },
    {
        "question": "After the Civil War, one way business leaders tried to eliminate competition was by",
        "correct_answer": "forming monopolies or trusts",
        "distractor1": "developing overseas markets",
        "distractor2": "increasing the prices of their products",
        "distractor3": "paying high wages to their workers"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the United States, organized labor made its greatest membership gains when",
        "correct_answer": "the right to unionize and bargain collectively was guaranteed by legislation",
        "distractor1": "international competition began to threaten jobs in the United States",
        "distractor2": "the major business groups encouraged unionization",
        "distractor3": "the economy began to shift from manufacturing to service employment"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which factor most limited the growth of labor unions during the late 1800 s?",
        "correct_answer": "Most employers were very hostile toward workers  efforts to organize.",
        "distractor1": "Most factory workers were satisfied with their wages and working conditions.",
        "distractor2": "The Federal Government declared that unions were illegal.",
        "distractor3": "Workers preferred to negotiate with factory owners as individuals rather than as members of a group."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 19th century, the major national labor unions wanted to improve the position of workers mainly by",
        "correct_answer": "obtaining the legal right to organize and bargain collectively",
        "distractor1": "using government troops to settle labor disputes with management",
        "distractor2": "supporting government ownership of major industries",
        "distractor3": "endorsing a third political party for workers only"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the latter half of the 19th century, many business organizations in the United States combined into large corporations because",
        "correct_answer": "efficiency in production methods could be increased",
        "distractor1": "income levels for workers would be improved",
        "distractor2": "government intervention in economic affairs would decline",
        "distractor3": "economic possibilities outside the United States could be explored"
    },
    {
        "question": "Many reformers who opposed the laissez-faire attitude of the late 19th century argued that",
        "correct_answer": "government should protect society through the regulation of business",
        "distractor1": "the National Government should not interfere in the activities of big business    big business",
        "distractor2": "national wealth could best be assured by the accumulation of gold",
        "distractor3": "the idea of rugged individualism is vital to the nation s economic growth"
    },
    {
        "question": "A major way in which the United States has practiced \"economic nationalism\" has been to",
        "correct_answer": "implement protective tariffs to help American industry",
        "distractor1": "establish social welfare programs to aid the poor",
        "distractor2": "pass legislation outlawing most monopolies",
        "distractor3": "require industry to provide safe working conditions for employees"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the United States, industrial unions of the 1880 s and of the 1980 s had similar goals in that both campaigned for",
        "correct_answer": "greater job security and higher wages",
        "distractor1": "national health insurance",
        "distractor2": "better unemployment insurance",
        "distractor3": "wage and price freezes"
    },
    {
        "question": "In response to the demands of farmers and small business owners, Congress enacted laws in the late 19th century that",
        "correct_answer": "regulated the activities of railroads and trusts",
        "distractor1": "supported the organization of farm cooperatives",
        "distractor2": "provided direct payments to farmers to help them buy modem machinery",
        "distractor3": "dropped tariff rates to the lowest point in the century"
    },
    {
        "question": "A negative effect of holding companies, mergers, and pools on the United States during the late 19th century was that these combinations",
        "correct_answer": "decreased competition between businesses",
        "distractor1": "encouraged the Federal Government to spend more than its income",
        "distractor2": "reduced the need for labor unions",
        "distractor3": "ended United States participation in inter-national trade"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nativism in the late 19th century was motivated primarily by",
        "correct_answer": "hostility toward immigrant workers",
        "distractor1": "the need to reduce overcrowding in western states",
        "distractor2": "cultural conflicts with Native American Indians",
        "distractor3": "the migration of African Americans to northern cities"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the late 1800 s, labor unions in the United States had their greatest success in",
        "correct_answer": "organizing skilled workers into craft unions",
        "distractor1": "persuading the government to limit most immigration",
        "distractor2": "winning the great majority of strikes",
        "distractor3": "achieving a legally guaranteed minimum wage"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Sherman Antitrust Act, the Social Security Act, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) are examples of",
        "correct_answer": "the Federal Government s response to changes in the economy",
        "distractor1": "Federal laws designed to protect consumers from unsafe products",
        "distractor2": "Federal laws designed to control spending",
        "distractor3": "the Federal Government s attempts to regulate big business"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which term best describes United States economic policy during the era of the rise of big business (1865-1900)?",
        "correct_answer": "laissez-faire capitalism",
        "distractor1": "mercantilism",
        "distractor2": "Marxism",
        "distractor3": "welfare-state capitalism"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement best describes the status of the labor union movement in the United States in 1900?",
        "correct_answer": "Unions were still struggling to gain public acceptance.",
        "distractor1": "Most of the labor force was organized into unions.",
        "distractor2": "Government and business opposition had destroyed the labor union movement.",
        "distractor3": "Unions had won the right to strike and bargain collectively."
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of the Interstate Commerce Act (1887), the Sherman Antitrust Act (1890), and the Clayton Antitrust Act (1914) was to",
        "correct_answer": "eliminate unfair business practices",
        "distractor1": "reduce imports from foreign nations",
        "distractor2": "reduce the power of the unions",
        "distractor3": "increase the power of local governments"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why did the United States follow a policy of unrestricted immigration for Europeans during most of the 1800 s?",
        "correct_answer": "The American economy needed many unskilled workers.",
        "distractor1": "Business and industry depended on the foreign capital brought by immigrants.",
        "distractor2": "Most Americans desired a more diversified culture.",
        "distractor3": "The United States wanted to help European nations by taking in their surplus pop-ulation."
    },
    {
        "question": "  Statement A:   \"The best way to economic recovery is to subsidize industry so that it will hire more workers and expand production.\"",
        "correct_answer": "Speaker C",
        "distractor1": "Speaker A",
        "distractor2": "Speaker B",
        "distractor3": "Speaker D"
    },
    {
        "question": "A common characteristic of third political parties in the United States is that they",
        "correct_answer": "tend to focus on one person or one issue",
        "distractor1": "come into existence only during periods of corruption",
        "distractor2": "have dealt mainly with foreign policy issues",
        "distractor3": "have frequently forced Congress to decide Presidential elections"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which situation brought about the rapid growth of industry between 1865 and 1900?",
        "correct_answer": "availability of investment capital",
        "distractor1": "high worker morale resulting from good wages and working conditions",
        "distractor2": "establishment of western reservations for Native American Indians",
        "distractor3": "decline in the number of people attending schools"
    },
    {
        "question": "From 1865 to 1900, how did the growth of industry affect American society?",
        "correct_answer": "The percentage of Americans living in urban areas increased.",
        "distractor1": "The United States experienced the disappearance of the traditional ",
        "distractor2": "Population centers shifted from the Northeast to the South",
        "distractor3": "Restrictions on immigration created a more homogeneous culture."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the late 1800 s, a major reaction to the activities of labor unions in the United States was that",
        "correct_answer": "courts frequently issued injunctions to stop strikes",
        "distractor1": "the press in most communities supported unions",
        "distractor2": "United States Presidents opposed the use of Federal troops to end strikes called by organized labor",
        "distractor3": "most factory workers quickly joined the unions"
    },
    {
        "question": "Many wealthy American industralists of the late 19th century used the theory of Social Darwinism to",
        "correct_answer": "justify monopolistic actions",
        "distractor1": "support the labor union movement",
        "distractor2": "promote legislation establishing a minimum wage",
        "distractor3": "encourage charitable orga-nizations to help the poor"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to 1880, the number of immigrants to the United States was not restricted mainly because",
        "correct_answer": "industry owners wanted cheap labor",
        "distractor1": "the nations of Europe dis-couraged emigration",
        "distractor2": "the United States birthrate was increasing",
        "distractor3": "Congress lacked the power to limit immigration"
    },
    {
        "question": "Laws requiring individuals to pass civil service examinations to obtain government jobs were enacted to",
        "correct_answer": "eliminate patronage and corruption in government hiring",
        "distractor1": "allow the government to compete with private industry for employees",
        "distractor2": "support the development of public employee labor unions",
        "distractor3": "encourage the growth of local political parties"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the theory of laissez faire, the economy functions best when the government",
        "correct_answer": "does not interfere in business",
        "distractor1": "subsidizes business so that it can compete worldwide",
        "distractor2": "regulates businesses for the good of the majority",
        "distractor3": "owns major industries"
    },
    {
        "question": "Businesses formed trusts, pools, and holding companies mainly to",
        "correct_answer": "increase profits by eliminating competition",
        "distractor1": "offer a wide range of goods and services to consumers",
        "distractor2": "provide employment opportunities for minorities",
        "distractor3": "protect the interests of workers"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Rockefeller Foundation, Carnegie Hall, and the Morgan Library illustrate various ways that entrepreneurs and their descendants have",
        "correct_answer": "supported philanthropic activities to benefit society",
        "distractor1": "suppressed the growth of labor unions",
        "distractor2": "applied scientific discoveries to industry",
        "distractor3": "attempted to undermine the United States eco-nomic system"
    },
    {
        "question": "The major reason the United States placed few restrictions on immigration during the 1800 s was that",
        "correct_answer": "the growing economy needed a steady supply of cheap labor",
        "distractor1": "few Europeans wished to give up their economic security",
        "distractor2": "little opposition to immigration existed",
        "distractor3": "most immigrants spoke English and thus needed little or no education"
    },
    {
        "question": "The American Federation of Labor became the first long-lasting, successful labor union in the United States mainly because it",
        "correct_answer": "fought for the rights of skilled workers",
        "distractor1": "refused to participate in strikes against employers",
        "distractor2": "concentrated on organizing workers in industries in the South",
        "distractor3": "formed its own political party and elected many prolabor public officials"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the United States during the late 19th century, much of the prejudice expressed toward immigrants was based on the belief that they would",
        "correct_answer": "fail to assimilate into American society",
        "distractor1": "cause overcrowding in farm areas",
        "distractor2": "refuse to become citizens",
        "distractor3": "support the enemies of the United States in wartime"
    },
    {
        "question": "The actions of Jane Addams, Ida Tarbell, and Booker T. Washington illustrate that reform in the United States has",
        "correct_answer": "utilized a variety of methods to achieve many goals",
        "distractor1": "depended on support from religious groups",
        "distractor2": "relied on programs initiated by the Federal Government",
        "distractor3": "promoted women s suffrage as its main goal"
    },
    {
        "question": "  Speaker A:  \"To preserve our American culture, people whose national origins do not match the origins of our nation s founders must be refused admission.\"",
        "correct_answer": "Speaker D",
        "distractor1": "Speaker A",
        "distractor2": "Speaker B",
        "distractor3": "Speaker C"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the decades after the Civil War, the major result of the shift from single proprietorship to corporate organization was that business was able to",
        "correct_answer": "raise large sums of money",
        "distractor1": "make more efficient use of natural resources",
        "distractor2": "concentrate on improving the quality of manufactured goods",
        "distractor3": "provide workers with higher wages"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the period from 1865 to 1900, disputes between labor and management were often marked by",
        "correct_answer": "the use of violence by both sides",
        "distractor1": "cooperative efforts to resolve differences",
        "distractor2": "government support of striking workers",
        "distractor3": "arbitration by the Federal Government"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Federal Civil Service System was begun in the late 19th century primarily to",
        "correct_answer": "reduce the practice of political patronage",
        "distractor1": "reward political party supporters",
        "distractor2": "secure political campaign contributions",
        "distractor3": "provide government contracts for big business"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the 19th century, what was the major reason that an increasing number of states established public schools and passed compulsory education laws?",
        "correct_answer": "Reformers argued that an educated, literate population was necessary for a successful democracy.",
        "distractor1": "The Supreme Court required the states to do so.",
        "distractor2": "Most jobs required a high school diploma.",
        "distractor3": "The United States had begun a massive program of technical training to enhance its international economic position."
    },
    {
        "question": "Jacob Riis, Jane Addams, and Margaret Sanger are most closely associated with efforts to",
        "correct_answer": "improve conditions for the poor",
        "distractor1": "educate and train formerly enslaved persons",
        "distractor2": "preserve the natural environment",
        "distractor3": "advance the interests of organized labor"
    },
    {
        "question": "One way in which the Chinese Exclusion Act, the Gentlemen s Agreement, and the National Origins Act were similar is that all were expressions of",
        "correct_answer": "nativism",
        "distractor1": "imperialism",
        "distractor2": "militarism",
        "distractor3": "Manifest Destiny"
    },
    {
        "question": "Both the Sherman Antitrust Act and the Clayton Antitrust Act were passed in response to the problem of",
        "correct_answer": "business combinations limiting competition",
        "distractor1": "companies refusing to hire minority workers",
        "distractor2": "businesses choosing to hire illegal immigrants",
        "distractor3": "unsafe working conditions in factories"
    },
    {
        "question": "Industrialists of the late 1800s contributed most to economic growth by",
        "correct_answer": "establishing large corporations",
        "distractor1": "supporting the efforts of labor unions",
        "distractor2": "encouraging government ownership of banks",
        "distractor3": "opposing protective tariffs"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the cartoon, how was the United States in the 1990s similar to the United States in the 1890s?",
        "correct_answer": "Business consolidation was accepted practice.",
        "distractor1": "Little need existed for government regulation.",
        "distractor2": "Investment in the stock market decreased.",
        "distractor3": "The price of petroleum products decreased."
    },
    {
        "question": "The main purpose of this 1886 poster was to",
        "correct_answer": "organize a protest against acts of police brutality against workers",
        "distractor1": "oppose immigrants who took jobs from American workers",
        "distractor2": "support nativist calls for limitations on labor unions",
        "distractor3": "show support for police actions against foreign revolutionaries"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the second half of the 19th century, government commitment to the principles of laissez-faire capitalism contributed to",
        "correct_answer": "economic domination by business trusts",
        "distractor1": "healthy and positive competition between businesses",
        "distractor2": "the growth of small business firms",
        "distractor3": "friendly working relationships between labor and management"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the late 19th century, owners of big businesses generally embraced Social Darwinism because it reinforced their belief that",
        "correct_answer": "economic success demonstrates fitness to lead",
        "distractor1": "business monopolies are contrary to the social order",
        "distractor2": "all wealth should be returned to society",
        "distractor3": "economic competition should be regulated"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which factor most influenced the growth of the United States economy between 1865 and 1900?",
        "correct_answer": "governmental policy of laissez faire",
        "distractor1": "development of the sharecropping system",
        "distractor2": "success of organized labor",
        "distractor3": "restrictions on immigration"
    },
    {
        "question": "Industrialists of the late 1800s used pools and trusts to",
        "correct_answer": "increase profits by minimizing competition",
        "distractor1": "promote fair business practices in the marketplace",
        "distractor2": "work cooperatively with labor unions",
        "distractor3": "exclude immigrant workers from factory jobs"
    },
    {
        "question": " Labor Leaders Executed for Causing Haymarket Riot   State Militia Called In To End Homestead Strike ",
        "correct_answer": "The government frequently opposed labor union activities.",
        "distractor1": "Strikes by labor unions usually gained public support.",
        "distractor2": "Labor union demands were usually met.",
        "distractor3": "Arbitration was commonly used to end labor unrest."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which 19th-century business practice does this cartoon illustrate?",
        "correct_answer": "creating monopolies",
        "distractor1": "forming cooperatives",
        "distractor2": "establishing trade zones",
        "distractor3": "expanding global markets"
    },
    {
        "question": "The cartoonist would most likely support federal government attempts to",
        "correct_answer": "pass antitrust legislation",
        "distractor1": "limit regulation of business",
        "distractor2": "establish high tariffs",
        "distractor3": "stop industrial pollution"
    },
    {
        "question": "One factor that furthered industrialization in the United States between 1865 and 1900 was the",
        "correct_answer": "expansion of the railroads",
        "distractor1": "development of the airplane",
        "distractor2": "mass production of automobiles",
        "distractor3": "widespread use of steamboats"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term business monopoly can best be described as",
        "correct_answer": "a company that controls or dominates an industry",
        "distractor1": "the most common form of business in the United States",
        "distractor2": "government control of the means of production",
        "distractor3": "an agreement between partners to manage a corporation"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the late 19th century, Samuel Gompers, Terence Powderly, and Eugene Debs were leaders in the movement to",
        "correct_answer": "improve working conditions",
        "distractor1": "stop racial segregation of Native American Indians",
        "distractor2": "limit illegal immigration",
        "distractor3": "gain fair treatment of Native American Indians"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 19th-century philosophy of Social Darwinism maintained that",
        "correct_answer": "economic success comes to those who are the hardest working and most competent",
        "distractor1": "the government should have control over the means of production and the marketplace",
        "distractor2": "all social class distinctions in American society should be eliminated",
        "distractor3": "wealth and income should be more equally distributed"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the late 1800s, industrialization in the United States led to",
        "correct_answer": "the growth of the middle class",
        "distractor1": "an overall decline in labor union membership",
        "distractor2": "the creation of affirmative action programs",
        "distractor3": "a decrease in the use of natural resources"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the late 19th century, the major argument used by labor union leaders against immigrants was that immigrants",
        "correct_answer": "took jobs from United States citizens",
        "distractor1": "contributed little to enrich American life",
        "distractor2": "placed financial drains on social services",
        "distractor3": "refused to assimilate into American culture"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which generalization about population growth is supported by information in this chart?",
        "correct_answer": "By 1920, more people lived in cities than in rural areas.",
        "distractor1": "For every census listed, rural population exceeded urban population.",
        "distractor2": "The Civil War significantly slowed the rate of population growth.",
        "distractor3": "Most urban population growth was due to people migrating from rural areas."
    },
    {
        "question": "The slogan  Eight hours for work, eight hours for sleep, eight hours for what we will  was used in the late 1800s to promote a major goal of",
        "correct_answer": "organized labor",
        "distractor1": "farmers",
        "distractor2": "politicians",
        "distractor3": "industrialists"
    },
    {
        "question": "A significant contribution to the industrialization of the United States was Henry Ford s development of",
        "correct_answer": "the assembly line",
        "distractor1": "electric-powered vehicles",
        "distractor2": "the first holding company",
        "distractor3": "a new process for making steel"
    },
    {
        "question": "One reason John D. Rockefeller, Andrew Carnegie, and J. Pierpont Morgan were sometimes called robber barons was because they",
        "correct_answer": "used ruthless business tactics against their competitors",
        "distractor1": "robbed from the rich to give to the poor",
        "distractor2": "made unnecessarily risky investments",
        "distractor3": "stole money from the federal government"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 19th century, protective tariffs, subsidies for railroads, and open immigration showed that the federal government followed a policy of",
        "correct_answer": "support for economic development",
        "distractor1": "noninterference in the free-market system",
        "distractor2": "regulation of unfair business practices",
        "distractor3": "support for organized labor"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which United States foreign policy was most directly related to the rise of big business in the late 1800s?",
        "correct_answer": "imperialism",
        "distractor1": "d tente",
        "distractor2": "neutrality",
        "distractor3": "containment"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement describes a result of the Industrial Revolution in the United States?",
        "correct_answer": "Immigration to the United States increased.",
        "distractor1": "Farm production decreased.",
        "distractor2": "Slavery in the South increased.",
        "distractor3": "The population of the cities decreased."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the main benefit that labor unions of the late 19th century gained for their members?",
        "correct_answer": "improved wages and hours",
        "distractor1": "job security",
        "distractor2": "paid vacations",
        "distractor3": "health insurance"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the late 1800s, business leaders formed trusts mainly to",
        "correct_answer": "eliminate competition",
        "distractor1": "reduce prices",
        "distractor2": "improve worker productivity",
        "distractor3": "establish overseas factories"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main idea of this cartoon?",
        "correct_answer": "The Standard Oil Company was a harmful monopoly.",
        "distractor1": "The best way to develop major industries was to form proprietorships.",
        "distractor2": "Government regulations were strangling the Standard Oil Company.",
        "distractor3": "Foreign competition in the oil industry was hurting American companies."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the late 1800s, the theory of laissez-faire capitalism was used by many industrialists to",
        "correct_answer": "argue against government regulation of business practices",
        "distractor1": "petition the government for assistance during times of financial crisis",
        "distractor2": "oppose colonial expansion in Africa and Asia",
        "distractor3": "defend limits on the number of immigrants allowed to work in factories"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the late 1800s, a major reason labor unions had difficulty achieving their goals was that",
        "correct_answer": "government supported business over labor",
        "distractor1": "industrialization created better working conditions",
        "distractor2": "there was a shortage of new workers",
        "distractor3": "businesses promoted labor officials to management positions"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conclusion can be drawn about the impact of the Populist and the Progressive parties on the United States?",
        "correct_answer": "Some third-party goals eventually become planks in the platforms of the major parties.",
        "distractor1": "The United States has steadily moved from a two-party system to a multiparty system.",
        "distractor2": "Religious ideals have most often motivated people to splinter away from major parties .",
        "distractor3": "An increasing number of citizens have grown weary of party politics and fail to vote in elections."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the late 19th century, farmers desired  cheap money  policies because farmers believed that rising prices for their crops would",
        "correct_answer": "enable them to pay back their loans more easily",
        "distractor1": "require banks to lend them more money at reduced interest rates",
        "distractor2": "force manufacturers to reduce the prices of manufactured goods purchased by farmers",
        "distractor3": "cause the price of undeveloped farmland to drop"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the 1870 s and 1880 s, midwestern farmers found that earning a living was increasingly difficult because",
        "correct_answer": "railroad companies charged high rates for transporting farm products",
        "distractor1": "prices of agricultural products were increasing",
        "distractor2": "agricultural output was declining rapidly",
        "distractor3": "farm labor was becoming more unionized"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Populists believed that most of the United States economic problems would be solved by establishing",
        "correct_answer": "currency reform",
        "distractor1": "postal savings banks",
        "distractor2": "a national property tax",
        "distractor3": "a renewed policy of open immigration"
    },
    {
        "question": "A main goal of the Granger movement of the 1870 s and 1880 s was to",
        "correct_answer": "force the railroads to lower freight rates",
        "distractor1": "reduce the rate of inflation",
        "distractor2": "strengthen labor unions",
        "distractor3": "improve living conditions in urban slums"
    },
    {
        "question": "Although the Populist Party failed to elect its candidates to the Presidency, some of the Party s aims were later achieved by the",
        "correct_answer": "creation of a graduated income tax and the direct election of Senators",
        "distractor1": "adoption of the gold standard",
        "distractor2": "elimination of racial segregation laws in the South",
        "distractor3": "establishment of higher protective tariffs on manufactured goods"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the early 1900 s, the initiative, recall, and referendum were changes made in many states to give",
        "correct_answer": "voters greater direct participation in government",
        "distractor1": "citizens the right to choose Presidential candidates",
        "distractor2": "workers more rights in the collective bargain-ing process",
        "distractor3": "business leaders more control over their industries"
    },
    {
        "question": "-Free and unlimited coinage of silver",
        "correct_answer": "Populist Party in 1892",
        "distractor1": "Republican Party in 1876",
        "distractor2": "Bull-Moose Party 1912",
        "distractor3": "Democratic Party in 1932"
    },
    {
        "question": "A common characteristic of third political parties in the United States is that they",
        "correct_answer": "tend to focus on one person or one issue",
        "distractor1": "come into existence only during periods of corruption",
        "distractor2": "have dealt mainly with foreign policy issues",
        "distractor3": "have frequently forced Congress to decide Presidential elections"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Populist Party was important in United States history because it",
        "correct_answer": "proposed ideas that later became law",
        "distractor1": "succeeded in electing two presidential candidates",
        "distractor2": "won control of many state governments",
        "distractor3": "achieved suffrage for African Americans"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the late 1800s, many business practices of the railroads led to",
        "correct_answer": "an increase in the demand for government regulation",
        "distractor1": "an increase in the unemployment rate",
        "distractor2": "a decrease in the demand for raw materials",
        "distractor3": "a decrease in the variety of products available for consumers"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the second half of the 19th century, agriculture in the United States was transformed most by the",
        "correct_answer": "increase in the use of farm machinery",
        "distractor1": "increase in prices paid for farm products",
        "distractor2": "decline in the population growth rate of the United States",
        "distractor3": "decline in demand for agricultural products"
    },
    {
        "question": "A goal of the Granger and Populist movements was to",
        "correct_answer": "help western farmers fight unjust economic practices",
        "distractor1": "expand rights for African Americans",
        "distractor2": "provide support for the banking industry",
        "distractor3": "enable big business to expand without government interference"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Interstate Commerce Act and the Sherman Antitrust Act were passed by Congress to",
        "correct_answer": "protect the interests of small businesses",
        "distractor1": "increase safety in the workplace",
        "distractor2": "promote fair hiring practices",
        "distractor3": "improve working conditions"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was a major effect of the Agricultural Revolution in the United States during the late 1800s?",
        "correct_answer": "Food supplies were increased to feed urban dwellers.",
        "distractor1": "Unemployed factory workers could find jobs in agriculture.",
        "distractor2": "The size of farms decreased.",
        "distractor3": "United States farm exports decreased."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Populist movement was most interested in improving conditions for",
        "correct_answer": "farmers",
        "distractor1": "business leaders",
        "distractor2": "African Americans",
        "distractor3": "Native American Indians"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the late 1800s, the Granger movement tried to improve conditions for farmers by",
        "correct_answer": "forcing railroads to lower their rates",
        "distractor1": "lowering the rate of inflation",
        "distractor2": "strengthening the gold standard",
        "distractor3": "making labor unions stronger"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which trend is shown in these graphs?",
        "correct_answer": "When production increases, prices decrease.",
        "distractor1": "When production increases, prices increase.",
        "distractor2": "When production remains unchanged, prices decrease.",
        "distractor3": "Prices and production are usually unrelated."
    },
    {
        "question": "As a result of the trends shown in the graphs, the Populist Party wanted the federal government to increase the money supply to",
        "correct_answer": "raise the prices of crops",
        "distractor1": "limit the exportation of corn",
        "distractor2": "discourage the consumption of corn",
        "distractor3": "increase agricultural imports"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the turn of the century, why did most immigrants to the United States settle in cities?",
        "correct_answer": "Jobs were readily available.",
        "distractor1": "Government relief programs required immigrants to settle in cities.",
        "distractor2": "Labor union leaders encouraged unrestricted immigration.",
        "distractor3": "Immigrants were not permitted to buy farmland."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about immigration to the United States during the 19th century is most valid?",
        "correct_answer": "Industrial growth led to a demand for cheap immigrant labor.",
        "distractor1": "Organized labor supported unlimited immigration.",
        "distractor2": "Most immigrants to the United States were illegal aliens.",
        "distractor3": "Few immigrants came from western Europe."
    },
    {
        "question": "\"America s strength lies in its diversity. Many immigrant groups have joined the mainstream of American life, while maintaining their languages, religions, and traditions. This has made the United States a strong nation.\"",
        "correct_answer": "cultural pluralism",
        "distractor1": "nativism",
        "distractor2": "ethnocentrism",
        "distractor3": "limited social mobility"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the late 19th century, the pattern of United States immigration changed in that",
        "correct_answer": "increasing numbers of immigrants came from eastern and southern Europe",
        "distractor1": "far fewer immigrants arrived in the United States than in previous years",
        "distractor2": "most immigrants chose to settle in the rural, farming regions of the western United States",
        "distractor3": "most immigrants were political refugees"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about immigration to the United States is most accurate?",
        "correct_answer": "The desire for economic advancement has been a major reason for immigration to the United States",
        "distractor1": "The ethnic mix of immigrants to the United States has remained mostly unchanged.",
        "distractor2": "The number of immigrants has remained constant in each decade during most of United States history.",
        "distractor3": "Nearly all immigrants have easily assimilated into American culture."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the experience of most of the  new immigrants  who arrived in the United States from southern and eastern Europe in the late 1800s and early 1900s?",
        "correct_answer": "They lived in urban areas and most held lowpaying jobs.",
        "distractor1": "They obtained free land in the West and became farmers.",
        "distractor2": "They became discouraged with America and returned to their homelands.",
        "distractor3": "They were easily assimilated into mainstream American culture."
    },
    {
        "question": "The intent of the United States immigration laws of the 1920s was to",
        "correct_answer": "restrict immigration through the use of quotas",
        "distractor1": "increase economic opportunities for recent immigrants",
        "distractor2": "encourage cultural diversity",
        "distractor3": "restore an open-door policy toward immigration"
    },
    {
        "question": "Between 1890 and 1915, the majority of immigrants to the United States were labeled  new immigrants  because they were",
        "correct_answer": "culturally different from most earlier immigrants",
        "distractor1": "considered physically and mentally superior to earlier immigrants",
        "distractor2": "forced to settle in the cities of the Midwest",
        "distractor3": "from China, Japan, and other Asian countries"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which expression most accurately illustrates the concept of nativism?",
        "correct_answer": " Help Wanted   Irish Need Not Apply ",
        "distractor1": " Go West, young man. ",
        "distractor2": " America   first in war and peace ",
        "distractor3": " The only thing we have to fear, is fear itself. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Over the past twenty years, an objective of United States immigration policy has been to",
        "correct_answer": "reduce the number of illegal immigrants",
        "distractor1": "keep out immigrants from former communist nations",
        "distractor2": "return to an open immigration policy",
        "distractor3": "encourage emigration from Western Europe"
    },
    {
        "question": "Between 1870 and 1920, the federal government placed few restrictions on immigration primarily because it wanted to",
        "correct_answer": "ensure that there would be workers for the factories",
        "distractor1": "sell land in the West",
        "distractor2": "recruit men for the military",
        "distractor3": "avoid offending foreign governments"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the late 19th century, the major argument used by labor union leaders against immigrants was that immigrants",
        "correct_answer": "took jobs from United States citizens",
        "distractor1": "contributed little to enrich American life",
        "distractor2": "refused to assimilate into American culture",
        "distractor3": "placed financial drains on social services"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement best describes President Theodore Roosevelt s foreign policy position toward Latin America in the early 1900 s?",
        "correct_answer": "The Monroe Doctrine permits the United States to intervene actively in the affairs of Latin American nations.",
        "distractor1": "The United States should reduce its involvement in Latin American affairs.",
        "distractor2": "Latin American nations should form an organization to help them achieve political and economic stability.",
        "distractor3": "The United States should give large amounts of financial aid to help the poor of Latin Amenca."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Republican Presidents of the 1920 s generally followed a foreign policy based on",
        "correct_answer": "noninvolvement",
        "distractor1": "collective security",
        "distractor2": "brinkmanship",
        "distractor3": "militarism"
    },
    {
        "question": "The speakers below are discussing foreign policies that the United States has followed at various times. Base your answers on their statements and on your knowledge of social studies. Speaker A: Steer clear of permanent alliances with any portion of the foreign world.",
        "correct_answer": "C and D",
        "distractor1": "A and B",
        "distractor2": "A and C",
        "distractor3": "B and D"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Monroe Doctrine declared that the United States would",
        "correct_answer": "view European interference in the Americas as a threat to the national interest of the United States",
        "distractor1": "prevent the establishment of new European colonies anywhere in the world",
        "distractor2": "help colonies in North and South America adopt a democratic form of government",
        "distractor3": "prevent other nations from trading with South American nations"
    },
    {
        "question": "One important conclusion that can be drawn as a result of the United States experience in both the Spanish-American War (1898) and the Persian Gulf War (1991) is that",
        "correct_answer": "the media are a powerful influence in shaping American public opinion toward war",
        "distractor1": "only the President should decide issues of war and peace",
        "distractor2": "the public has little confidence in the ability of the American military",
        "distractor3": "international organizations play a decisive role in determining the outcome of a war"
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1823, the Monroe Doctrine was established mainly because the United States wanted to",
        "correct_answer": "warn Europe against any further colonization in Latin America",
        "distractor1": "keep control of Alaska and Hawaii",
        "distractor2": "establish more colonies in Latin America",
        "distractor3": "support England s attempt to keep its empire in Central America"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why did the United States formulate the Open Door policy toward China?",
        "correct_answer": "to prevent a European and Japanese monopoly of Chinese trade and markets",
        "distractor1": "to develop democratic institutions and practices in China",
        "distractor2": "to establish a military presence on the Chinese mainland",
        "distractor3": "to support Japanese efforts to industrialize China"
    },
    {
        "question": "From 1900 to 1915, a basic aim of United States foreign policy was to",
        "correct_answer": "promote United States influence in Latin America",
        "distractor1": "develop close economic ties with African nations",
        "distractor2": "oppose revolutionary movements in western Europe",
        "distractor3": "prevent the spread of communism in western Europe and Asia"
    },
    {
        "question": "President Theodore Roosevelt s Square Deal and President Lyndon Johnson s Great Society were similar in that both",
        "correct_answer": "increased the role of the Federal Government in dealing with social and economic problems",
        "distractor1": "returned control of social welfare programs to the states",
        "distractor2": "relied on individual initiative to improve the economy",
        "distractor3": "were supported by Congress over the objections of the majority of state governments"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which action was necessary to change from the indirect to the direct election of United States Senators?",
        "correct_answer": "ratification of a constitutional amendment",
        "distractor1": "passage of a Federal law",
        "distractor2": "a Supreme Court decision",
        "distractor3": "a national referendum"
    },
    {
        "question": "An important political aim of the Progressive movement was to",
        "correct_answer": "stimulate democratic reforms such as the initiative and the referendum",
        "distractor1": "guarantee government jobs for the unemployed",
        "distractor2": "create a unicameral national legislature",
        "distractor3": "increase the participation of African Americans in the Federal Government"
    },
    {
        "question": "Congress has attempted to deal with the issue of taxing citizens fairly by enacting a",
        "correct_answer": "graduated income tax",
        "distractor1": "high tariff",
        "distractor2": "property tax",
        "distractor3": "sales tax"
    },
    {
        "question": "The abolitionist movement, the women s suffrage movement, and the 1960 s civil rights movement are all examples of reform efforts that",
        "correct_answer": "developed significant popular support",
        "distractor1": "succeeded without causing major controversy",
        "distractor2": "achieved their goals without government action",
        "distractor3": "failed to affect the nation as a whole"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the period from 1890 to 1920, which development was the result of the other three?",
        "correct_answer": "passage of child labor laws by individual states",
        "distractor1": "labor union agitation in response to unemployment",
        "distractor2": "Progressive Party plea for compulsory education",
        "distractor3": "public outcry following numerous industrial accidents"
    },
    {
        "question": "A main purpose of President Theodore Roosevelt s trustbusting policies was to",
        "correct_answer": "encourage competition in business",
        "distractor1": "reduce corruption in government",
        "distractor2": "save the nation s banks",
        "distractor3": "end strikes by labor unions"
    },
    {
        "question": "Since 1913, the United States banking system, interest rates, and the amount of money in circulation have largely been controlled by the",
        "correct_answer": "Federal Reserve System",
        "distractor1": "United States Supreme Court",
        "distractor2": "Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation",
        "distractor3": "President s Council of Economic Advisors"
    },
    {
        "question": "During which period in United States history were the amendments concerning the income tax, direct election of Senators. Prohibition, and women s suffrage enacted?",
        "correct_answer": "Progressive Era",
        "distractor1": "Reconstruction",
        "distractor2": "The Gilded Age",
        "distractor3": "New Deal"
    },
    {
        "question": "Theodore Roosevelt, Woodrow Wilson, and Robert M. LaFollette are all considered progressives because they",
        "correct_answer": "worked to limit the power of big business",
        "distractor1": "supported the formation of the first trade union",
        "distractor2": "used Presidential power to break up strikes",
        "distractor3": "formed the first civil rights organizations"
    },
    {
        "question": "A progressive income tax is based on the idea that",
        "correct_answer": "taxpayers with larger incomes should be taxed at a higher rate",
        "distractor1": "all taxpayers should be taxed equal amounts of money",
        "distractor2": "all income should be taxed at the same rate",
        "distractor3": "taxation should be used to encourage social programs"
    },
    {
        "question": " Speaker A:  \"The business of America is business, and we would be wise to remember that.\"",
        "correct_answer": "Speaker C",
        "distractor1": "Speaker A",
        "distractor2": "Speaker B",
        "distractor3": "Speaker D"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the early 20th century, muckrakers were able to influence American society mainly through their",
        "correct_answer": "publication of articles and books",
        "distractor1": "frequent acts of civil disobedience",
        "distractor2": "activities as government officials",
        "distractor3": "control over factories"
    },
    {
        "question": "The initiative, referendum, recall, and direct primary are all intended to",
        "correct_answer": "increase participation in government by citizens",
        "distractor1": "make the President more responsive to the wishes of Congress",
        "distractor2": "reduce the influence of the media on elections",
        "distractor3": "give political parties more control of the electoral process"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which event of the early 1900 s is evidence that Upton Sinclair s novel  The Jungle  had an important impact on the United States?",
        "correct_answer": "passage of legislation requiring Federal inspection of meat",
        "distractor1": "adoption of reforms in public education",
        "distractor2": "passage of legislation limiting immigration",
        "distractor3": "adoption of the 18th amendment establishing Prohibition"
    },
    {
        "question": "A valid generalization about reform movements throughout United States history is that",
        "correct_answer": "many reform movements have led to long-lasting changes in society",
        "distractor1": "reform movements have failed to use the media effectively",
        "distractor2": "most successful reform movements affect relatively few people",
        "distractor3": "most reform movements have had little impact on the economy"
    },
    {
        "question": "A major purpose of the Federal Reserve System is to",
        "correct_answer": "regulate interest rates and the money supply",
        "distractor1": "deal with the trade deficit through tariffs and quotas",
        "distractor2": "control the minimum wage",
        "distractor3": "establish the Federal budget"
    },
    {
        "question": "A major goal of reformers during the Progressive Era was to",
        "correct_answer": "correct the abuses of big business",
        "distractor1": "end segregation in the South",
        "distractor2": "limit immigration from Latin America",
        "distractor3": "enact high tariffs to help domestic industry grow"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main purpose of a progressive income tax is to",
        "correct_answer": "base tax rates on a person's ability to pay",
        "distractor1": "increase government spending on welfare programs",
        "distractor2": "tax everyone at the same percentage rate",
        "distractor3": "ensure a balanced budget"
    },
    {
        "question": "A belief shared by Presidents Theodore Roosevelt, William Taft, and Woodrow Wilson is that the Federal Government should",
        "correct_answer": "use its power to regulate unfair business practices",
        "distractor1": "allow the free-enterprise system to work without regulation",
        "distractor2": "provide jobs for unemployed workers",
        "distractor3": "support unions in labor-management disputes"
    },
    {
        "question": " How the Other Half Lives , Jacob Riis (1890)",
        "correct_answer": "These works have had significant influence on social, political, and economic reforms.",
        "distractor1": "Most Americans have developed a preference for escapist and romantic literature.",
        "distractor2": "Most American authors have adopted a con-servative viewpoint",
        "distractor3": "American business has corrected poor condi-tions quickly."
    },
    {
        "question": "A major function of the Federal Reserve System is to",
        "correct_answer": "manage the supply of currency and bank credit",
        "distractor1": "suggest ways for the Federal Government to save money",
        "distractor2": "lend money to state governments",
        "distractor3": "issue United States Savings Bonds"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of the Interstate Commerce Act (1887), the Sherman Antitrust Act (1890), and the Clayton Antitrust Act (1914) was to",
        "correct_answer": "eliminate unfair business practices",
        "distractor1": "reduce imports from foreign nations",
        "distractor2": "reduce the power of the unions",
        "distractor3": "increase the power of local governments"
    },
    {
        "question": "A common characteristic of third political parties in the United States is that they",
        "correct_answer": "tend to focus on one person or one issue",
        "distractor1": "come into existence only during periods of corruption",
        "distractor2": "have dealt mainly with foreign policy issues",
        "distractor3": "have frequently forced Congress to decide Presidential elections"
    },
    {
        "question": "The actions of Jane Addams, Ida Tarbell, and Booker T. Washington illustrate that reform in the United States has",
        "correct_answer": "utilized a variety of methods to achieve many goals",
        "distractor1": "depended on support from religious groups",
        "distractor2": "relied on programs initiated by the Federal Government",
        "distractor3": "promoted women s suffrage as its main goal"
    },
    {
        "question": "Both the Sherman Antitrust Act and the Clayton Antitrust Act were passed in response to the problem of",
        "correct_answer": "business combinations limiting competition",
        "distractor1": "companies refusing to hire minority workers",
        "distractor2": "businesses choosing to hire illegal immigrants",
        "distractor3": "unsafe working conditions in factories"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Sherman Antitrust Act and the Clayton Antitrust Act were passed in an effort to",
        "correct_answer": "maintain competition in business",
        "distractor1": "promote the formation of new trusts",
        "distractor2": "increase business investment",
        "distractor3": "limit the activities of foreign corporations"
    },
    {
        "question": "One idea that both Booker T. Washington and W. E. B. Du Bois supported is that",
        "correct_answer": "African Americans should have increased civil rights",
        "distractor1": "vocational training was the best approach to education",
        "distractor2": "immigration was responsible for racial segregation",
        "distractor3": "Jim Crow laws were needed to help African Americans"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which leader founded a vocational training institution in the late 1800s to improve economic opportunities for African Americans?",
        "correct_answer": "Booker T. Washington",
        "distractor1": "George Washington Carver",
        "distractor2": "Frederick Douglass",
        "distractor3": "W. E. B. Du Bois"
    },
    {
        "question": "The initiative, referendum, and recall election were supported by the Progressives as ways to",
        "correct_answer": "increase citizen participation in the political process",
        "distractor1": "limit government regulation of the press",
        "distractor2": "limit the role of the Supreme Court in constitutional issues",
        "distractor3": "increase the influence of major political parties"
    },
    {
        "question": "Jacob Riis, in How the Other Half Lives, and Lincoln Steffens, in The Shame of the Cities, contributed to reform movements in the United States by",
        "correct_answer": "exposing poverty and corruption",
        "distractor1": "opposing westward expansion",
        "distractor2": "criticizing racial injustice",
        "distractor3": "supporting organized labor"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lincoln Steffens and Jane Addams are best known for",
        "correct_answer": "attempting to ease the problems of the urban poor",
        "distractor1": "fighting for temperance and Prohibition",
        "distractor2": "leading political movements on behalf of the Populist Party",
        "distractor3": "promoting the interests of organized labor"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Clayton Antitrust Act was passed to",
        "correct_answer": "restore business competition",
        "distractor1": "end stock market speculation",
        "distractor2": "prosecute corrupt labor unions",
        "distractor3": "break up city political party machines"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Federal Reserve System attempts to manage the United States economy by",
        "correct_answer": "regulating interest rates",
        "distractor1": "setting tariff rates",
        "distractor2": "raising or lowering income taxes",
        "distractor3": "insuring bank accounts"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was a significant impact of the Progressive movement on American life?",
        "correct_answer": "increased government regulation of business",
        "distractor1": "increased restrictions on presidential  powers",
        "distractor2": "decreased influence of the media on public policy",
        "distractor3": "reduced government spending for social programs"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Fourteen Points and the Atlantic Charter were both",
        "correct_answer": "statements of post-war goals for establishing world peace",
        "distractor1": "plans of victorious nations to divide conquered territories",
        "distractor2": "military strategies for defeating enemy nations",
        "distractor3": "agreements between nations to eliminate further development of weapons"
    },
    {
        "question": " The most stringent protection of free speech would not protect a man in falsely shouting fire in a theater and causing a panic.\"",
        "correct_answer": "Constitutional protections of liberty are not absolute.",
        "distractor1": "The needs of the government are more important than civil liberties.",
        "distractor2": "The Supreme Court can eliminate freedoms listed in the Bill of Rights.",
        "distractor3": "The Bill of Rights does not safeguard individual liberties."
    },
    {
        "question": "From 1914 to 1916, as World War I raged in Europe, Americans were not able to remain neutral in thought as well as action mainly because",
        "correct_answer": "the warring powers interfered with the United States right to freedom of the seas",
        "distractor1": "United States membership in military alliances required the nation to fight",
        "distractor2": "United States newspapers encouraged a policy of imperialist expansion",
        "distractor3": "President Woodrow Wilson supported the war aims of Germany and Austria-Hungary"
    },
    {
        "question": "After World War I, the opposition of some Members of Congress to the Versailles Treaty was based largely on the idea that the Treaty",
        "correct_answer": "would require the United States to join the League of Nations and might result in a loss of United States sovereignty",
        "distractor1": "did not punish the Central Powers harshly enough",
        "distractor2": "did not give the United States an important role in world affairs",
        "distractor3": "would require the United States to assume the cost of rebuilding the war-torn European economies"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"clear and present danger\" ruling of the Supreme Court in  Schenck v. United States  illustrates the continuing conflict between",
        "correct_answer": "free speech and governmental authority",
        "distractor1": "the use of search warrants and the rights of the accused",
        "distractor2": "state powers and Federal powers",
        "distractor3": "religious freedom and separation of church and state"
    },
    {
        "question": "President Woodrow Wilson s Fourteen Points were intended to",
        "correct_answer": "prevent international tensions from leading to war",
        "distractor1": "make the United States, Great Britain, and France into leading world powers",
        "distractor2": "redistribute Germany s colonies among the Allied nations",
        "distractor3": "punish Germany for causing World War I"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"clear and present danger\" ruling in the Supreme Court case  Schenck v. United States  (1919) confirmed the idea that",
        "correct_answer": "constitutional rights are not absolute",
        "distractor1": "prayer in public schools is unconstitutional",
        "distractor2": "racism in the United States is illegal",
        "distractor3": "interstate commerce can be regulated by state governments"
    },
    {
        "question": "A major reason for the isolationist trend in the United States following World War I was",
        "correct_answer": "a disillusionment over the outcomes of the war",
        "distractor1": "a desire to continue the reforms of the Progressives",
        "distractor2": "the public s desire to end most trade with other nations",
        "distractor3": "the failure of the United States to gain new territory"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"We are to be an instrument in the hands of God to see that liberty is made secure for mankind.\"",
        "correct_answer": "urging the Allies to adopt the Fourteen Points",
        "distractor1": "protesting the sinking of the Lusitania",
        "distractor2": "proposing a program of civil rights for minorities in American society",
        "distractor3": "taking control of territories conquered in World War I"
    },
    {
        "question": "In stating the principle of a \"clear and present danger\" in  Schenck v. United States , the Supreme Court established that",
        "correct_answer": "constitutional rights are not absolute",
        "distractor1": "the Constitution guarantees the right to privacy",
        "distractor2": "Congress can pass a law to eliminate any part of the Bill of Rights",
        "distractor3": "all individual rights are eliminated during wartime"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which action best demonstrated the United States effort to isolate itself from European conflicts after World War I?",
        "correct_answer": "refusing to join the League of Nations",
        "distractor1": "lowering tariff rates",
        "distractor2": "attempting to improve relations with Asia",
        "distractor3": "failing to sign international disarmament agreements"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which generalization is consistent with the ruling of the United States Supreme Court in  Schenck v. United States ?",
        "correct_answer": "Individual rights can be limited in the national interest",
        "distractor1": "The freedoms guaranteed in the Bill of Rights are virtually unlimited",
        "distractor2": "Government has the right to suspend any rights at any time.",
        "distractor3": "The balance between individual rights and the general social welfare almost always favors individual rights."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Woodrow Wilson s statement  The world must be made safe for democracy  was made to justify his decision to",
        "correct_answer": "ask Congress to declare war against Germany",
        "distractor1": "end United States imperialism in Latin America",
        "distractor2": "support tariff reform",
        "distractor3": "send troops into Mexico to capture Pancho Villa"
    },
    {
        "question": "President Woodrow Wilson s Fourteen Points were based on the belief that",
        "correct_answer": "the principle of self-determination should be applied to people of all nations",
        "distractor1": "military strength is a nation s best path to world peace",
        "distractor2": "isolationism should guide international relations",
        "distractor3": "industrial nations should have equal access to colonial possessions"
    },
    {
        "question": "The demand for German war reparations by the European Allies helps to explain the failure of the peace settlement following",
        "correct_answer": "World War I",
        "distractor1": "World War II",
        "distractor2": "the Korean War",
        "distractor3": "the Vietnam War"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was a major reason for United States entry into World War I?",
        "correct_answer": "to maintain freedom of the seas",
        "distractor1": "to overthrow the czarist government of Russia",
        "distractor2": "to keep Latin America from being attacked by Germany",
        "distractor3": "to break up the colonial empires of the Allies"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which situation was the immediate cause of the United States entry into World War I in 1917?",
        "correct_answer": "German submarines sank United States merchant ships.",
        "distractor1": "The League of Nations requested help.",
        "distractor2": "The Maine was blown up in Havana Harbor.",
        "distractor3": "Nazi tyranny threatened Western democracy."
    },
    {
        "question": "Why did the Senate reject the Versailles Treaty (1919)?",
        "correct_answer": "to keep the United States free from foreign entanglements",
        "distractor1": "to express opposition to the harsh sanctions imposed on Germany",
        "distractor2": "to avoid the dues for membership in the League of Nations",
        "distractor3": "to reduce United States military forces in Europe"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which argument did President Woodrow Wilson use to persuade Congress to enter World War I?",
        "correct_answer": "making the world safe for democracy",
        "distractor1": "retaliating against the Japanese bombing of Pearl Harbor",
        "distractor2": "assisting the neutral nations with their defense",
        "distractor3": "removing the Nazi threat from the Western Hemisphere"
    },
    {
        "question": "Data from this graph support the conclusion that World War I",
        "correct_answer": "was a significant benefit to the American economy",
        "distractor1": "caused the United States trade deficit to increase",
        "distractor2": "cost the United States many billions of dollars",
        "distractor3": "created an unfavorable balance of trade"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the case Schenck v. United States (1919), the United States Supreme Court settled the issue of limits on individual freedoms during wartime by establishing the",
        "correct_answer": "clear and present danger test",
        "distractor1": "states  rights principle",
        "distractor2": "separate but equal doctrine",
        "distractor3": "popular sovereignty principle"
    },
    {
        "question": "Many senators who opposed United States membership in the League of Nations argued that joining the League would",
        "correct_answer": "involve the nation in future military conflicts",
        "distractor1": "reduce freedom of the seas",
        "distractor2": "end the country s free-trade policy",
        "distractor3": "endanger the nation s military preparedness"
    },
    {
        "question": "During World War I, many American women helped gain support for the suffrage movement by",
        "correct_answer": "working in wartime industries",
        "distractor1": "protesting against the war",
        "distractor2": "joining the military service",
        "distractor3": "lobbying for child-care facilities"
    },
    {
        "question": "Following World War I, the United States Senate refused to ratify the Treaty of Versailles primarily because the treaty",
        "correct_answer": "contained provisions that might lead the United States into foreign conflicts",
        "distractor1": "failed to include most of President Wilson s Fourteen Points",
        "distractor2": "did not punish Germany for starting the war",
        "distractor3": "made no provision for reduction of military weapons"
    },
    {
        "question": "The migration of African Americans to the North during and following World War I was mainly a result of the",
        "correct_answer": "availability of new factory jobs",
        "distractor1": "success of military desegregation",
        "distractor2": "efforts of the civil rights movement",
        "distractor3": "impact of affirmative action programs"
    },
    {
        "question": "One goal for a lasting peace that President Woodrow Wilson included in his Fourteen Points was",
        "correct_answer": "establishing a League of Nations",
        "distractor1": "maintaining a permanent military force in Europe",
        "distractor2": "returning the United States to a policy of isolationism",
        "distractor3": "blaming Germany for causing World War I"
    },
    {
        "question": "The  clear and present danger  doctrine stated by the Supreme Court in the case of Schenck v. United States (1919) had an important impact on the Bill of Rights because it",
        "correct_answer": "placed limits on freedom of speech",
        "distractor1": "limited the powers of the president",
        "distractor2": "clarified standards for a fair trial",
        "distractor3": "expanded the rights of persons accused of crimes"
    },
    {
        "question": "During his reelection campaign in 1916, President Woodrow Wilson used the slogan,  He kept us out of war.  In April of 1917, Wilson asked Congress to declare war on Germany. What helped bring about this change?",
        "correct_answer": "Germany resumed unrestricted submarine warfare.",
        "distractor1": "Bolshevik forces increased their strength in Germany and Italy.",
        "distractor2": "Britain was invaded by nations of the Central Powers.",
        "distractor3": "Russia signed a treaty of alliance with the Central Powers."
    },
    {
        "question": "The change in the nation s attitude toward membership in the League of Nations and membership in the United Nations shows the contrast between",
        "correct_answer": "isolationism and involvement",
        "distractor1": "neutrality and containment",
        "distractor2": "appeasement and internationalism",
        "distractor3": "interventionism and d tente"
    },
    {
        "question": "A major reason the United States entered World War I was to",
        "correct_answer": "safeguard freedom of the seas for United States ships",
        "distractor1": "gain additional colonial possessions",
        "distractor2": "react to the bombing of Pearl Harbor",
        "distractor3": "honor prewar commitments to its military allies"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the beginning of World War I, President Woodrow Wilson followed a traditional United States foreign policy by",
        "correct_answer": "declaring American neutrality",
        "distractor1": "refusing to permit trade with either side in the conflict",
        "distractor2": "sending troops to aid Great Britain",
        "distractor3": "requesting an immediate declaration of war against the aggressors"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conclusion can be drawn from the occurrence of the Red Scare and the decision of the Supreme Court in  Schenck v. United States ?",
        "correct_answer": "Civil rights are sometimes compromised by the public s fear of radical political groups",
        "distractor1": "Immigrants to the United States are consistently denied equal protection under the law.",
        "distractor2": "A person s best protection from persecution rests with the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor3": "Violent protests in the United States are usually met with a violent response from the government."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which factors were the major causes of the Red Scare and the Palmer Raids, which followed World War I?",
        "correct_answer": "the Bolshevik Revolution of 1917 in Russia and workers  strikes in the United States",
        "distractor1": "success of the Communist Party in congressional and Presidential elections",
        "distractor2": "race riots in Los Angeles and the revival of the Ku Klux Klan",
        "distractor3": "failure of the United States to join the League of Nations and the unpaid German war debts"
    },
    {
        "question": "Based on a study of the trial of Sacco and Vanzetti (1920 s) and the internment of Japanese Americans (1940 s), which conclusion is most accurate?",
        "correct_answer": "Nativism and racism sometimes override the ideals of constitutional democracy",
        "distractor1": "The Bill of Rights is not intended to apply to naturalized citizens",
        "distractor2": "Racial and ethnic hostilities are effectively checked by adherence to due process of law.",
        "distractor3": "Internment of suspected criminals is necessary during wartime."
    },
    {
        "question": "One way in which the Red Scare of the 1920s and McCarthyism of the 1950s were similar is that both",
        "correct_answer": "jeopardized the rights of individuals suspected of un-American activity",
        "distractor1": "occurred during times of economic depression",
        "distractor2": "addressed the issue of increased government bureaucracy after a world war",
        "distractor3": "led to the imprisonment of ethnic minorities during wartime"
    },
    {
        "question": "The trial of Sacco and Vanzetti in the 1920s was similar to the trial of the Rosenbergs in the 1950s in that both trials were accompanied by",
        "correct_answer": "nativist fears of foreign influence in the United States",
        "distractor1": "concern that the United States would sink into a depression",
        "distractor2": "public reactions against organized crime",
        "distractor3": "a grassroots movement to gain equal rights for minorities"
    },
    {
        "question": "After World War I, why did American farmers fail to share in the general economic growth of the United States?",
        "correct_answer": "Overproduction and competition caused falling prices.",
        "distractor1": "Many immigrants were settling in the west and competing with the farmers.",
        "distractor2": "The Federal Government reduced the number of acres on which farmers could grow subsidized crops.",
        "distractor3": "Farmers could not produce enough to keep up with demand."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Harlem Renaissance of the 1920 s was a period when African Americans",
        "correct_answer": "created noteworthy works of art and literature",
        "distractor1": "left the United States in large numbers to settle in Nigeria",
        "distractor2": "migrated to the West in search of land and jobs",
        "distractor3": "used civil disobedience to fight segregation in the Armed Forces"
    },
    {
        "question": "Public disregard for Prohibition and for laws prohibiting gambling indicates that",
        "correct_answer": "attempts to legislate public morality may be met with strong resistance",
        "distractor1": "the American film industry has great influence on public opinion",
        "distractor2": "the system of checks and balances does not work",
        "distractor3": "American citizens have little, if any, respect for laws"
    },
    {
        "question": "United States participation in the Washington Conference (1921), in the Kellogg-Briand Pact (1928), and in the SALT talks of the 1970 s is evidence that the United States",
        "correct_answer": "has been willing to cooperate with other nations to reduce world tensions",
        "distractor1": "has followed a free trade policy for most of the 20th century",
        "distractor2": "relies on military alliances for defense against aggression",
        "distractor3": "believes that cultural exchange programs are a way to promote international understanding"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 1920 s are sometimes called the \"Roaring Twenties\" because",
        "correct_answer": "widespread social and economic change occurred",
        "distractor1": "foreign trade prospered after World War I",
        "distractor2": "the United States assumed a leadership role in world affairs",
        "distractor3": "political reforms made government more democratic"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which condition increased the negative effects of the Great Depression?",
        "correct_answer": "Factories had to decrease production because of low demand.",
        "distractor1": "Low levels of unemployment created labor shortages.",
        "distractor2": "The demand for imported products increased.",
        "distractor3": "The Federal Government raised taxes repeatedly."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Washington Naval Conference of 1921-22 and the SALT talks of the 1970 s between the United States and the Soviet Union both reflect the belief that",
        "correct_answer": "escalating military buildups are one of the causes of war",
        "distractor1": "civil wars within nations can create international hostilities",
        "distractor2": "cultural exchange programs can reduce world tensions",
        "distractor3": "rivalry between nations over the control of natural resources is the major cause of conflict"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which generalization most accurately describes the literary works of Langston Hughes, Sinclair Lewis, and John Steinbeck?",
        "correct_answer": "Literature often reflects the times in which it is created.",
        "distractor1": "Politics and art seldom mix well.",
        "distractor2": "The best literature concerns the lives of the wealthy.",
        "distractor3": "Traditional American themes are the most popular."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was one similarity between the Red Scare following World War I and the Cold War following World War II?",
        "correct_answer": "Fear of communism led to the suppression of the civil liberties of some Americans.",
        "distractor1": "Large numbers of Russian revolutionaries set-tled in the United States.",
        "distractor2": "Congressional investigations proved that the Federal Government was heavily infiltrated by Communist spies.",
        "distractor3": "Renewed fighting between wartime enemies was a constant threat."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which events best support the image of the 1920 s as a decade of nativist sentiment?",
        "correct_answer": "the passage of the National Origins Act and the rise of the Ku Klux Klan",
        "distractor1": "the Scopes trial and the passage of women s suffrage",
        "distractor2": "the Washington Naval Conference and the Kellogg-Briand Pact",
        "distractor3": "the growth of the auto industry and the Teapot Dome Affair"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the United States, the decade of the 1920 s was characterized by",
        "correct_answer": "increased consumer borrowing and spending",
        "distractor1": "a willingness to encourage immigration to the United States",
        "distractor2": "the active involvement of the United States in European affairs",
        "distractor3": "major reforms in national labor legislation"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 1920 s, the depressed situation of United States agriculture was chiefly caused by",
        "correct_answer": "mechanization and overproduction",
        "distractor1": "overregulation by government",
        "distractor2": "inefficient production techniques",
        "distractor3": "stock-market speculation"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 1920 s, the Immigration Act of 1924 and the Sacco-Vanzetti trial were typical of the",
        "correct_answer": "increase in nativism and intolerance",
        "distractor1": "rejection of traditional customs and beliefs",
        "distractor2": "acceptance of cultural differences",
        "distractor3": "support of humanitarian causes"
    },
    {
        "question": "The economic boom and the financial speculation of the 1920 s were caused in part by",
        "correct_answer": "installment buying and an unregulated stock market",
        "distractor1": "the expansion of civil rights to women and minorities",
        "distractor2": "the mobilization of the economy for war",
        "distractor3": "increased government restrictions on big business"
    },
    {
        "question": "  Speaker A:  \"To preserve our American culture, people whose national origins do not match the origins of our nation s founders must be refused admission.\"",
        "correct_answer": "Speaker C",
        "distractor1": "Speaker A",
        "distractor2": "Speaker B",
        "distractor3": "Speaker D"
    },
    {
        "question": "After World War I, which factor was the major cause of the migration of many African Americans to the North?",
        "correct_answer": "increased job opportunities in Northern cities",
        "distractor1": "the start of the Harlem Renaissance",
        "distractor2": "laws passed in Northern States to end racial discrimination",
        "distractor3": "Federal Government job-training programs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which feature of the immigration laws of the 1920 s was different from prior laws?",
        "correct_answer": "Quotas were set to limit immigration from many countries",
        "distractor1": "Preference was granted to Chinese immigrants",
        "distractor2": "Refugees from war-torn Europe were encour-aged to enter the United States.",
        "distractor3": "Efforts were made to stop illegal immigration from Latin America."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which combination of factors contributed most to the start of the Great Depression of the 1930 s?",
        "correct_answer": "overproduction and the excessive use of credit",
        "distractor1": "immigration restrictions and a lack of skilled workers",
        "distractor2": "high taxes and overspending on social welfare programs",
        "distractor3": "United States war debts and the declining value of the dollar"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conclusion can be drawn from the occurrence of the Red Scare and the decision of the Supreme Court in  Schenck v. United States ?",
        "correct_answer": "Civil rights are sometimes compromised by the public s fear of radical political groups",
        "distractor1": "Immigrants to the United States are consistently denied equal protection under the law.",
        "distractor2": "A person s best protection from persecution rests with the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor3": "Violent protests in the United States are usually met with a violent response from the government."
    },
    {
        "question": " How the Other Half Lives , Jacob Riis (1890)  The Jungle , Upton Sinclair (1906)",
        "correct_answer": "These works have had significant influence on social, political, and economic reforms.",
        "distractor1": "Most Americans have developed a preference for escapist and romantic literature.",
        "distractor2": "Most American authors have adopted a conservative viewpoint",
        "distractor3": "American business has corrected poor conditions quickly."
    },
    {
        "question": "A result of the Harlem Renaissance of the 1920s was the",
        "correct_answer": "increased recognition of African-American writers and musicians",
        "distractor1": "restoration of buildings and the infrastructure in New York City",
        "distractor2": "end of racial segregation laws in New York State",
        "distractor3": "appointment of several African Americans as presidential advisors"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 1925 trial of John Scopes reflects the conflict between",
        "correct_answer": "science and religion",
        "distractor1": "isolation and international involvement",
        "distractor2": "traditional roles and new roles for women",
        "distractor3": "Prohibition and organized crime"
    },
    {
        "question": " The business of America is business.    President Calvin Coolidge. By making this statement, President Coolidge was expressing his support for",
        "correct_answer": "the free-enterprise system",
        "distractor1": "higher taxes on corporations",
        "distractor2": "banking regulations",
        "distractor3": "democratic socialism"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which action is an example of nativism in the 1920s?",
        "correct_answer": "passage of laws restricting immigration",
        "distractor1": "widespread violation of Prohibition laws",
        "distractor2": "efforts to improve living conditions for Native American Indians",
        "distractor3": "provision of credit to farmers"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which economic practice became significantly more widespread during the 1920s?",
        "correct_answer": "stock market speculation",
        "distractor1": "governmental regulation of business",
        "distractor2": "dependence on government welfare programs",
        "distractor3": "reduction of tariff rates"
    },
    {
        "question": "A significant cause of the Great Depression of the 1930 s was that",
        "correct_answer": "some banking policies were unsound and had led to the overexpansion of credit",
        "distractor1": "a decrease in protective tariffs had opened American business to competition from abroad",
        "distractor2": "a wave of violent strikes had paralyzed the major industries",
        "distractor3": "consumer goods were relatively inexpensive"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 1930 s, the enactment of New Deal programs demonstrated a belief that",
        "correct_answer": "the Federal Government must concern itself with the people s economic well-being",
        "distractor1": "corporations were best left to operate without government interference",
        "distractor2": "state governments should give up control over commerce inside their states",
        "distractor3": "the United States Constitution was not relevant to 20th-century life"
    },
    {
        "question": "Critics charged that President Franklin D. Roosevelt s plan to increase the number of Supreme Court Justices was clearly in conflict with",
        "correct_answer": "the constitutional principle of checks and balances",
        "distractor1": "the Supreme Court s practice of judicial restraint",
        "distractor2": "attempts of Congress to limit judicial responsibilities",
        "distractor3": "efforts to restrict the number of terms a President could serve"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which New Deal program was chiefly designed to correct abuses in the stock market?",
        "correct_answer": "Securities and Exchange Commission",
        "distractor1": "Federal Emergency Relief Act",
        "distractor2": "Civilian Conservation Corps",
        "distractor3": "Works Progress Administration"
    },
    {
        "question": "During President Franklin D. Roosevelt s administration, which situation was viewed by critics as a threat to the principle of separation of powers?",
        "correct_answer": "proposing the expansion of Supreme Court membership",
        "distractor1": "changing the date of the Presidential inauguration",
        "distractor2": "congressional support of banking legislation",
        "distractor3": "passage of Social Security legislation"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main purpose of New Deal measures such as the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) was to",
        "correct_answer": "develop rules to limit speculation and safeguard savings",
        "distractor1": "provide immediate employment opportunities",
        "distractor2": "enable the Federal Government to take over failing industries",
        "distractor3": "assure a guaranteed income for American families"
    },
    {
        "question": "A lasting result of the New Deal in the United States has been the",
        "correct_answer": "assumption by the Federal Government of greater responsibility for the nation s well-being",
        "distractor1": "reduction of the national debt",
        "distractor2": "control of stock prices by the Federal Government",
        "distractor3": "joint effort of business and labor to strengthen the Presidency"
    },
    {
        "question": "During World War II, women and minorities made economic gains mainly because",
        "correct_answer": "a shortage of traditional labor created new opportunities in the workplace",
        "distractor1": "more educational opportunities increased the number of skilled workers in these groups",
        "distractor2": "labor unions successfully demanded equal opportunities for these groups",
        "distractor3": "new civil rights legislation forced businesses to change their hiring practices"
    },
    {
        "question": "A major cause of the internment of Japanese Americans during World War II was",
        "correct_answer": "racial prejudice",
        "distractor1": "national segregation policies",
        "distractor2": "immigration quotas",
        "distractor3": "economic depression"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the early 1940 s, the \"destroyers-for-military-bases deal\" with Great Britain and the Lend-Lease Act were evidence that the United States",
        "correct_answer": "recognized that its policy of neutrality conflicted with its self-interest",
        "distractor1": "followed its policy of neutrality more strictly as World War II progressed in Europe",
        "distractor2": "believed that the Allied policy of appeasement would succeed",
        "distractor3": "wanted to honor the military commitments it had made just after World War I"
    },
    {
        "question": "A violation of civil rights that occurred in the United States during World War II was the",
        "correct_answer": "internment of Japanese Americans",
        "distractor1": "arrests made as a result of the Palmer raids",
        "distractor2": "passage of an open immi-gration law",
        "distractor3": "forced removal of Native American Indians from their reservations"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Lend-Lease Act and the Destroyers-for-Bases deal were adopted prior to World War II primarily because these actions would",
        "correct_answer": "help Allied nations without the United States entering the war",
        "distractor1": "stop the spread of communism",
        "distractor2": "convince the American people that war was necessary",
        "distractor3": "create jobs to end the Great Depression"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about Japanese Americans interned during World War II is most accurate?",
        "correct_answer": "Many lost their homes and businesses",
        "distractor1": "Many were forced to return to Japan at the conclusion of the war.",
        "distractor2": "No Japanese Americans were allowed to serve in the United States armed services during the war.",
        "distractor3": "Most were released after signing a loyalty oath"
    },
    {
        "question": "President Harry Truman s decision to use atomic bombs against Japan was primarily based on his belief that",
        "correct_answer": "an invasion of Japan would result in excessive casualties",
        "distractor1": "Germany would refuse to surrender in Europe",
        "distractor2": "an alliance was developing between Japan and the Soviet Union",
        "distractor3": "Japan was in the process of developing its own atomic weapons"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which action best illustrates the policy of isolationism followed by the United States before it entered World War II?",
        "correct_answer": "passage of neutrality legislation forbidding arms sales to warring nations",
        "distractor1": "signing of a collective security pact with Latin American nations",
        "distractor2": "embargo on the sale of gasoline and steel to Japan",
        "distractor3": "President Franklin D. Roosevelt s exchange of American destroyers for British naval and air bases"
    },
    {
        "question": "President Harry Truman justified using atomic bombs on Japan in 1945 on the grounds that the",
        "correct_answer": "early ending of the war would save many lives",
        "distractor1": "world was ready for a demonstration of nuclear power",
        "distractor2": "Axis powers deserved total destruction",
        "distractor3": "American public demanded that the bombs be used"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which precedent was established by the Nuremberg war crimes trials?",
        "correct_answer": "National leaders can be held responsible for crimes against humanity .",
        "distractor1": "Only individuals who actually commit murder during a war can be guilty of a crime.",
        "distractor2": "Defeated nations cannot be forced to pay reparations.",
        "distractor3": "Defeated nations can be occupied by the victors."
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1988, Congress voted to pay $20,000 to each of the surviving Americans of Japanese descent who were interned during World War II because",
        "correct_answer": "many Americans believed the internment was unjust and unnecessary",
        "distractor1": "the danger of war with Japan no longer existed",
        "distractor2": "all of the interned Japanese Americans eventually became American citizens",
        "distractor3": "the World Court ordered the United States to pay reparations"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"The great rule of conduct for us in regard to foreign nations is, in extending our commercial relations, to have with them as little political connection as possible.\"",
        "correct_answer": "neutrality",
        "distractor1": "imperialism",
        "distractor2": "appeasement",
        "distractor3": "economic sanctions"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 1930 s, the United States attempted to avoid a repetition of the events leading up to United States involvement in World War I by",
        "correct_answer": "passing a series of neutrality laws",
        "distractor1": "establishing the Good Neighbor policy with Latin American nations",
        "distractor2": "forgiving the foreign debts incurred during World War I",
        "distractor3": "officially recognizing the existence of the Soviet Union"
    },
    {
        "question": "How did the personal diplomacy conducted by President Franklin D. Roosevelt during World War II affect the Presidency?",
        "correct_answer": "The President s role in shaping United States foreign policy was strengthened.",
        "distractor1": "Subsequent Presidents have refused to use this unsuccessful method.",
        "distractor2": "The President s war powers as Commander in Chief were sharply reduced.",
        "distractor3": "Congress increased its power over the executive branch."
    },
    {
        "question": "As World War II was ending, the United States decided to join the United Nations mainly because the United States",
        "correct_answer": "recognized that efforts to achieve world peace required United States involvement",
        "distractor1": "sought to meet the American public s overwhelming demand for free-trade agreements",
        "distractor2": "wanted to continue to play the same role it had in the League of Nations",
        "distractor3": "wanted to stop the growing influence of newly independent developing nations"
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States became involved in World War II primarily because",
        "correct_answer": "Germany and Japan achieved important military successes in Europe and Asia",
        "distractor1": "Germany refused to pay its debts from World War I",
        "distractor2": "European democracies supported United States policies toward Germany and Japan",
        "distractor3": "President Franklin D. Roosevelt did not enforce the Neutrality Acts"
    },
    {
        "question": "  Speaker A:  \"We must take action even if we are not sure it will work. To do nothing to stop them would be a repeat of the Munich mistake.\"",
        "correct_answer": "appeasement",
        "distractor1": "interdependence",
        "distractor2": "balance of power",
        "distractor3": "collective security"
    },
    {
        "question": "After World War II, the United States was better able than its allies to adjust its economy from wartime to peacetime because the United States",
        "correct_answer": "had suffered no widespread wartime destruction",
        "distractor1": "possessed nuclear weapons",
        "distractor2": "raised tariffs on imports",
        "distractor3": "had collected its war debts from the Allies"
    },
    {
        "question": "An immediate effect of the Lend-Lease program was that",
        "correct_answer": "the United States provided critical aid to Great Britain and the Soviet Union",
        "distractor1": "Western Europe recovered from the damage caused by World War I",
        "distractor2": "the Soviet Union formed the Warsaw Pact",
        "distractor3": "Japan declared war against the United States"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Japanese attack on Pearl Harbor in 1941 is an illustration of the",
        "correct_answer": "impact a single event can have on public opinion a time of crisis",
        "distractor1": "effectiveness of a policy of appeasement in stopping aggression",
        "distractor2": "success of the pacifist movement in the United States",
        "distractor3": "role of communism as a negative influence in global affairs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which congressional action not only raised money for World War II but also contributed to the national debt?",
        "correct_answer": "selling war bonds",
        "distractor1": "requiring employers to withhold taxes from workers  paychecks",
        "distractor2": "raising income tax rates",
        "distractor3": "enacting wage and price controls"
    },
    {
        "question": "The rulings of the Supreme Court in Dred Scott v. Sanford  (1857),  Plessy v. Ferguson  (1896), and  Korematsu v. United States  (1944) all demonstrate that the Supreme Court has",
        "correct_answer": "sometimes failed to protect the rights of minorities",
        "distractor1": "continued to extend voting rights to minorities",
        "distractor2": "protected itself from internal dissent",
        "distractor3": "often imposed restrictions on free speech during wartime"
    },
    {
        "question": "Based on a study of the trial of Sacco and Vanzetti (1920 s) and the internment of Japanese Americans (1940 s), which conclusion is most accurate?",
        "correct_answer": "Nativism and racism sometimes override the ideals of constitutional democracy",
        "distractor1": "The Bill of Rights is not intended to apply to naturalized citizens",
        "distractor2": "Racial and ethnic hostilities are effectively checked by adherence to due process of law.",
        "distractor3": "Internment of suspected criminals is necessary during wartime."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was a key challenge faced by the United States during World War II?",
        "correct_answer": "fighting the war on several fronts",
        "distractor1": "lack of public support for the war effort",
        "distractor2": "difficulty gaining congressional support",
        "distractor3": "total reliance on naval power"
    },
    {
        "question": "How did the post World War II baby boom affect American society between 1945 and 1960?",
        "correct_answer": "It increased the need for educational resources.",
        "distractor1": "It decreased the demand for housing.",
        "distractor2": "It bankrupted the Social Security System.",
        "distractor3": "It encouraged people to migrate to the Sun Belt."
    },
    {
        "question": "World War I and World War II brought about changes for minorities and women because these conflicts led to",
        "correct_answer": "the creation of new job opportunities",
        "distractor1": "the passage of the Equal Rights Amendment",
        "distractor2": "a greater number of high-level management positions",
        "distractor3": "greater integration in housing and schools throughout the nation"
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States Supreme Court decision in Korematsu v. United States (1944) concerned",
        "correct_answer": "limiting civil liberties during wartime",
        "distractor1": "restricting freedom of the press",
        "distractor2": "the president s right to use atomic weapons",
        "distractor3": "the right of women to serve in military combat"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement identifies a change in American society during World War II?",
        "correct_answer": "Economic opportunities for women increased",
        "distractor1": "Government regulation of the economy decreased.",
        "distractor2": "The Great Depression worsened.",
        "distractor3": "Racial tensions were eliminated."
    },
    {
        "question": "After World War II, the Marshall Plan was proposed as a way to",
        "correct_answer": "help European nations recover economically",
        "distractor1": "improve diplomatic relations with the Soviet Union",
        "distractor2": "remove nuclear weapons from Western Europe",
        "distractor3": "bring Nazi war criminals to justice"
    },
    {
        "question": "President Harry Truman supported a containment policy after World War II in an attempt to",
        "correct_answer": "reduce the influence of the Soviet Union in European countries",
        "distractor1": "limit the use of atomic bombs and other nuclear weapons",
        "distractor2": "end colonialism in Africa and Asia",
        "distractor3": "bring German and Japanese war criminals to justice"
    },
    {
        "question": "Korematsu was not ",
        "correct_answer": "Individual rights can be restricted under certain circumstances.",
        "distractor1": "Individual rights need to be maintained in national emergencies.",
        "distractor2": "The Supreme Court lacks the power to block presidential actions taken during wartime.",
        "distractor3": "Only the Supreme Court can alter the constitutional rights of American citizens."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the period following World War II, the United States established a long-term military presence in West Germany in an effort to",
        "correct_answer": "stop communist expansion in Europe",
        "distractor1": "support the unification of Europe, by force if necessary",
        "distractor2": "prevent the renewal of German aggression in  Europe",
        "distractor3": "allow the United Nations to resolve international disputes"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to United States entry into World War II, Congress passed the Cash-and-Carry Act of 1939 and the Lend-Lease Act of 1941. These foreign policy actions showed that the United States",
        "correct_answer": "became increasingly drawn into the war in Europe",
        "distractor1": "gave equal support to both the Allied and Axis Powers",
        "distractor2": "attempted to contain the spread of communism",
        "distractor3": "maintained a strict policy of isolationism"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the early years of World War II, the Destroyer Deal and the Lend-Lease Act were efforts by the United States to",
        "correct_answer": "help the Allies without formally declaring war",
        "distractor1": "maintain strict neutrality toward the war",
        "distractor2": "negotiate a settlement of the war",
        "distractor3": "provide help to both sides in the war"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which change in United States foreign policy is demonstrated by the passage of these acts prior to World War II? Cash and Carry (1937) Destroyers for Naval Bases Deal (1940) Lend-Lease Act (1941)",
        "correct_answer": "a shift from neutrality toward more direct involvement",
        "distractor1": "an effort to become more neutral",
        "distractor2": "a movement from isolationism to containment of communism",
        "distractor3": "a desire to provide aid to both Allied and Axis powers"
    },
    {
        "question": "During World War II, many women experienced a change in role in that they",
        "correct_answer": "worked in jobs formerly held by men",
        "distractor1": "served in military combat positions",
        "distractor2": "controlled most corporations",
        "distractor3": "chaired several congressional committees"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 1944 case Korematsu v. United States, the Supreme Court ruled that wartime conditions justified the",
        "correct_answer": "limitations placed on civil liberties",
        "distractor1": "use of women in military combat",
        "distractor2": "ban against strikes by workers",
        "distractor3": "reduction in the powers of the president"
    },
    {
        "question": "During World War II, posters of Rosie the Riveter were used to",
        "correct_answer": "recruit women into wartime industries",
        "distractor1": "encourage women to serve in the armed forces",
        "distractor2": "promote women s suffrage",
        "distractor3": "support higher education for women"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was one result of World War II?",
        "correct_answer": "Two superpowers emerged.",
        "distractor1": "The arms race ended.",
        "distractor2": "The Cold War ended.",
        "distractor3": "Communism was eliminated."
    },
    {
        "question": "Convictions of war criminals by courts at Tokyo and Nuremberg following World War II showed that",
        "correct_answer": "government officials and military leaders could be held accountable for their actions",
        "distractor1": "the United Nations accepted responsibility for international peacekeeping",
        "distractor2": "the League of Nations could successfully enforce international law",
        "distractor3": "nations that start wars would be forced to rebuild war-torn nations"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which federal policy was enacted during World War II and justified as a wartime necessity?",
        "correct_answer": "internment of Japanese Americans",
        "distractor1": "a ban on German-language books",
        "distractor2": "exclusion of Chinese immigrants",
        "distractor3": "adoption of the quota system of immigration"
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1944, Congress enacted the GI Bill of Rights in order to",
        "correct_answer": "provide economic aid to veterans",
        "distractor1": "reduce military expenditures",
        "distractor2": "ban racial segregation in the armed forces",
        "distractor3": "create government jobs for returning soldiers"
    },
    {
        "question": "During World War II, this poster was used primarily to",
        "correct_answer": "gain financial support for the war",
        "distractor1": "contain the spread of communism",
        "distractor2": "create jobs for the unemployed",
        "distractor3": "convince women to fill vacant factory jobs"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 1930s, Congress attempted to avoid the situations that led to United States involvement in World War I by",
        "correct_answer": "passing a series of neutrality acts",
        "distractor1": "enacting a peacetime draft law",
        "distractor2": "authorizing the deportation of American Communist Party members",
        "distractor3": "relocating Japanese Americans to internment camps"
    },
    {
        "question": "During World War II, the federal government used rationing to",
        "correct_answer": "provide more resources for the military",
        "distractor1": "hold down prices of military weapons",
        "distractor2": "increase educational benefits for veterans",
        "distractor3": "increase imports of scarce products"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the main purpose of the GI Bill passed by Congress shortly before the end of World War II?",
        "correct_answer": "to provide economic aid to veterans",
        "distractor1": "to offer low-interest loans to the defense industry",
        "distractor2": "to contain the spread of international communism",
        "distractor3": "to expand career opportunities in the military"
    },
    {
        "question": "During World War II, many Japanese Americans living on the West Coast were relocated to detention centers primarily because they",
        "correct_answer": "were seen as a security threat",
        "distractor1": "were known spies for Japan",
        "distractor2": "refused to serve in the United States military",
        "distractor3": "expressed their support for Italy and Germany"
    },
    {
        "question": "To help pay for World War II, the United States government relied heavily on the",
        "correct_answer": "sale of war bonds",
        "distractor1": "money borrowed from foreign governments",
        "distractor2": "sale of United States manufactured goods to neutral nations",
        "distractor3": "printing of additional paper money"
    },
    {
        "question": "The decision of the Supreme Court in Korematsu v. United States (1944) upheld the power of the president during wartime to",
        "correct_answer": "limit a group s civil liberties",
        "distractor1": "ban terrorists from entering the country",
        "distractor2": "stop mistreatment of resident legal aliens",
        "distractor3": "deport persons who work for enemy nations"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why was the United States called the  arsenal of democracy  in 1940?",
        "correct_answer": "The United States provided much of the weaponry needed to fight the Axis powers.",
        "distractor1": "The leaders in the democratic nations of Europe were educated in the United States",
        "distractor2": "Most of the battles to defend worldwide democracy took place on American soil.",
        "distractor3": "The United States supervised elections in European nations before the war."
    },
    {
        "question": "Shortly after entering World War II, the United States began the Manhattan Project to",
        "correct_answer": "work on the development of an atomic bomb",
        "distractor1": "increase economic production to meet wartime demands",
        "distractor2": "defend New York City against a nuclear attack",
        "distractor3": "recruit men for the military services"
    },
    {
        "question": "The experiences of African Americans serving in the military forces during World War II influenced their postwar decision to",
        "correct_answer": "increase efforts to end racial discrimination",
        "distractor1": "renew support for the principle of separate but equal",
        "distractor2": "join the armed forces in record numbers",
        "distractor3": "move back to the rural south"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which wartime policy toward Japanese Americans was upheld by the Supreme Court in its 1944 ruling in Korematsu v. United States?",
        "correct_answer": "confinement in internment camps",
        "distractor1": "deportation to Japan",
        "distractor2": "mandatory military service",
        "distractor3": "denial of voting rights"
    },
    {
        "question": "A controversial issue that resulted from World War II was the",
        "correct_answer": "morality of nuclear warfare",
        "distractor1": "future role of the League of Nations",
        "distractor2": "commitment of troops without congressional approval",
        "distractor3": "civilian control of the military"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the beginning of World War II, national debate focused on whether the United States should continue the policy of",
        "correct_answer": "isolationism",
        "distractor1": "coexistence",
        "distractor2": "containment",
        "distractor3": "imperialism"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before entering World War II, the United States acted as the  arsenal of democracy  by",
        "correct_answer": "supplying war materials to the Allies",
        "distractor1": "financing overseas radio broadcasts in support of democracy",
        "distractor2": "creating a weapons stockpile for use after the war",
        "distractor3": "providing workers for overseas factories"
    },
    {
        "question": "One reason the Nuremberg trials following World War II were held was to",
        "correct_answer": "make German leaders accountable for the Holocaust",
        "distractor1": "bring Hitler, Mussolini, and Tojo to justice",
        "distractor2": "force Japan to pay for the attack on Pearl Harbor",
        "distractor3": "punish the German government for bombing England"
    },
    {
        "question": " Arms Sales to Warring Nations Banned   Americans Forbidden to Travel on Ships of Warring Nations ",
        "correct_answer": "avoid participation in European wars",
        "distractor1": "maintain freedom of the seas",
        "distractor2": "send military supplies to the League of Nations",
        "distractor3": "limit the spread of international communism"
    },
    {
        "question": "A main purpose of government-ordered rationing during World War II was to",
        "correct_answer": "conserve raw materials for the war effort",
        "distractor1": "increase foreign trade",
        "distractor2": "limit the growth of industry",
        "distractor3": "encourage women to enter the workforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "This World War II cartoon was used to encourage Americans to",
        "correct_answer": "conserve natural resources",
        "distractor1": "buy war bonds",
        "distractor2": "serve in the armed forces",
        "distractor3": "work in war industries"
    },
    {
        "question": "A major purpose of the GI Bill (1944) was to",
        "correct_answer": "provide federal funds for veterans to attend college",
        "distractor1": "replace the draft near the end of World War II",
        "distractor2": "prohibit racial discrimination in the armed forces",
        "distractor3": "increase the number of women working in defense industries"
    },
    {
        "question": "A similarity between the Red Scare of the 1920 s and McCarthyism in the 1950 s was that during each period",
        "correct_answer": "the civil liberties of American citizens were threatened",
        "distractor1": "thousands of American citizens were expelled from the United States",
        "distractor2": "the Communist Party gained many members in the United States",
        "distractor3": "many government employees were convicted of giving secrets to the Soviet Union"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which situation resulted from Senator Joseph McCarthy s search for Communists within the United States during the 1950 s?",
        "correct_answer": "The reputations of many people were ruined by false accusations of disloyalty",
        "distractor1": "Thousands of American citizens who believed in communism were either jailed or deported.",
        "distractor2": "Many high-ranking government officials were exposed as spies of the Soviet Union.",
        "distractor3": "Organized groups of Communists began a wave of violent political terrorism."
    },
    {
        "question": "The successful launching of Sputnik by the Soviet Union in 1957 signaled the beginning of",
        "correct_answer": "American fears that the Soviets had achieved technological superiority",
        "distractor1": "the Cold War with the United States",
        "distractor2": "Soviet aggression in Afghanistan and China",
        "distractor3": "disarmament discussions between the superpowers"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 1950 s, Senator Joseph McCarthy was most closely associated with issues related to",
        "correct_answer": "Communist infiltration and the denial of civil liberties",
        "distractor1": "farm problems and taxation",
        "distractor2": "military preparedness and foreign aid",
        "distractor3": "collective bargaining and the rights of unions"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Those of us who shout the loudest about Americanism in making character assassinations are all too frequently those who, by our own words and acts, ignore some of the basic principles of Americanism.\"",
        "correct_answer": "Senator McCarthy was a greater threat to the nation than Communist sympathizers were",
        "distractor1": "Senator McCarthy did not do enough to protect the nation from a Communist conspiracy",
        "distractor2": "the tactics of Senator McCarthy were necessary to protect the basic principles of democracy",
        "distractor3": "free speech must be limited in times of national crisis"
    },
    {
        "question": "A governmental action that was consistent with the Cold War mentality was the",
        "correct_answer": "establishment of loyalty reviews of government employees",
        "distractor1": "reduction in military defense spending",
        "distractor2": "elimination of the Central Intelligence Agency",
        "distractor3": "adoption of the GI Bill of Rights"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which would be the most appropriate entry for line D in the list below?",
        "correct_answer": "Loyalty oaths",
        "distractor1": "Labor unrest",
        "distractor2": "Racial segregation",
        "distractor3": "Wage and price controls"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a farewell message to the American public, President Dwight D. Eisenhower warned of the growth of the \"military-industrial complex.\" This term refers to the",
        "correct_answer": "influence of defense contractors on Congress",
        "distractor1": "threat from the Soviet Army",
        "distractor2": "internal danger from Communist spies",
        "distractor3": "economy s dependence on oil imported from the Middle East"
    },
    {
        "question": "Most Americans who opposed sending United States troops to fight in the Vietnam War believed that",
        "correct_answer": "the United States should not police the world",
        "distractor1": "nuclear weapons should be used to end the war",
        "distractor2": "the war should be extended into China",
        "distractor3": "international trade would be interrupted"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the United States, the Red Scare of 1919 and the McCarthy Era of the early 1950 s were periods of",
        "correct_answer": "persecution of people suspected of holding anti-American political views",
        "distractor1": "severe economic depression",
        "distractor2": "widespread support for groups promoting international anarchy",
        "distractor3": "great growth in art, literature, and music"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was one similarity between the Red Scare following World War I and the Cold War following World War II?",
        "correct_answer": "Fear of communism led to the suppression of the civil liberties of some Americans.",
        "distractor1": "Large numbers of Russian revolutionaries set-tled in the United States.",
        "distractor2": "Congressional investigations proved that the Federal Government was heavily infiltrated by Communist spies.",
        "distractor3": "Renewed fighting between wartime enemies was a constant threat."
    },
    {
        "question": "The growth of McCarthyism in the early 1950s was based on",
        "correct_answer": "public fear concerning the spread of communism",
        "distractor1": "outrage over government corruption",
        "distractor2": "dissatisfaction with the results of World War II",
        "distractor3": "opposition to the policy of containment"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was a cause for the investigations of the House Un-American Activities Committee in the late 1940s and the investigations of a Senate committee headed by Joseph McCarthy in the early 1950s?",
        "correct_answer": "the belief that there were Communist agents in the federal government",
        "distractor1": "excessive spending by the United States military",
        "distractor2": "the corruption and bribery of members of Congress",
        "distractor3": "actions of President Harry Truman that might have led to his impeachment"
    },
    {
        "question": " Sputnik Launch Propels Soviets Ahead in Space Race  In 1957, the United States government responded to the event described in this headline by",
        "correct_answer": "providing funds to improve the educational system in the United States",
        "distractor1": "reducing military spending",
        "distractor2": "building a joint space station with the Soviet Union",
        "distractor3": "constructing President Ronald Reagan s  Star Wars  defense system"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which development following World War II caused the urban-suburban pattern shown in the diagram?",
        "correct_answer": "expansion of highways and automobile ownership",
        "distractor1": "increase in the number of farms",
        "distractor2": "movement of most factories to rural areas",
        "distractor3": "decline in the number of middle-income families"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the post World War II era, Senator Joseph McCarthy and the House Un-American Activities Committee attempted to",
        "correct_answer": "identify Communists in the government and elsewhere in American society",
        "distractor1": "develop an effective system for spying on other countries",
        "distractor2": "make Cold War programs a priority in United States foreign policy",
        "distractor3": "establish a policy of d tente with the Soviet Union"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who led a  witch hunt  for Communist spies in the United States government during the early 1950s?",
        "correct_answer": "Senator Joseph McCarthy",
        "distractor1": "Supreme Court Justice Earl Warren",
        "distractor2": "President Dwight Eisenhower",
        "distractor3": "Secretary of State Dean Acheson"
    },
    {
        "question": "The baby boom primarily resulted from the",
        "correct_answer": "delay in marriages during World War II",
        "distractor1": "economic prosperity of the 1920s",
        "distractor2": "Great Depression of the 1930s",
        "distractor3": "counterculture movement of the 1960s"
    },
    {
        "question": "Since the 1950s, the term McCarthyism has been applied to events that are related to",
        "correct_answer": "reckless accusations unsupported by evidence",
        "distractor1": "the basic rights of citizens to own and carry guns",
        "distractor2": "the violent activities of international terrorists",
        "distractor3": "questionable methods used to finance political campaigns"
    },
    {
        "question": "The immediate impact of the 1957 launch of Sputnik I was that it",
        "correct_answer": "heightened the space race as a form of Cold War competition",
        "distractor1": "forced the United States to find new sources of fuel",
        "distractor2": "focused attention on the need to regulate the uses of outer space",
        "distractor3": "ended the period of peaceful coexistence between the United States and the Soviet"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the main purpose of the GI Bill passed by Congress shortly before the end of World War II?",
        "correct_answer": "to provide economic aid to veterans",
        "distractor1": "to offer low-interest loans to the defense industry",
        "distractor2": "to contain the spread of international communism",
        "distractor3": "to expand career opportunities in the military"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does this photograph indicate about the United States in the 1950s?",
        "correct_answer": "Much fear was created by the Cold War.",
        "distractor1": "Extraordinary steps were taken to hide atomic weapons.",
        "distractor2": "The nation had become the only nuclear superpower.",
        "distractor3": "Only government officials would be safe in a nuclear attack."
    },
    {
        "question": "The rapid growth in personal income in the decade after World War II contributed to",
        "correct_answer": "expansion of the middle class",
        "distractor1": "a decrease in the birthrate",
        "distractor2": "a major economic depression",
        "distractor3": "shortages in the supply of luxury goods"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which event of the 1950s most likely led to the publication of this cartoon?",
        "correct_answer": "The Soviet Union launched the Sputnik satellite.",
        "distractor1": "Russia put cosmonauts on the Moon.",
        "distractor2": "The United States was defeated in the Vietnam War.",
        "distractor3": "American students scored low on tests in math and science."
    },
    {
        "question": "The GI Bill affected American society after World War II by",
        "correct_answer": "extending educational and housing opportunities",
        "distractor1": "eliminating child labor",
        "distractor2": "expanding voting rights",
        "distractor3": "increasing spending on space exploration"
    },
    {
        "question": "The changes shown on the chart most clearly reflect the",
        "correct_answer": "effects of the Cold War",
        "distractor1": "influence of the business cycle",
        "distractor2": "failure of United States military policy",
        "distractor3": "reverses in political party control of Congress"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before ratification of the 22nd amendment in 1951, most presidents served no more than two terms because of",
        "correct_answer": "custom and tradition",
        "distractor1": "a federal law",
        "distractor2": "the elastic clause",
        "distractor3": "a Supreme Court decision"
    },
    {
        "question": "The protestors in the photograph are expressing their hatred for",
        "correct_answer": "communists",
        "distractor1": "fascists",
        "distractor2": "immigrants",
        "distractor3": "police officers"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which factor is most closely associated with McCarthyism?",
        "correct_answer": "fear of communist influence in the United States",
        "distractor1": "buildup of Soviet missiles in Cuba",
        "distractor2": "rise of the Communist Party in China",
        "distractor3": "creation of the Warsaw Pact by the Soviet Union"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which development led to the other three?",
        "correct_answer": "The Soviet Union launched the Sputnik satellite.",
        "distractor1": "The United States government increased funding for science and math education.",
        "distractor2": "A joint Soviet-American space mission was announced.",
        "distractor3": "President John F. Kennedy set the goal of landing a man on the Moon."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Truman Doctrine and the Marshall Plan represented attempts by the United States to deal with the",
        "correct_answer": "spread of communism",
        "distractor1": "national debt",
        "distractor2": "President s political opposition",
        "distractor3": "arms race"
    },
    {
        "question": "Both the Bay of Pigs invasion of Cuba (1961) and the invasion of Panama (1989) are examples of United States attempts to",
        "correct_answer": "eliminate unfriendly governments geographically close to the United States",
        "distractor1": "cultivate good relations with Latin American nations",
        "distractor2": "stop the drug trade",
        "distractor3": "end the Cold War"
    },
    {
        "question": "The speakers below are discussing foreign policies that the United States has followed at various times. Base your answers on their statements and on your knowledge of social studies. Speaker A: Steer clear of permanent alliances with any portion of the foreign world.",
        "correct_answer": "C",
        "distractor1": "A",
        "distractor2": "B",
        "distractor3": "D"
    },
    {
        "question": "The speakers below are discussing foreign policies that the United States has followed at various times. Base your answers on their statements and on your knowledge of social studies. Speaker A: Steer clear of permanent alliances with any portion of the foreign world.",
        "correct_answer": "C and D",
        "distractor1": "A and B",
        "distractor2": "A and C",
        "distractor3": "B and D"
    },
    {
        "question": " An attack on one shall be considered an attack on all.  This statement summarizes the foreign policy known a",
        "correct_answer": "collective security",
        "distractor1": "colonialism",
        "distractor2": "nonalignment",
        "distractor3": "appeasement"
    },
    {
        "question": "Shortly after World War II, the cold war developed mainly as a result of the",
        "correct_answer": "Soviet domination of Eastern Europe",
        "distractor1": "United States refusal to send economic aid to European nations",
        "distractor2": "competition between the superpowers to explore outer space",
        "distractor3": "continuation of the pre-World War II balance of power"
    },
    {
        "question": "A common purpose of the Truman Doctrine, the Marshall Plan, and the Eisenhower Doctrine was to",
        "correct_answer": "carry out the United States policy of preventing the spread ofcommunism",
        "distractor1": "insure the survival of the newly independent nations of Africa andAsia",
        "distractor2": "limit the proliferation of nuclear weapons",
        "distractor3": "provide medical aid to LatinAmerican nations"
    },
    {
        "question": "A constitutional issue that was frequently raised about United States involvement in the Korean conflict and the Vietnam conflict was the",
        "correct_answer": "lack of a formal declaration of war by Congress",
        "distractor1": "right to regulate commerce with foreign nations",
        "distractor2": "use of deficit spending to finance wars",
        "distractor3": "Supreme Court s role in foreign policy decision-making"
    },
    {
        "question": "After World War II, the United States departed most sharply from its traditional foreign policy when it",
        "correct_answer": "organized global systems of alliances",
        "distractor1": "stopped foreign-aid programs",
        "distractor2": "sponsored disarmament treaties",
        "distractor3": "recognized revolutionary governments"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the main purpose of the Truman Doctrine, the Marshall Plan, and the Berlin air-lift?",
        "correct_answer": "limiting Soviet expansion",
        "distractor1": "controlling Nazism in Europe",
        "distractor2": "establishing friendly relations between the United States and the Soviet Union",
        "distractor3": "spreading democracy to developing nations"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the years just after World War II, the United States attempted to prevent the spread of communism in Europe mainly by",
        "correct_answer": "establishing policies of economic and military aid for European nations",
        "distractor1": "taking over the governments of several Western European nations",
        "distractor2": "increasing opportunities for political refugees to settle in the United States",
        "distractor3": "holding a series of summit meetings with leaders of the Soviet Union"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Korean War and the Persian Gulf War were similar in that both",
        "correct_answer": "represented United Nations efforts to assist nations in repelling aggressors",
        "distractor1": "involved unilateral military action by the United States",
        "distractor2": "were military defeats for the United Nations",
        "distractor3": "brought about lasting solutions to problems in each region"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Many foreign peoples, in Europe at least, are . . . frightened by experiences of the past and are less interested in . . . freedom than in security . They are seeking guidance rather than responsibilities. We should be better able than the Russians to give them this. And unless we do, the Russians certainly will.\"",
        "correct_answer": "develop the Marshall Plan",
        "distractor1": "drop atomic bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki",
        "distractor2": "end segregation in the Armed Forces",
        "distractor3": "deport any person suspected of being a Communist"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the Korean War, what was the main reason that President Harry Truman dismissed General Douglas MacArthur as commander of the United States troops?",
        "correct_answer": "President Truman believed that General MacArthur s conduct threatened the concept of civilian control over the military",
        "distractor1": "The United States had suffered many severe military losses.",
        "distractor2": "Congress refused to appropriate any more money to support the war.",
        "distractor3": "General MacArthur disobeyed President Truman by deciding to stop fighting the war."
    },
    {
        "question": "During the Cold War Era, the easing of tensions between the United States and the Soviet Union resulted in",
        "correct_answer": "a treaty banning nuclear tests",
        "distractor1": "the organization of the Warsaw Pact",
        "distractor2": "the invasion of Hungary and Czechoslovakia",
        "distractor3": "the Berlin Airlift"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a valid conclusion based on United States involvement in the Korean War?",
        "correct_answer": "The policy of containment was applied in Asia as well as in Europe",
        "distractor1": "United Nations economic sanctions are more effective than military action.",
        "distractor2": "The American people will support United States participation in any war, whether declared or undeclared.",
        "distractor3": "United States cooperation with a wartime ally ends when the war ends."
    },
    {
        "question": "A major long-term effect of the Vietnam War has been",
        "correct_answer": "a reluctance to commit United States troops for extended military action abroad",
        "distractor1": "an end to communist governments in Asia",
        "distractor2": "a change in United States foreign policy from containment to imperialism",
        "distractor3": "a continued boycott of trade with Asia"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Truman Doctrine and the Eisenhower Doctrine were United States foreign policies concerning",
        "correct_answer": "the containment of communism",
        "distractor1": "the international balance of payments",
        "distractor2": "world-wide environmental pollution",
        "distractor3": "nuclear disarmament"
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary purpose of the War Powers Act (1973) is to",
        "correct_answer": "limit Presidential power to send troops into combat",
        "distractor1": "allow for a quicker response to a military attack",
        "distractor2": "assure adequate defense of the Western Hemisphere",
        "distractor3": "stop the use of troops for nonmilitary purposes"
    },
    {
        "question": "\". . . Let every nation know, whether it wishes us well or ill, that we shall pay any price, bear any burden, meet any hardship, support any friend, oppose any foe to assure the survival and the success of liberty.\"",
        "correct_answer": "President Kennedy was encouraging a very strong presence in foreign policy in the post-World War II period.",
        "distractor1": "The Cold War was over, and the Soviet Union was beginning to unravel.",
        "distractor2": "Compromise and appeasement were the best avenues to world peace.",
        "distractor3": "President Kennedy understood the limitations of power, even for a strong nation like the United States"
    },
    {
        "question": "The intent of the War Powers Act of 1973 is to limit the President s power to",
        "correct_answer": "commit troops to major military operations in a foreign nation",
        "distractor1": "send troops to rescue Americans held captive by terrorists in a foreign nation",
        "distractor2": "use troops to defend against an armed attack on the United States",
        "distractor3": "send troops to suppress a riot in an American city"
    },
    {
        "question": "From the end of World War II until the 1980 s, the United States carried out its foreign policy mainly by",
        "correct_answer": "taking a variety of actions to prevent the spread of communism",
        "distractor1": "giving in to foreign demands",
        "distractor2": "avoiding any situation that might involve the nation in a conflict",
        "distractor3": "acting forcefully to obtain and control colonies"
    },
    {
        "question": "One similarity between the Korean War and the Persian Gulf War is that in each conflict the",
        "correct_answer": "United Nations took action to halt the aggression",
        "distractor1": "United States attempted to limit traffic through the Suez Canal",
        "distractor2": "sentimet of the American public turned against the conflict",
        "distractor3": "dictators of North Korea and Iraq were removed from office"
    },
    {
        "question": "Throughout United States history, the most important aim of the country s foreign policy has been",
        "correct_answer": "advancement of national self interest",
        "distractor1": "participation in international organizations",
        "distractor2": "containment of communism",
        "distractor3": "development of military alliances"
    },
    {
        "question": "United States annexation of the Philippines (1898) and military involvement in Vietnam (1960 s and 1970 s) are similar because in each event the United States",
        "correct_answer": "provoked domestic debate about its involvement in the internal affairs of other nations",
        "distractor1": "achieved its long-range foreign policy objectives",
        "distractor2": "put the domino theory into action",
        "distractor3": "demonstrated the strength and success of its military power"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Peace Corps was established by President John F. Kennedy in an effort to provide",
        "correct_answer": "support to developing nations of the world",
        "distractor1": "job training for the unemployed",
        "distractor2": "markets for consumer goods",
        "distractor3": "teachers for inner-city areas"
    },
    {
        "question": "President John F. Kennedy supported the 1961 Bay of Pigs invasion of Cuba as an effort to",
        "correct_answer": "remove a communist dictator from power",
        "distractor1": "stop the flow of illegal drugs to the United States",
        "distractor2": "support Fidel Castro s efforts for reform",
        "distractor3": "rescue hostages held by Cuban freedom fighters"
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States experience in the Vietnam War supports the idea that the outcome of a war",
        "correct_answer": "can be strongly affected by public opinion",
        "distractor1": "is determined mainly by technological superiority",
        "distractor2": "is dependent on using the greatest number of soldiers",
        "distractor3": "is assured to countries dedicated to democratic ideals"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which event led directly to the end of the cold war?",
        "correct_answer": "breakup of the Soviet Union",
        "distractor1": "reunification of Germany",
        "distractor2": "formation of the European Union",
        "distractor3": "creation of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO)"
    },
    {
        "question": "One way in which the Korean War, the Vietnam War, and the Persian Gulf War are similar is that in all three wars",
        "correct_answer": "no formal declaration of war was made by Congress",
        "distractor1": "the goal was to defeat the Soviet Union",
        "distractor2": "the United States was primarily interested in protecting oil supplies",
        "distractor3": "the United States was fighting without allies"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which foreign policy decision by President Harry Truman is an example of the policy of containment?",
        "correct_answer": "providing military aid to Greece and Turkey",
        "distractor1": "relieving General MacArthur of his Korean command",
        "distractor2": "recognizing the new nation of Israel",
        "distractor3": "supporting the trials of war criminals in Germany and Japan"
    },
    {
        "question": " Batista Driven from Power   Bay of Pigs Invasion Fails ",
        "correct_answer": "Cuba",
        "distractor1": "Canada",
        "distractor2": "Mexico",
        "distractor3": "Panama"
    },
    {
        "question": "One reason for the creation of the Peace Corps by President John F. Kennedy was to",
        "correct_answer": "give support to developing nations",
        "distractor1": "stop the spread of AIDS in Africa and Asia",
        "distractor2": "gain control of territory in Latin America",
        "distractor3": "provide workers for industrial nations"
    },
    {
        "question": "Issuing the Truman Doctrine, defending South Korea, and sending military advisors to Vietnam were actions taken by the United States to",
        "correct_answer": "limit the spread of communism",
        "distractor1": "encourage membership in the United Nations",
        "distractor2": "promote American business in Asia",
        "distractor3": "gain additional overseas colonies"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which action was taken by the United States government to help Europe s economic recovery after World War II?",
        "correct_answer": "creating the Marshall Plan",
        "distractor1": "forming the Alliance for Progress",
        "distractor2": "sending troops to Turkey",
        "distractor3": "joining the North Atlantic Treaty Organization"
    },
    {
        "question": "The cartoonist is commenting on which Cold War foreign policy?",
        "correct_answer": "d tente ",
        "distractor1": "brinkmanship ",
        "distractor2": "the domino theory",
        "distractor3": "collective security"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which United States foreign policy decision most clearly reflects the relationship shown in the cartoon?",
        "correct_answer": "negotiation of the Strategic Arms Limitation Treaty (SALT)",
        "distractor1": "issuance of the Eisenhower Doctrine",
        "distractor2": "quarantine of Cuba",
        "distractor3": "support of Israel in the Six Day War"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Truman Doctrine, President Harry Truman pledged to",
        "correct_answer": "support Greece in its fight against communist aggression",
        "distractor1": "fight hunger in Africa and Asia",
        "distractor2": "strengthen the United States nuclear arsenal",
        "distractor3": "reject a policy of containment"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which development led to the other three?",
        "correct_answer": "The Soviet Union launched the Sputnik satellite.",
        "distractor1": "The United States government increased funding for science and math education.",
        "distractor2": "A joint Soviet-American space mission was announced.",
        "distractor3": "President John F. Kennedy set the goal of landing a man on the Moon."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which development is most closely associated with the belief in the domino theory?",
        "correct_answer": "military involvement in Vietnam",
        "distractor1": "construction of the Berlin Wall",
        "distractor2": "signing of the nuclear test ban treaty",
        "distractor3": "end of the Korean War"
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary purpose of President Richard Nixon s policy of d tente was to",
        "correct_answer": "ease tensions between the United States and the Soviet Union",
        "distractor1": "expand United States military involvement in Southeast Asia",
        "distractor2": "assure an adequate supply of oil from the Middle East",
        "distractor3": "maintain a favorable balance of trade with China"
    },
    {
        "question": "The abolitionist movement, the women s suffrage movement, and the 1960 s civil rights movement are all examples of reform efforts that",
        "correct_answer": "developed significant popular support",
        "distractor1": "succeeded without causing major controversy",
        "distractor2": "achieved their goals without government action",
        "distractor3": "failed to affect the nation as a whole"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which generalization can most accurately be drawn from a study of Supreme Court cases Plessy v. Ferguson and Brown v. Board of Education?",
        "correct_answer": "The Supreme Court has helped to determine public policy.",
        "distractor1": "The Supreme Court has issued consistent decisions in cases involving rights of the accused.",
        "distractor2": "Supreme Court decisions are accepted without public controversy.",
        "distractor3": "The Justices believe that social issues are best left for state courts to decide."
    },
    {
        "question": "The major goal of the civil rights movement of the 1960 s was to",
        "correct_answer": "end segregation based on race",
        "distractor1": "establish a separate political state for African Americans",
        "distractor2": "gain passage of an equal rights amendment to the Constitution",
        "distractor3": "permit unlimited immigration to the United States"
    },
    {
        "question": "An original purpose of affirmative action programs was to",
        "correct_answer": "increase educational and employment opportunities for women and minorities",
        "distractor1": "improve the Amencan economy by guaranteeing that employees will be highly skilled",
        "distractor2": "decrease social welfare costs by requiring recipients of public assistance to work",
        "distractor3": "reduce the Federal deficit by increasing government efficiency"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under Chief Justice Earl Warren, the Supreme Court was considered \"activist\" because of its",
        "correct_answer": "expansion of individual rights in criminal cases",
        "distractor1": "reluctance to overturn state laws",
        "distractor2": "insistence on restricting freedom of speech to spoken words",
        "distractor3": "refusal to reconsider the issues of the Plessy v. Ferguson case"
    },
    {
        "question": "When necessary to achieve justice, which method did Martin Luther King, Jr., urge his followers to employ?",
        "correct_answer": "engaging in civil disobedience",
        "distractor1": "using violence to bring about political change",
        "distractor2": "leaving any community in which racism is practiced",
        "distractor3": "demanding that Congress pay reparations to African Americans"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main goal of the Seneca Falls Convention (1848) was to",
        "correct_answer": "obtain equal rights for women",
        "distractor1": "make the public aware of environmental prob-lems",
        "distractor2": "correct the abuses of big business",
        "distractor3": "organize the first labor union in the United States"
    },
    {
        "question": "When President Dwight D. Eisenhower sent Federal troops to Little Rock, Arkansas, during the 1957 school integration crisis, he was exercising his constitutional power as",
        "correct_answer": "Commander-in-Chief",
        "distractor1": "Chief Legislator",
        "distractor2": "Chief Diplomat",
        "distractor3": "Head of State"
    },
    {
        "question": "The decisions of the United States Supreme Court in  Miranda v. Arizona ,  Gideon v. Wainwright , and  Escobedo v. Illinois  all advanced the",
        "correct_answer": "rights of accused persons",
        "distractor1": "voting rights of minorities",
        "distractor2": "guarantees of free speech and press",
        "distractor3": "principle of separation of church and state"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Separate educational facilities are inherently unequal.\"  - Brown v. Board of Education  ",
        "correct_answer": "require the integration of public schools",
        "distractor1": "establish affirmative action programs in higher education",
        "distractor2": "desegregate the armed forces and the military academies",
        "distractor3": "force states to spend an equal amount on each public school student"
    },
    {
        "question": "After the passage of the 13th, 14th, and 15th amendments, African Americans continued to experience political and economic oppression mainly because",
        "correct_answer": "Southern legislatures enacted Jim Crow laws",
        "distractor1": "the amendments were not intended to solve their problems",
        "distractor2": "many African Americans distrusted the Federal Government",
        "distractor3": "poor communications kept people from learning about their legal rights"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Seneca Falls Convention of 1848 was primarily concerned with",
        "correct_answer": "bringing about equal rights for women",
        "distractor1": "carrying out Reconstruction in the South",
        "distractor2": "limiting immigration to the United States",
        "distractor3": "promoting the settlement of western territories"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Civil Rights Act of 1964 was passed in an effort to correct",
        "correct_answer": "racial and gender discrimination",
        "distractor1": "limitations on freedom of speech",
        "distractor2": "unfair immigration quotas",
        "distractor3": "segregation in the armed forces"
    },
    {
        "question": "   . . . his legislative leadership was remarkable. No President since Lincoln had done more for civil rights. Yet much of this was forgotten as American society became increasingly divided over United States participation in a bloody, undeclared war.  Which 20th-century President does this statement most accurately describe?",
        "correct_answer": "Lyndon Johnson",
        "distractor1": "Woodrow Wilson",
        "distractor2": "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
        "distractor3": "Ronald Reagan"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Great Society of Lyndon Johnson is most similar to which other Presidential program?",
        "correct_answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt s New Deal",
        "distractor1": "Warren Harding s Return to Normalcy",
        "distractor2": "Ronald Reagan s New Federalism",
        "distractor3": "George Bush s Thousand Points of Light"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Great Society programs of the 1960 s used the power of the Federal Government to bring about",
        "correct_answer": "antipoverty reforms",
        "distractor1": "an all-volunteer military",
        "distractor2": "deregulation of business",
        "distractor3": "reduced defense spending"
    },
    {
        "question": "The chief objective of President Lyndon Johnson s Great Society programs was to",
        "correct_answer": "help the disadvantaged in the United States",
        "distractor1": "increase foreign aid to developing nations",
        "distractor2": "correct environmental pollution",
        "distractor3": "unite democratic nations and contain communism"
    },
    {
        "question": "One similarity between President Franklin D. Roosevelt and President Lyndon B. Johnson is that both",
        "correct_answer": "expanded the power of the Presidency",
        "distractor1": "believed strongly in States rights",
        "distractor2": "supported a strict construction of the Constitution",
        "distractor3": "opposed most civil rights legislation"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which action was a common objective of President Franklin D. Roosevelt s New Deal and President Lyndon B. Johnson s Great Society?",
        "correct_answer": "helping those living in poverty",
        "distractor1": "eliminating nuclear weapons",
        "distractor2": "lowering barriers to immigration",
        "distractor3": "breaking up business monopolies"
    },
    {
        "question": "President Lyndon B. Johnson s Great Society is similar to President Franklin D. Roosevelt s New Deal in that both programs",
        "correct_answer": "supported federal funding of programs for the poor",
        "distractor1": "sought ratification of the Equal Rights Amendment to guarantee equality for women",
        "distractor2": "advocated passage of civil rights laws to help African Americans",
        "distractor3": "approved efforts by states to reduce taxes for the middle class"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which situation was a result of the Vietnam War?",
        "correct_answer": "The United States questioned its role as a police officer of the world.",
        "distractor1": "South Vietnam was able to maintain its noncommunist status.",
        "distractor2": "Richard Nixon was forced to resign the presidency.",
        "distractor3": "The War Powers Act was repealed by Congress."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which initiative was part of President Lyndon Johnson s Great Society program?",
        "correct_answer": "providing medical care to the poor and elderly",
        "distractor1": "reducing federal aid to education",
        "distractor2": "increasing foreign aid to the Soviet Union",
        "distractor3": "opposing civil rights legislation"
    },
    {
        "question": "One reason the United States became involved in the Vietnam War was to",
        "correct_answer": "prevent the spread of communism in Indochina",
        "distractor1": "reduce French influence in Vietnam",
        "distractor2": "stop China from seizing Vietnam",
        "distractor3": "support the government of North Vietnam"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which federal government program was designed to solve the problem illustrated in this cartoon?",
        "correct_answer": "Great Society",
        "distractor1": "Peace Corps",
        "distractor2": "New Federalism",
        "distractor3": "Dollar Diplomacy"
    },
    {
        "question": "President Lyndon Johnson s Great Society programs were similar to Progressive Era programs in that both",
        "correct_answer": "used federal government power to improve social conditions",
        "distractor1": "strictly enforced antitrust laws",
        "distractor2": "focused on expanding civil rights for African Americans",
        "distractor3": "made urban renewal their primary concern"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Feminine Mystique by Betty Friedan was an influential book in the 1960s because it",
        "correct_answer": "energized a new women s rights movement",
        "distractor1": "helped strengthen family values",
        "distractor2": "led directly to the defeat of the Equal Rights Amendment",
        "distractor3": "reinforced the importance of women s traditional roles"
    },
    {
        "question": "A major goal of President Lyndon B. Johnson s Great Society was to",
        "correct_answer": "end poverty in the United States",
        "distractor1": "provide government aid to business",
        "distractor2": "conserve natural resources",
        "distractor3": "stop emigration from Latin America"
    },
    {
        "question": "The program that promotes preference in hiring for African Americans and other minorities to correct past injustices is known as",
        "correct_answer": "affirmative action",
        "distractor1": "Title IX",
        "distractor2": "open admissions",
        "distractor3": "Head Start"
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1965, Congress established Medicare to",
        "correct_answer": "provide health care to the elderly",
        "distractor1": "assist foreign nations with their health problems",
        "distractor2": "grant scholarships to medical students",
        "distractor3": "establish universal health care"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which principle was most weakened as a result of the Watergate controversy?",
        "correct_answer": "executive privilege",
        "distractor1": "congressional immunity",
        "distractor2": "judicial review",
        "distractor3": "States' Rights"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main significance of the Watergate affair was that it",
        "correct_answer": "showed that the laws of the United States are superior to the actions of a President",
        "distractor1": "led to the impeachment and conviction of President Richard Nixon",
        "distractor2": "was the first time a President had disagreed with Congress",
        "distractor3": "proved that Presidential powers are unlimited"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Presidency of Gerald Ford was different from all previous Presidencies because he was the first President who",
        "correct_answer": "was not elected to either the Presidency or the Vice-Presidency",
        "distractor1": "won the office by running on a third-party ticket",
        "distractor2": "resigned from the office of the President",
        "distractor3": "ran for office as a nonpartisan candidate"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"President Nixon Plans Trip to China To Meet with Chairman Mao\"",
        "correct_answer": "chief diplomat",
        "distractor1": "head of his political party",
        "distractor2": "Commander in Chief",
        "distractor3": "chief legislator"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main idea of this cartoon from the Watergate era?",
        "correct_answer": "No person or group is above the law.",
        "distractor1": "The Supreme Court presides over a presidential impeachment trial.",
        "distractor2": "Congress has to obey the Constitution.",
        "distractor3": "The president has the final word involving constitutional issues."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was a lasting effect of the Watergate scandal under President Richard Nixon?",
        "correct_answer": "Trust in elected officials was undermined.",
        "distractor1": "The system of checks and balances was weakened.",
        "distractor2": "The scope of executive privilege was broadened.",
        "distractor3": "Presidential responsiveness to public opinion was lessened."
    },
    {
        "question": "The easing of Cold War tensions between the United States and the Soviet Union during the 1970s was called",
        "correct_answer": "d tente",
        "distractor1": "containment",
        "distractor2": "neutrality",
        "distractor3": "isolationism"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was a major result of the Watergate controversy?",
        "correct_answer": "The president resigned from office.",
        "distractor1": "Presidential veto power was expanded.",
        "distractor2": "Congressional power was reduced.",
        "distractor3": "The Supreme Court was weakened."
    },
    {
        "question": "President Richard Nixon supported the policy of d tente as a way to",
        "correct_answer": "reduce tensions between the United States and the Soviet Union",
        "distractor1": "introduce democratic elections to communist nations",
        "distractor2": "encourage satellite nations to break their ties with the Soviet Union",
        "distractor3": "undermine Soviet influence among nonaligned countries in Africa and Asia"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main purpose of the War Powers Act of 1973 was to",
        "correct_answer": "limit the president s ability to send troops into combat abroad",
        "distractor1": "expand the power of Congress to declare war",
        "distractor2": "allow people to vote on the issue of United States commitments overseas",
        "distractor3": "end the Vietnam War on favorable terms"
    },
    {
        "question": "The war in Vietnam led Congress to pass the War Powers Act of 1973 in order to",
        "correct_answer": "assert the role of Congress in the commitment of troops overseas",
        "distractor1": "affirm United States support for the United Nations",
        "distractor2": "strengthen the policy of d tente",
        "distractor3": "increase United States participation in international peacekeeping operations"
    },
    {
        "question": "President Richard Nixon s visit to the People s Republic of China in 1972 was significant because it",
        "correct_answer": "reduced tensions between the United States and Communist China",
        "distractor1": "convinced the Chinese to abandon communism",
        "distractor2": "brought about the unification of Taiwan and Communist China",
        "distractor3": "decreased United States dependence on Chinese exports"
    },
    {
        "question": "An effect of the War Powers Act of 1973 was that",
        "correct_answer": "the authority of the president as commander in chief was limited",
        "distractor1": "the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) became more involved in world conflicts",
        "distractor2": "congressional approval was not needed when appropriating funds for the military",
        "distractor3": "women were prevented from serving in combat roles during wartime"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main goal of President Richard Nixon s foreign policy of d tente was to",
        "correct_answer": "improve relations with the Soviet Union",
        "distractor1": "assure American victory in Vietnam",
        "distractor2": "resolve conflicts in the Middle East",
        "distractor3": "abolish the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO)"
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary purpose of President Richard Nixon s policy of d tente was to",
        "correct_answer": "ease tensions between the United States and the Soviet Union",
        "distractor1": "expand United States military involvement in Southeast Asia",
        "distractor2": "assure an adequate supply of oil from the Middle East",
        "distractor3": "maintain a favorable balance of trade with China"
    },
    {
        "question": "United States participation in the Washington Conference (1921), in the Kellogg-Briand Pact (1928), and in the SALT talks of the 1970 s is evidence that the United States",
        "correct_answer": "has been willing to cooperate with other nations to reduce world tensions",
        "distractor1": "has followed a free trade policy for most of the 20th century",
        "distractor2": "relies on military alliances for defense against aggression",
        "distractor3": "believes that cultural exchange programs are a way to promote international understanding"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is most accurate about the economy of the United States during the 1970 s and early 1980 s?",
        "correct_answer": "The increased cost of imported oil hurt economic growth.",
        "distractor1": "The Federal budget was balanced.",
        "distractor2": "Inflation declined sharply throughout these years .",
        "distractor3": "The number of jobs in farming increased while service jobs decreased."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Camp David accords negotiated during President Jimmy Carter s administration were an attempt to",
        "correct_answer": "establish peace in the Middle East",
        "distractor1": "decrease United States control of the Panama Canal",
        "distractor2": "encourage the use of solar and other nonpolluting energy sources",
        "distractor3": "end inflationary oil prices"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Washington Naval Conference of 1921-22 and the SALT talks of the 1970 s between the United States and the Soviet Union both reflect the belief that",
        "correct_answer": "escalating military buildups are one of the causes of war",
        "distractor1": "civil wars within nations can create international hostilities",
        "distractor2": "cultural exchange programs can reduce world tensions",
        "distractor3": "rivalry between nations over the control of natural resources is the major cause of conflict"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"President Nixon Plans Trip to China To Meet with Chairman Mao\"",
        "correct_answer": "chief diplomat",
        "distractor1": "head of his political party",
        "distractor2": "Commander in Chief",
        "distractor3": "chief legislator"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which factor contributed most to inflation in the United States during the 1970s?",
        "correct_answer": "oil embargoes",
        "distractor1": "high tariffs",
        "distractor2": "tax increases",
        "distractor3": "high unemployment"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which foreign policy agreement had the most direct influence on the Middle East?",
        "correct_answer": "Camp David Accords",
        "distractor1": "Kellogg-Briand Pact",
        "distractor2": "Yalta Conference declaration",
        "distractor3": "SALT I Treaty"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement most accurately describes the main idea of this 1975 cartoon?",
        "correct_answer": "The government is improperly hiding information from the public.",
        "distractor1": "The press should not publish materials that damage the reputation of public officials.",
        "distractor2": "Government should restrict the publication of sensitive materials.",
        "distractor3": "Libraries are making too many government reports open to the public."
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"supply side\" economics of President Ronald Reagan and President George Bush favored",
        "correct_answer": "providing incentives to stimulate business growth",
        "distractor1": "raising tariffs to increase the number of imports",
        "distractor2": "increasing Federal taxes to support social welfare programs",
        "distractor3": "establishing government programs to provide jobs for the unemployed"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the supply-side economics principles promoted by President Ronald Reagan, economic growth would occur when",
        "correct_answer": "corporate business taxes were reduced",
        "distractor1": "business was regulated by antitrust legislation",
        "distractor2": "unemployment benefits were increased",
        "distractor3": "investment in capital goods was decreased"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the United States, industrial unions of the 1880 s and of the 1980 s had similar goals in that both campaigned for",
        "correct_answer": "greater job security and higher wages",
        "distractor1": "national health insurance",
        "distractor2": "better unemployment insurance",
        "distractor3": "wage and price freezes"
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1988, Congress voted to pay $20,000 to each of the surviving Americans of Japanese descent who were interned during World War II because",
        "correct_answer": "many Americans believed the internment was unjust and unnecessary",
        "distractor1": "the danger of war with Japan no longer existed",
        "distractor2": "all of the interned Japanese Americans eventually became American citizens",
        "distractor3": "the World Court ordered the United States to pay reparations"
    },
    {
        "question": "A primary reason for the increase in federal debt between 1980 and 1996 was",
        "correct_answer": "high levels of spending by the federal government",
        "distractor1": "the cost of sending United States troops to Bosnia",
        "distractor2": "instability of the stock market",
        "distractor3": "lower sales tax revenues collected by state governments"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the 1980s, President Ronald Reagan used the ideas of supply-side economics to justify",
        "correct_answer": "tax cuts for businesses",
        "distractor1": "increases in social welfare spending",
        "distractor2": "expansion of the Social Security program",
        "distractor3": "reductions in military spending"
    },
    {
        "question": "A major goal of the Republican Party since the 1980s has been to",
        "correct_answer": "cut federal taxes",
        "distractor1": "increase welfare benefits",
        "distractor2": "increase the size of the federal workforce",
        "distractor3": "reduce defense spending"
    },
    {
        "question": "A major policy of President Ronald Reagan s administration was to",
        "correct_answer": "lower federal income tax rates",
        "distractor1": "reduce defense spending",
        "distractor2": "end desegregation of public facilities",
        "distractor3": "promote regulation of small businesses"
    },
    {
        "question": "President Ronald Reagan s supply-side economic policy was successful in",
        "correct_answer": "lowering tax rates on personal and business income",
        "distractor1": "increasing government spending on social programs",
        "distractor2": "reducing defense spending",
        "distractor3": "enforcing stricter environmental regulations"
    },
    {
        "question": "One important conclusion that can be drawn as a result of the United States experience in both the Spanish-American War (1898) and the Persian Gulf War (1991) is that",
        "correct_answer": "the media are a powerful influence in shaping American public opinion toward war",
        "distractor1": "only the President should decide issues of war and peace",
        "distractor2": "the public has little confidence in the ability of the American military",
        "distractor3": "international organizations play a decisive role in determining the outcome of a war"
    },
    {
        "question": "For the United States, the breakup of the Soviet Union has had the greatest effect on",
        "correct_answer": "defense spending",
        "distractor1": "import quotas",
        "distractor2": "immigration policies",
        "distractor3": "advances in technology"
    },
    {
        "question": "One direct result of the Persian Gulf War was that the United States",
        "correct_answer": "liberated Kuwait from Iraqi control",
        "distractor1": "gained control of oil resources in the Middle East",
        "distractor2": "brought about peaceful relations between Israel and its neighbors",
        "distractor3": "obtained overseas colonies in the Middle East"
    },
    {
        "question": "Since the Russian people rejected communism in the early 1990 s, the United States has provided support to the new nation by",
        "correct_answer": "giving foreign aid to Russia in the form of low-interest loans",
        "distractor1": "creating a military alliance with Russia",
        "distractor2": "destroying most United States nuclear weapons",
        "distractor3": "opposing the independence of the other Russian republics"
    },
    {
        "question": "The growth of modern technology has resulted in",
        "correct_answer": "increasing interdependence among nations",
        "distractor1": "a decrease in the population of the world",
        "distractor2": "a growing need for unskilled labor",
        "distractor3": "a sharp decline in the need for oil and coal"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the United States in the 1990 s, cuts in defense spending have been proposed because",
        "correct_answer": "communist governments in Eastern Europe and the former Soviet Union have collapsed",
        "distractor1": "Japan has assumed the peacekeeping responsibilities of the United Nations",
        "distractor2": "military technology has become less expensive",
        "distractor3": "the United States has returned to an isolationist foreign policy"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main reason that the United States sent troops to Bosnia in 1995 was to try to",
        "correct_answer": "bring a peaceful end to a civil war",
        "distractor1": "contain the spread of communism",
        "distractor2": "take over the area as a protectorate",
        "distractor3": "resettle refugees in North America"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Korean War and the Persian Gulf War were similar in that both",
        "correct_answer": "represented United Nations efforts to assist nations in repelling aggressors",
        "distractor1": "involved unilateral military action by the United States",
        "distractor2": "were military defeats for the United Nations",
        "distractor3": "brought about lasting solutions to problems in each region"
    },
    {
        "question": "One similarity between the Korean War and the Persian Gulf War is that in each conflict the",
        "correct_answer": "United Nations took action to halt the aggression",
        "distractor1": "United States attempted to limit traffic through the Suez Canal",
        "distractor2": "sentimet of the American public turned against the conflict",
        "distractor3": "dictators of North Korea and Iraq were removed from office"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the cartoon, how was the United States in the 1990s similar to the United States in the 1890s?",
        "correct_answer": "Business consolidation was accepted practice",
        "distractor1": "Little need existed for government regulation",
        "distractor2": "Investment in the stock market decreased",
        "distractor3": "The price of petroleum products decreased"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main idea of this 1997 cartoon?",
        "correct_answer": "Workers are being laid off to keep corporate profits high.",
        "distractor1": "Investors believe the stock market may crash in the near future.",
        "distractor2": "Illegal aliens are trying to come to the United States in record numbers.",
        "distractor3": "Workers still suffer from dangerous conditions on the job."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main idea of this cartoon about President Bill Clinton?",
        "correct_answer": "Positive economic conditions helped maintain his high approval ratings.",
        "distractor1": "Voter approval of the president declined due to flaws in his character.",
        "distractor2": "He did not deserve credit for the economic prosperity of the nation.",
        "distractor3": "The American public considered personal character the most important trait of a president in the 1990s."
    },
    {
        "question": "This 1991 cartoon is criticizing President George Bush for",
        "correct_answer": "using foreign affairs to hide domestic failures",
        "distractor1": "refusing to support the United Nations",
        "distractor2": "involving the United States in foreign wars",
        "distractor3": "ignoring the economic needs of developing nations"
    },
    {
        "question": "President Bill Clinton s decision to send troops to Bosnia in 1995 and to participate in the bombing of Kosovo in 1999 were both in response to international concern over",
        "correct_answer": "human rights violations",
        "distractor1": "trade agreement violations",
        "distractor2": "access to world oil reserves",
        "distractor3": "monetary policies"
    },
    {
        "question": "President Bill Clinton supported the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) primarily as a way to",
        "correct_answer": "stimulate economic growth in the United States",
        "distractor1": "normalize trade relations with Cuba",
        "distractor2": "restrict the flow of drugs into the United States",
        "distractor3": "increase the United States trade deficit"
    },
    {
        "question": "Support for the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) reflected the United States commitment to",
        "correct_answer": "globalization",
        "distractor1": "Manifest Destiny",
        "distractor2": "collective security",
        "distractor3": "isolationism"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which situation faced by President Bill Clinton is expressed in the cartoon?",
        "correct_answer": "International problems interfered with domestic policy goals.",
        "distractor1": "Impeachment hampered his ability to carry out programs.",
        "distractor2": "Health care costs took away funds needed for peacekeeping commitments.",
        "distractor3": "Budget deficits prevented military action in world trouble spots."
    },
    {
        "question": " Clinton Offers Economic Aid to Russia   U.S. Sends Peacekeeping Troops to Bosnia ",
        "correct_answer": "global involvement",
        "distractor1": "containment",
        "distractor2": "collective security",
        "distractor3": "neutrality"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is most clearly supported by the information in the graph?",
        "correct_answer": "Fewer women are staying home to raise their young children.",
        "distractor1": "More children were under age 6 in 1990 than in 1950.",
        "distractor2": "Since 1990, women have made up more than half of the workforce.",
        "distractor3": "The gap between male and female incomes has declined."
    },
    {
        "question": "A candidate for public office would likely conclude from a study of this graph that the public would favor increased government support for",
        "correct_answer": "child day-care centers",
        "distractor1": "additional foreign aid",
        "distractor2": "health care facilities",
        "distractor3": "colleges and universities"
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1991, one of the reasons President George H. W. Bush committed United States troops to the Persian Gulf War was to",
        "correct_answer": "assure the flow of Middle East oil to the United States and its allies",
        "distractor1": "maintain the flow of trade through the Suez Canal",
        "distractor2": "fulfill military obligations as a member of the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA)",
        "distractor3": "contain the spread of communism in the Middle East"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the United States, support for the passage and expansion of the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) has been strongest among",
        "correct_answer": "big business",
        "distractor1": "labor unions",
        "distractor2": "environmentalists",
        "distractor3": "farmers"
    },
    {
        "question": "The point of view expressed in this cartoon is that",
        "correct_answer": "Democrats sometimes support traditionally Republican issues",
        "distractor1": "President and Mrs. Clinton have made Chicago their new home",
        "distractor2": "President Clinton supports adoption over abortion",
        "distractor3": "Republican issues should not be part of the Democratic National Convention"
    },
    {
        "question": "The beginning of the collapse of communism in Eastern Europe is most closely associated with the",
        "correct_answer": "fall of the Berlin Wall",
        "distractor1": "admission of Warsaw Pact nations to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO)",
        "distractor2": "intervention of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) in Yugoslavia",
        "distractor3": "formation of the European Union"
    },
    {
        "question": "Data from the graphs most clearly support the conclusion that by the mid-1990s, American women as a group",
        "correct_answer": "had gained more opportunities in professional areas",
        "distractor1": "surpassed men in the number of businesses owned and law degrees received",
        "distractor2": "had given up marriage in favor of careers outside the home",
        "distractor3": "earned more than men in the legal profession"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which trend has reflected the increasing pluralism in United States society in recent years?",
        "correct_answer": "new efforts by public schools to teach about ethnic heritages",
        "distractor1": "a decrease in immigration from Latin America",
        "distractor2": "growing demands for unskilled labor",
        "distractor3": "failure of Congress to approve appointments of women and minority groups to Federal courts"
    },
    {
        "question": "The goal of current Federal Government policies toward Native Americans is to",
        "correct_answer": "give Native Americans more control over their own affairs",
        "distractor1": "make Native Americans more dependent on the Federal Government",
        "distractor2": "give the states more control over Native American affairs",
        "distractor3": "eliminate tribal ties and customs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement best summarizes economic conditions in the United States since the end of World War II?",
        "correct_answer": "The United States has come to depend more heavily on imports to meet its economic needs.",
        "distractor1": "The economy has been in a depression for most of the period.",
        "distractor2": "The United States has had the world s highest unemployment rate.",
        "distractor3": "The legal minimum wage has steadily declined."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the United States, most new jobs created during the 1980 s were jobs that",
        "correct_answer": "provided services rather than produced goods",
        "distractor1": "were classified as managerial",
        "distractor2": "depended on heavy manufacturing",
        "distractor3": "were farm related"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the most valid conclusion that may be drawn from the study of population patterns in the United States today?",
        "correct_answer": "Most of the population is concentrated in and around large urban centers.",
        "distractor1": "The number of ethnic groups has declined.",
        "distractor2": "The population of the South has continued to decline.",
        "distractor3": "The Northeast is the fastest growing region in the nation."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is an opinion rather than a fact?",
        "correct_answer": "Executions are a major deterrent to violent crime.",
        "distractor1": "Penalties for crimes vary from state to state.",
        "distractor2": "Most European nations no longer use capital punishment.",
        "distractor3": "Most murders in the United States occur within families or among acquaintances."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the last 20 years, the use of automation in United States industry has led to",
        "correct_answer": "increased unemployment among unskilled workers",
        "distractor1": "a shortage of consumer goods",
        "distractor2": "increased union membership",
        "distractor3": "the lowering of the legal minimum wage"
    },
    {
        "question": "The power of the Presidency has increased in the 20th century mainly because",
        "correct_answer": "events have often required the personal diplomacy and leadership of the President",
        "distractor1": "Congress has granted much of its authority to the President",
        "distractor2": "constitutional amendments have increased the power of the executive branch",
        "distractor3": "Supreme Court rulings have enhanced Presidential authority"
    },
    {
        "question": "The reason for ending the importation of enslaved persons to the United States after 1807 was the",
        "correct_answer": "passage of legislation that forbids the practice",
        "distractor1": "success of the American colonial revolution against Britain",
        "distractor2": "rapid industrialization of the South",
        "distractor3": "replacement of slave labor by immigrant workers from eastern Europe"
    },
    {
        "question": "One similarity between the actions of Samuel Gompers and Cesar Chavez is that both leaders",
        "correct_answer": "organized workers to strive for better conditions",
        "distractor1": "relied on the use of force to gain minority rights",
        "distractor2": "advocated federal regulation of railroad rates",
        "distractor3": "worked to improve consumer product safety"
    },
    {
        "question": "One similarity in the presidential administrations of Abraham Lincoln, Franklin D. Roosevelt, and Lyndon Johnson is that each",
        "correct_answer": "expanded the power of the presidency",
        "distractor1": "maintained a foreign policy of neutrality",
        "distractor2": "removed Supreme Court Justices from office",
        "distractor3": "decreased the size of the military"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Pacific [Transcontinental] Railway Act (1862) and the Interstate Highway Act (1956) are both examples of",
        "correct_answer": "federally supported internal improvement projects linking the nation",
        "distractor1": "regional construction projects coordinated by southern and western states",
        "distractor2": "military projects required to meet the needs of the defense industry",
        "distractor3": "transportation legislation designed to encourage foreign trade"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mark Twain, Langston Hughes, and John Steinbeck made their most important contributions to the United States in the field of",
        "correct_answer": "literature",
        "distractor1": "music ",
        "distractor2": "politics ",
        "distractor3": "business"
    },
    {
        "question": "One way in which the New Deal, the Fair Deal, and the Great Society are similar is that these programs",
        "correct_answer": "increased government commitment to the well-being of the people",
        "distractor1": "promoted the idea of  rugged individualism ",
        "distractor2": "reduced the amount of money spent on domestic programs",
        "distractor3": "encouraged the states to take a more active role in national defense"
    },
    {
        "question": "One way in which Andrew Jackson, Abraham Lincoln, and Woodrow Wilson are similar is that each",
        "correct_answer": "expanded presidential powers",
        "distractor1": "reduced the size of the federal bureaucracy",
        "distractor2": "faced congressional investigations over the handling of the military",
        "distractor3": "used his power as commander in chief to send troops overseas to fight a war"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these trials established the principle that leaders of a nation may be tried for crimes against humanity?",
        "correct_answer": "Nuremberg",
        "distractor1": "Scopes ",
        "distractor2": "Rosenberg ",
        "distractor3": "Sacco and Vanzetti"
    },
    {
        "question": "One similarity between the laws being challenged in the United States Supreme Court cases of Plessy v. Ferguson (1896) and Korematsu v. United States (1944) is that",
        "correct_answer": "specific groups of people were being targeted based on race or ethnicity",
        "distractor1": "state laws were declared unconstitutional",
        "distractor2": "immigrants were relocated to prison camps",
        "distractor3": "federal laws segregating public transportation were upheld"
    }
]